You look great.
Thanks.
No, thank you.
Where are we going today?
-To Grandma's.
We'll leave you at Grandma's.
And Mom and Dad will come pick you up
later, okay?
No, why? I don't want to.
-I don't want to.
No "I don't want to," girls, no arguing,
You're going to Grandma's, that's it.
Did you bring the DVD that puts them to sleep?
Of course, "War and Peace" in the kids' version.
Bedtime songs with grape jam.
-Very funny.
If you had arranged a babysitter,
that could've entertained me too.
This is your event, right? Not mine.
What's your problem coordinating something once in your life?
It's not that complicated,
it's way easier than coordinating a crop-dusting plane
taking off from Ovda Airport in the Negev.
How did you get from the babysitter
to Ovda Airport in the Negev? Tell me.
Just like you got from guava jam to Tolstoy, okay?
I don't want to.
-Here we go.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Have a good week.
What, you guys are leaving already?
-Yeah.
What, Orna and Moshe aren't here?
No, they waited for you, saw you weren't coming, so they left.
Why did you come so late?
No, we just decided to stay a bit longer today.
There's a reunion for my school friends tonight.
A reunion?
-Why not?
I'm in touch
with three babies from my class at the health clinic.
We meet once a month
for a purpose.
First of all, it's a concentrated school
and there's nothing wrong with that,
you see where you are, where your friends are.
-Yeah.
What each one has accomplished.
How many kilometers you've traveled, how many you have left.
-Yeah.
What each one got married with.
To show off my wife.
Come on, Manny, what's up? We're waiting.
-Coming!
Honestly, I didn't get it,
what's the connection between you coming late
and having a reunion?
We just didn't manage to get a babysitter
and I thought to ask Mom
if we could leave the girls here?
We'll put them to sleep,
at a quarter past eight my friend, Tzvika, will come pick them up,
by ten-thirty, eleven at the latest after the reunion, we'll be here.
Alright, come on.
If I don't have to change them
or bring them, then it's fine.
Did you bring the one who puts them to sleep?
From the DVD, I don't have my own DVD.
-Of course, relax.
Ella, Maya, Daria,
-Love you.
Bye, Mom, have a good week.
-Bye, sweetie.
See you.
-Girls.
Have a good week. It was, a big problem.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
What, are you coming now?
-No, we have some...
What’s this?
Rachel, what, didn’t any of the sauce stay in the bowl?
No, nothing’s left,
I put the last three triangles in plastic for them.
You should’ve come earlier.
Want some coffee and pareve cake?
-Hold on a sec.
Mom, can I ask for something?
I just chatted with someone
I’ve been messaging for over a month.
Through a dating site, no details, just a first name.
And we set up to meet tonight.
Good luck with that.
I don’t know, I’m pretty skeptical
if anything will come of it.
So what did you want to ask?
Is there any chance you and Dad
could clear out the apartment for tonight?
What, so we won’t sit in the living room?
-No, clear out, clear out,
So you won’t be home at all. Is that a problem?
Maybe you could go to a movie? I’ll treat.
Here,
I had something here...
It’s okay, Meirav, it’s okay, it’s okay.
Dad,
Where would it be more comfortable
for us to put the girls down,
in the living room or in the bedroom?
I’m not comfortable at all.
Okay, so where do you want us to put the girls down?
You said by 11 at the latest?
Bedroom.
-Bedroom.
No, in the living room.
No, bedroom.
-Final answer.
Yeah,
Okay. Where did you put the disc?
-In my pocket.
Great, so take them to the bedroom,
get them settled, and put on Tolstoy.
They’re...
Shabbat Shalom.
What’s with that dress?
-You hear that, Mom?
The guys want...
-Grandma.
What?
-Dad sent me.
What, did something bad happen?
He forgot a bag here.
-A bag? Where was the bag?
Here.
Did you take that for yourself?
No, I just looked to see what was inside
to know who it belongs to.
Of course.
What?
I’m not here.
Good thing I remembered, Sali,
we need to go out to a movie tonight.
-What movie, Mom, what movie?
I really don’t need a movie right now.
Where did you get that? What, do you have coupons for a movie?
What coupons?
Meirav asked us to leave the house because she has a date.
With a guy?
-No, with a frog.
Of course with a guy.
Well, I have a date too, with my bed and my pillow.
And it’s a double date.
Mom, Shai and I really have to go today
so we wanted to leave the girls with you.
See? It’s not working out, please.
And I also said yes to them.
-Right.
But I said yes to Meirav.
You said yes to Meirav?
-Yeah.
Without asking me?
-Why, because you asked me?
They have a cycle.
-And she has a suitor.
Sali, if you go out tonight
it could very well be she’ll be gone for good.
I’m sorry, find another arrangement!
Wait, wait, wait, both of you.
I’ll handle it, I’ll talk to Meirav,
I’ll ask her to take her guy to a movie
and you can stay here to watch the girls.
I’m on it.
Hey Shabi, what’s up?
-All good, Meiravi.
I think we need to talk.
-Are you leaving me?
What? No.
No, no, no, listen, babe, listen,
Shai and I need to go to a reunion
from Shai’s high school,
but we couldn’t get a babysitter and I talked to Dad
and he agreed to watch the kids here.
Then I found out you have a date today.
-He agreed?
Yeah, of course he agreed, it’s his house.
But I’m his daughter.
-So what, Meiravi?
What are you mixing up for me, meat, milk, and pareve?
I invented pareve.
You have kids, a husband, and everything,
what do I have?
No meat, no milk, just pareve.
So what, what Meiravi, who’s this guy?
What?
We’ve been talking for a whole month.
-Nnnn.
Until now we’ve just been texting
but you don’t meet someone every day
who expresses himself just like you think.
And there aren’t many people who use
emojis as precisely and smartly as he does.
He’s not one of those who just throws them around,
every emoji of his is perfectly timed.
Seriously, when he writes haha...
you feel like he’s really laughing, not just haha...
Amazing. So I thought, like, I have an idea
how my girls can stay here
and not bother you.
You want me to babysit
on a date that’s really important to me?
Think about it, how great would it be for you to see
how he interacts with the kids.
Haha... I’m not ready.
I trust Shabi to change her mind.
You’re optimistic, you don’t know Meirav.
The chances are she won’t agree.
No chance she’ll agree, no—
I’m hungry.
What happened? Did something bad happen?
I can’t find the car keys, have you seen them?
-No.
What’s up, Manny, what happened?
-He lost the keys.
What’s the decision?
-You’re going to the movie.
And the reunion?
-No, no, we have to find a solution with the kids,
she’s not willing to compromise,
she’s not okay with the kids being here
when she has this date.
I don’t know what to do.
Dad, come on, what do we do?
Why don’t you let us know
about things like this in advance, can I know?
Why do you take it for granted that we’ll always agree?
Maybe I wanted to invite people over today?
Just like that, I feel like it, why not?
Maybe I wanted to throw a surprise party.
A surprise party for whom?
That's the thing about surprise parties, you don't know for whom.
Alright, we need to find a compromise with Meirav.
She'll never compromise.
That's why she'll never find a husband.
Even with the noise from the hairdryer, she picks up the word "husband."
Okay,
Don't worry, I've got this.
Stay strong.
Fifty bucks she’s peeling his skin
and rolling it in salt.
Meirav, Meirav, can I?
Shai, I told them not to send messengers,
If someone has something to say,
they should tell me directly.
So here I am, I have something to say, I came myself.
What?
Look, I have something really, really important tonight,
it’s really important to me.
Cycle, I heard you have something new?
Yeah, an idea.
We’ll put the girls to sleep before you came
and they’ll be here in the room,
You won’t even notice they’re here, they’ll be out cold.
Sorry to interrupt,
I think my keys are here.
I didn’t see them, look around.
And what if they’re not asleep?
-Don’t worry, they’re sleeping.
Sorry.
-Sleeping.
Block.
Sorry.
-And the living room?
It’s all yours.
-Hold on a sec.
Until eight-thirty?
-If not, we’re taking them with us.
Sorry.
-I don’t know.
I don’t know.
-Okay, sorry.
Two hundred shekels.
-800.
Meirav.
-And only if they’re asleep.
Alright.
He’s been there for a long time.
I’m really sorry, I didn’t
mean for all this chaos to happen.
A calm weekend only exists on the radio.
Even if it seems like it’s in an instant!
Just know there’s someone behind the door
who wants something from you.
What happened?
-What happened?
Did something bad happen?
Mom, enough.
So?
We reached a compromise, the girls are staying here.
What about me?
-You’re going to the movies, it’s all good.
Sit, sit.
How much for a flash at Meirav’s?
-800.
Enough, sweetie, enough, what happened?
Moshe the fool.
Where are the kids?
-They’re at home.
Why, did I need to bring them here?
-Not today,
it’s a bit chaotic but another day...
I’m sorry to interrupt, maybe my keys are here?
I don’t know, try to remember where you put them.
-I can’t.
What happened, Orna?
-Nothing.
So what, did you guys fight?
Sorry.
-Yeah.
Come on, maybe look somewhere else? Maybe in the bathroom.
Okay, sorry.
He wants to go again
to that ginger friend of his.
And then I have to be stuck
with the showers, with the putting to bed,
So I don't want to, today I'm 'going out'
while he's "stuck with the girls."
I'll be back because it's late,
I want to stay here tonight.
Tonight?
-Why? Is there a problem with that?
No, it's your house.
Every time it amazes me again
how fast it works.
Just realize there's already a warning you can't skip,
that you can't screen in public places, from the warnings.
Here, it's ready, three, four, and...
I'm fed up.
-Why?
I'm fed up. I've been waiting downstairs for an hour, there's a limit.
Michal, did you find the keys?
-I'm in the bathroom.
So we'll wait here.
Where are all the things?
I left them downstairs, by the car.
She's talking on the phone.
There's not much time left.
What about Orna? What did that idiot do to her?
No, nothing, nothing.
So why is the water cooler working?
-No, it's fine, nothing.
Did Orna and Moshe break up?
And where, where, where is the...
The news?
-No, they didn't break up.
I'll be right back,
I need to see what's up with... Meirav.
Rachel, Rachel, I already talked to Meirav
and we reached a compromise,
the girls will stay here but sleep in your room.
So I wouldn't light the fire again.
How much did it cost him?
-800.
Well, the fire's been going for a while.
Because now Orna arrived
!she also wants to stay here tonight.
So I need to see
how Meirav swallows this goat.
"I'm not choosing just one
From now on I'll be available
I give to everyone..."
Why is no one knocking here?
Meirav, you're looking great.
-Thanks, Mom.
I really hope everything will be okay.
-No, it will be okay, sweetie, it will be okay.
If he loves you, he loves you as you are,
and if not, then not.
But I kind of regret agreeing to Shai.
What, would you rather go out with the guy
to a movie or something?
No, no, but if Shai's kids
wake up, what will I do?
You see, in this matter you don't need to worry,
because Orna can take care of them,
she has a lot of experience with kids.
What Orna?
-Orna.
Orna Orna?
-Orna, your sister.
What is she doing here?
-She had some fight with Moshe.
Good grief, so she's here on my date too?
Is this how you want me to find a husband?
-Come on, relax, my sweet,
she won't bother you, I told her you have a date
and she'll stay in her room, she won't bother you.
Sweetie, she's in a terrible mood.
-I'm calling to cancel.
No, no, no, don't call, don't call,
you'll see it will be okay.
I have a really good feeling about this guy.
A feeling that this time it's it,
a much better feeling than last time
when it was it.
"Hope hope for the nation hope hope hope..."
Quiet.
They will never fall asleep like this.
Come on, get ready, it’s taking Dad too long.
Dad, I heard you’re going to the movies,
want a recommendation?
If it’s not "Home Alone 4,"
then no thanks.
What about Meirav?
It was tough this time.
I raised girls and raised girls and raised girls...
Sali, go get dressed, you can’t go to the movies like that.
Come on, what does it matter?
It’s a cinema,
it’s dark in there, no one sees.
I want a Tribevig, okay?
Silvan—
Chill out...
Sali...
I’m a bit hungry.
Next time, come earlier.
Make sure the girls fall asleep.
How can I when Manny’s
blasting the "United Nations" here?
If you help me find the key,
maybe we’ll get out of here faster.
What’s up, babe?
I’m staying here for a few hours, Moshe annoyed me.
What, annoyed you, huh?
Orna! Orna!
Orna!
Help me, Orna.
No, I can’t believe it.
Orna, come help.
I don’t want to yell like this all over the neighborhood.
Orna, are you there?
-Come on, what am I supposed to do with him?
Let me keep him for a week,
I’ll return him like those dogs
that sit on the dashboard,
and nod their heads all day like that.
Orna!
Please, help me.
This is the last time, I’m sorry.
What’s that red thing on the antenna next to Moshe?
It’s probably the beet.
Orna!
-Come on, tell him to shut up already.
Now take a deep breath.
Here.
Options. Movie in the garden.
Three, four, and...
Orna!
You on that side?
Babe, come here for a sec.
-What?
Can’t you hear Moshe screaming
like a madman all over the neighborhood?
Orna!
-What do you want me to do?
I’m trying to put the girls to sleep.
Okay, so from now on your job
is to calm Moshe down, alright?
No problem.
Orna!
Moshe, Moshe...
-Orna!
Shut up already, you idiot, and come up.
-Come up.
Why are you yelling like a crazy person?
-It’s not going to work like this.
Everything’s fine, Meirav.
Why aren’t you looking for the keys?
-Mom...
What’s going on, why are you doing this to me?
Meirav, I’m really sorry
if I’m adding to your headache.
But really, I can promise you, just tell her,
your smallest problem here tonight,
I'll sit quietly in my room.
I don’t get how you can feel private
when there are people in every room of the house.
It's like showering in the middle of Nokia Arena.
What?
Okay, I’m sorry,
I’ll look for the keys somewhere else.
Not now, why the keys now?
He stopped yelling.
-Moshe?
Manny and Alin's baby, Sivan.
Okay, sorry, you have ten minutes
to clean up the mess and clear out.
I can’t find the keys,
I’m sure the last time I saw them
they were in the kitchen.
Did you check the trash?
-Why the trash? Did I throw them away?
Not you, not you, Mom, maybe someone else.
What are you doing?
-Not here, look somewhere else.
Come on, go
Warning.
In the garden, a movie.
Three, four, and...
Ben...
What?
-Orna! Orna!
Moshe.
-Shai, open up.
No, I’m sorry, I don’t know
if I can let you in.
Hello, babe.
-Ah, Moshe.
Where are you taking the trash?
Looking for my keys.
Yeah
again.
Bye
He’s coming up.
Sit.
-What? Did something bad happen? What’s wrong?
Moshe's coming up.
-Why did you let him in on the intercom?
Orna!
Don’t let him into the kitchen, don’t let him dare enter the kitchen.
Orna, I want to talk to you.
-Moshe.
Let me, let me, okay?
Moshe, come.
-Orna, the beets are cooking in my car.
Moshe, come on, buddy.
-Orna.
Orna, babe, enough, I think you get
it’s time for you to make up, enough.
One, I’m not babe right now,
two, I don’t understand anything,
three, I’m not making up with him
until he comes to apologize,
on four.
And he has five minutes to do it.
That’s how women are,
they want to feel like they control us
and it makes them feel good.
So just accept it
and your life will be much quieter.
So you’re saying she’ll forgive me
if I apologize on four?
'Oh my dear', you need to take her out
to a restaurant one Saturday night,
what’s that?
After that, for two months,
for two months you can tell her,
what’s wrong? What’s not...
and that restaurant we went to together?
Got it?
-Yeah, I got it.
I can invite her for beets.
What, beets?
-Yeah.
If that’s what young people do today, then yeah, so...
Beets.
-Come on, we might have three minutes so let’s go.
That’s him, he’s here, hide.
Dad.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Hello, sweetheart.
-Hello, good evening, I hope I didn’t wake you.
Not at all, I was just expecting someone else.
I came to pick up Shai and Shani, are they here?
They're here, just a sec.
Where's Shai?
Maybe I'll write her a letter.
-A letter?
Yeah, like an apology letter, what do you think?
Bro.
-Okay, that was a false alarm, we can go out now.
What, what do you think of the idea?
-Which one?
K'
and
come
L'
A. `Ben.
Write her, write her a letter.
Here, take one, take it.
Give me a sec, Moshe, okay?
No, move over here.
That's it, go out, go out, let me.
You all have two minutes to get out of here.
What's up?
-How's it going?
Where's my brother?
There's a bit of a problem, his brother,
we couldn't find a babysitter.
Come on, Mavi, where are the keys?
-I couldn't find them.
Sit and move?
-No, we'll wait until the last minute,
maybe the white guy had a bass and something happened to it.
Orna, in my name,
you're the most, most mine.
I'm sorry for every little part
So come on! Hurry up
because downstairs a beet is waiting for me.
It doesn't matter if I'm wrong or you're wrong
we're paying the babysitter
by the hour.
I love you.
-Sorry.
I found your keys.
-Finally.
Where were they?
In... in... the bag area.
In the bags, who put them there anyway?
What does it matter? The important thing is they were found.
Alright, come on, guys,
let's clear the place, come on.
Seriously.
Listen, Yael! I got a babysitter,
I'll ask her
maybe she'll agree to take two more girls,
at most it'll be a party.
-There won't be a party, I have a disk.
Oh, great.
-Come on, come on, let's move.
Seriously, let's go. You get it, come on.
-Seriously.
We're also owners! So the whole house will be at your disposal.
Come
come bye
Come on, come on
Listen to me, I'm vacating my house
just this once,
and it's exceptional! Out of the ordinary.
You understand?
Just to make it clear to everyone here.
Also this, this jerk
shouldn't come and mess around in my house
and bring me the tenant protection law.
Enough, Sali, it's a first date,
why are you turning him into a protected tenant?
Whoever kicks you out of their house on Sunday
will send you to a nursing home on Monday, lady,
or to some trailer.
Come on
Let's go, come on.
Did I tell you everything would work out?
While you were dancing and Nike was up in Japan,
I talked to Meirav.
Turns out her dream guy
is seven heads shorter than her.
Everything but that.
Because online, it’s not about size, it’s about width.
Of the bar.
-Funny.
So, did you have a good time?
With what they paid Meirav and Tzvi's babysitter.
That was the most expensive reunion I’ve ever been to.
Well, at least you learned something about coordinating babysitters.
Tell me, did you find the keys in the mess?
Why?
-No, because you smell crazy like a mess.
No, the keys were in a bag,
I was next to it so I tasted it.
What, you didn’t save me a piece?
There were seven triangles,
I didn’t want to separate them.
Try to put the girls to sleep in the living room,
they’ll fall asleep later,
I’ll move them to the kitchen.
-Okay.
Not the kitchen, the bedroom.
-No problem.
You feel like he’s really joking.
Hold on.
I know the lines, I just...
Took her to some movie, something.
Again, a restaurant, why a movie?
I found your bags.
Meanwhile, seven crop-dusting planes
are taking off from the control tower.
They’ll take off from Ovda Airport in the Negev, right?
The control tower has a hard time taking off.
It’s a madhouse. This won’t work like this.
-It’ll be fine, it’ll be fine, Meirav...
Meirav...
Why aren’t you looking for the keys?
-Mom...