Mom, I think the hamster peed.
-Shai, come on, do me a favor,
it's gonna soak into the upholstery,
it's gonna smell bad in here.
Sit down, wait, don’t be hysterical.
It’s just a couple of drops, his pee.
He also poops on his bedding.
-Do me a favor,
when it comes to hamsters, you have no say at all.
Believe me, the moment you brought him home,
I should’ve kicked
all three of you out of the house.
-All three of us?
Yeah. You, the hamster, and the bedding.
-Okay, what do you want me to do?
The girl wanted a hamster.
-Great, and if the girl wants a mom,
are you gonna buy her one too?
-What mom?
A mom. The girl gets a pet mom. So buy her one.
Can I get a mom?
-Here, please.
Sss... Amen.
Don’t worry, babe, on Sunday Dad will buy you a mom
but on Sunday afternoon because on Sunday
morning he’s going to the Interior Ministry
to change his name to Dr. Dolittle.
Look at me, look at me and...
Come on, Dad, what, are you watching horse riding?
What do you want? What... it’s a sport.
It’s the only place where someone
walks around all day with their legs spread
and a whip in hand and it’s not weird.
You just ruined all the fun for me.
-What fun is that?
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
What’s that smell?
-I told you it stinks,
I’m not the only one saying it.
What is it? What is it? What did you bring? Not here, not here.
Over there, over there, put it there.
The girls wanted a pet so...
-Yeah, Shai bought them a hamster.
Really, put Justin Bieber
on the balcony! Don’t take him out of there.
Bieber is a doll, right?
-Yeah, that’s the name the girls gave
to the hamster Shai brought them.
As for me, I’m taking that hamster
and giving him a wireless bungee jump off the balcony.
-What, that’s unnecessary.
Why do you need a hamster?
It only brings diseases.
Why “only diseases”?
-Right, Shai is right. Why only diseases?
It’s also poop, also pee, also stink, also dirt,
the diseases are the fun part of the whole thing.
I’m going to eat.
I have a feeling that if it were technically possible for her,
she’d attach you
to that wireless bungee jump along with Justin Bieber.
It’s a bit discouraging because all the efforts
I make to not annoy her
go to waste.
-Hot blood,
and every time you burn her
thermostat again. You get it?
Why are you in a fighting mood today?
-Why? Because Shai bought a hamster for the girls.
One that looks like a rat and smells like a person.
A hamster?
-Yeah, yeah. It’s not the hamster itself,
it annoys me that Shai decides on his own.
Like he lives on some island of his own.
-Babe, he’s a man, that’s how men are.
He wanted to cheer the girls up a bit. What’s wrong with that?
Okay, okay, but he should call
before he does something silly,
just ask a little question: “Do you mind
having a rodent at home?”
It’s obvious I’d say no, but come on, he should ask.
So why did you agree to bring him home?
-The hamster?
Shai.
-Because the girls cried.
They wouldn’t let him stay outside.
Who, the hamster?
-Shai.
Now how do I get rid of him
without hurting her or the girls?
There are much easier questions than this
that I can’t solve.
You started with the complicated one.
-Come on, enough with the nonsense.
We waited for you because we need to do
a little job.
They bought a new PVC carpet.
We need to stick it in the bedroom.
PVC? What, that's still a thing?
Of course it's still a thing.
Only Rachel wants it in a wood pattern.
So why not wood?
-Do you know how to install wood?
No.
-Then it's PVC.
Fine.
Forget it, Shai, don’t go there,
I’ve been there, it’s not that fun.
I cried, wanted to go home.
You didn’t find your way. It’s just in the mourning room,
And honestly, he’s right.
PVC is way easier to stick down.
Easy?
-Easy, and I could do it myself,
I just get dizzy from the glue smell.
I once glued linoleum,
which is PVC's cousin.
Linoleum?
-Linoleum.
Well, if you finish on time, you’ll get a treat.
-Come on.
Enough, don’t be hysterical.
-I’m not hysterical. Hysterical...
Listen, is the hamster home alone now?
So go home, without the girls,
take care of it and later
find a good excuse for why it disappeared.
Yeah? You think the girls
left the hamster home alone?
It’s out here on your balcony.
-At my place?
What, Mom? Just for hysterics?
-Wait, a hamster is a lovely pet.
It’s like Grandpa. Just without the beard.
-Lovely and annoying.
Speaking of annoying, where’s Meirav?
-She went to the synagogue, God forbid.
What now, synagogue? What, is she becoming religious?
Why would she become religious? Did she go off the derech?
Meirav says you don’t go
to synagogue to become religious.
You go to synagogue
to find a match with good lineage.
A match?
-Wait, but even if she finds a match,
he’ll be from a religious family.
So?
-Why would he want her?
So what? Aren’t we traditional?
Mom, we’re traditional in "L." That guy
probably wants someone modest and nice,
someone who hasn’t seen Joseph and his brothers.
Someone who splits hooves,
chews the cud, and is kosher...
So what’s the problem?
We have the glue, the spatula, and the PVC.
Is there enough PVC?
-There’s a meter and a half spare.
No mistakes allowed. Got it?
Don’t worry, you’ll still be able to return
that meter and a half.
Then I’d be very happy.
-So come on, let’s start.
Alright, let’s start.
Start! Here, in this corner, please.
Okay, Dad, can you go?
-No, I just want to see
that you know what you’re doing. What’s wrong?
Fine. Go, come back in half an hour,
an hour, everything will be done.
For some reason, suddenly, I’m not relaxed. What now?
Well, you know what, Dad? Let’s make a bet
that we finish this job
here perfectly without a single flaw.
How?
-You’re going to get a finish
like in a fancy place.
-Alright then...
So start and I’ll be on my way.
Didn’t you say earlier you wanted
to watch the game on TV?
I’m recording it. Now start.
Open the glue.
-What? What’s the deal?
Did you know this glue is made from horses?
I’m leaving. Start, start.
-Thanks.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom, Silvan.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
What’s this, we’re sitting down?
-No, the women are in the kitchen.
Shai and Manny are in the living room.
-What is this? A dance competition for horses?
Yeah.
-I wish I could join a competition like that.
I'm really good at it.
Seriously, you're good at dancing?
-No, I'm good with animals.
Dad, can we stop with this?
What are Shai and Manny doing in the living room?
They're sticking PVC to the floor.
-And why didn't you wait for Moshe?
Moshe? We don't need him. Just an extra hand.
It's a job... a complex job, complex.
So what? Just so you know, Moshe
can do complex tasks too.
It would take them half the time.
Orna...
-Moshe, be quiet.
Moshe, you're not mad at me, right?
What can I say?
I think it's a complex job and you...
It just doesn't add up for me.
Correct me if I'm wrong.
-You're right.
Please.
-Or wrong.
What was the question?
-Okay. I'm tired of your attitude towards Moshe.
Fine, ugh...
-Wait. Do you want to go?
Go help them.
-No need.
Exactly, just like her mom, always insulting.
Insult and humiliation.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom.
-What, are you in a fighting mood too?
What, did Moshe buy you a hamster?
-What? No, he... Dad...
They won't even let Moshe stick
the PVC with them in the living room.
Maybe he's sensitive to the glue smell?
-No, but both he and I
are sensitive to everyone's disrespect
for Moshe's ability to help.
Enough, why does he need this? It's nonsense.
He shouldn't have to try hard.
-Orna, let's admit that Moshe is...
He's not the handyman of this family.
He's also not the Einstein of the family
or the Louis Pasteur of the family,
but that's his charm, that's what makes him special,
and that's why we love him so much.
So what, do you want to take that away from him?
No, I don't want to take that away from him,
but you've all turned him into
the family fool, and I can't accept that.
No, honey, we didn't turn him.
He came prepared from home.
Spread it evenly. Okay? No lumps.
-Okay.
Hey, Shabbat Shalom. What's up?
-Fine, sticking PVC.
Need help?
-Can't you help him from the living room?
What, do we need to stick it in the living room too?
-No, just the best help
you can give, Moshe, is, you know...
Not to interrupt.
-I know.
But Orna is forcing me. What can I do?
You don't have to.
-How "don't have to"? What choice do I have?
You all know I'm not good at this stuff.
-Come on, Moshe, it's not...
It's not that you're not good at it,
it's... you just aren't successful at it
like you're successful, say, at... at...
-At...
-Exams.
Exactly.
-Exactly.
Okay. What, still, can I mess up
without feeling too much guilt afterward?
Too much guilt?
Baseboards.
-Exactly. Stick the baseboards.
Great.
-Okay?
We need to cut...
Moshe, Moshe!
-Moshe...
No. No.
-What?
No, no, no.
-Thanks, Moshe.
Maybe we should ask Orna to let him off the hook?
Yeah, that would be good.
-You think?
Okay, Moshe, gently. Here are the baseboards.
Start there in the corner. Everything's ready for you.
Here’s the glue.
-Okay.
Moshe, Moshe...
-What? No? No...
Dad! Dad!
-Sweetie, Dad's in the bedroom.
I suggest you don’t go in there,
it smells really strong of glue.
The hamster got away.
-So you don’t need Dad,
you need Mom. She’ll be really happy.
What do you mean "the hamster got away"?
-It ran away.
Didn’t you see where?
No.
-Rachel!
Rachel!
-What happened?
There’s a free mouse roaming around the house.
-What mouse?
A mouse, a mouse... look, she says.
The hamster ran away from them.
Oh, thank God.
-Ah, it’s the hamster. Where did it run off to?
It’s in the house.
-It’s a house, so let’s find it.
It has nowhere to run.
-Yeah, but it could get into some small opening,
it could die there from hunger.
It’ll stink up the whole house. That’s what
I need, a dead hamster in the house.
Even when it’s alive, it’s already pretty stinky.
Shani, it’s your hamster.
Find it and get it out of here!
It’s not mine, Dad, it’s Shai’s.
And when he’s done gluing
the carpet in that room,
he can find it and get rid of it.
Here it is. No, sorry, sorry.
That’s the landlord. Sorry.
Sorry, sorry.
-Oh, that’s the landlord?
Come on. |
Shabbat Shalom, everyone.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Hello, honored rabbi.
Be careful.
-Why? What happened?
Mouse, mouse. It ran away. Here. Mouse.
What mouse and what...
-Hamster.
Hamster?
-Hamster, hamster.
Shai bought a hamster for his daughter,
and now it ran away from the cage.
Great, that’s just what I needed.
They’re messing around with
hunting an unclean animal on Shabbat, God have mercy.
-Amen. Amen.
Maybe instead of Him having mercy, He’ll
help us find that hamster.
Okay, listen up, the whole Hasson family
with all its branches and offshoots,
I don’t care about anything,
no more messing around with any hamsters.
My match is coming soon
from the synagogue. Got it?
Mazal Tov!
-Mazal Tov!
Mazal Tov, Meirav.
I mean, wow? This glue is really strong.
Of course it’s strong, Moshe.
It’s meant for carpets, not your shoes.
Moshe, you’re now stuck to the carpet
or the carpet’s coming up
and we’re losing the bet with Silvan.
-That piece is already a goner anyway.
There goes the meter and a half of spare.
-Wait, wait. I have a brilliant idea.
Ta-da!
-No way, you’re a genius, Moshe.
Here it is!
-Stop! Stop!
That’s my husband. You’ve already killed her. Enough.
Okay, listen to me, please.
I have a date, and this time it’s doubly important
because with the religious, there aren’t too many checks.
One meeting and a wedding.
We have to close this gap.
I know you’d like
me to find a partner and get out of the house
and relax a bit...
What are you talking about?
-What are you talking about?
Okay, enough, enough, enough. Alright. Let her speak.
Thanks, Mom.
-You’re welcome.
So what I wanted to ask each of you
is to make a small effort for me, please.
What effort, Meirav?
-Minimal.
Dad, from now on you’ll wear a kippah.
-I’m willing for you
to even grow sidelocks. Just that will take a bit of time.
Dad, this isn’t the time for jokes
and it’s not a place for clowns, I’m sorry.
God help us.
-Girls, you need long skirts.
Long?
-Long.
The longer, the better
it shows you’re more modest.
And of course, the news is that pretty much all of you here,
need head coverings.
-Oh, come on, how long is this going to last,
this head covering?
-Until the wedding is decided.
Do I have to?
-Come on, let her talk.
Thanks, Mom.
-You’re welcome.
From now on...
-Miravi, Miravi,
in the end, he should love you for who you are,
not because of skirts and head coverings.
Of course, in the end, he won’t have a choice
and he’ll love you for who you are.
This is really the perfect trap.
A mouse!
-Is that Dad's husband?
Did your husband just go to the kitchen?
-No, she’s here.
Come on, to the kitchen, to the kitchen. Let’s go.
I can’t believe that what’s ruining my chances,
which are already slim,
of finding a groom is my crazy, wild family.
Listen to me, when they come, we’ll behave accordingly.
I promise you, don’t worry. Okay?
-Yeah, I promise too.
Wait, where are the men?
-In the mourning room. They’re gluing PVC.
On Shabbat? Working on Shabbat?
Soon you’ll have a barbecue
in the middle of the living room with pigs,
shrimp in its mother’s milk and chips.
-Chips are kosher.
From potatoes that didn’t have
tithes taken from them on Shabbat of the sabbatical year?
What?
-How much impurity in one house?
Yuck.
Thank God she didn’t convert.
-Let them call.
I don’t know what smells worse, the glue
or Moshe’s shoes.
-How did glue get on my shirt? I don’t get it.
What’s this mess, for heaven’s sake?
Why mess? We’re gluing a carpet.
-And Moshe?
He’s gluing shoes, socks, and clothes.
He’s going for avant-garde art.
Helping them a bit.
-I see.
Well, you’re not leaving the room under any circumstances,
not even in a life-threatening situation,
because what’s happening here is just disgusting,
disgusting for Shabbat and for me.
-And if we need to pee?
No problem, just bless after,
with cups, cups, hollow, hollow,
wash your hands and that’s it, all without leaving the room.
Clear?
-So when can we leave?
When I release you.
-When? After Shabbat?
Yes, you’ll be the three stars.
The moment you leave the room,
for me, Shabbat is over,
it’ll only be spontaneous
according to my instructions. Clear?
-Yeah.
Yeah.
-Of course. Of course.
I think he’s here, behind the fridge.
Girls, I don’t want to join Mirav’s game.
I recommend you not tell her anything about this,
take Manny and the kids
and scram before the religious folks come.
On the other hand, she won’t stay for the parts that are going to be
for sure.
-Of course.
Yeah, but I...
-Forget it for now, close the laundry in the kitchen.
We have to catch them.
Close off this whole area,
so he doesn’t escape to that side.
-Yeah.
I’m stressing them out here, by the fridge.
Wherever he goes, you catch him.
Focus.
Here he is!
-Here.
Here.
Now he ran away.
Alin, sit down, Orna, in my room.
I'll get you skirts.
But Meirav, the hamster.
-I don't care about your hamster.
You need to be ready when he arrives.
Tell me, Meirav, can we not be so uptight?
It's not uptight. It's just a little bit of pretending, that's all.
Meirav, I really don't want
to wear those skirts...
Sit down..
-Yeah, I don't really want to either.
You want to ruin it for me on purpose, right?
-No, no, Meirav.
Alin could actually be
the shiksa in every Jewish family.
We don't have interfaith marriages in our family!
Ugh, but I'm scared
that Manny will see me... religious,
and it'll... turn him on.
I didn't know Manny liked that look.
Come on, girls, to the school.
He ran over there. Someone catch him already.
Quickly and soon.
And say Amen.
You look like someone pulled you out of Mea Shearim.
And you look like some Kabbalist from Safed
here to put up a mezuzah.
You know my grandfather, may he rest in peace, he was...
He was a Kabbalist...
Very much.
Come on, Sali, look at us. Come on.
How?
-You don't look like the one
from "Jerusalem Mix"?
-Oh, funny, Mom.
I can't believe it. God willing.
Where's Orna?
-Here’s Orna. Orna.
She just... Meirav says she's too pretty,
so she covered her up, made her a Taliban mom.
Hey.
-Peace be upon you.
Be careful with the last piece
because there are no more spare ones.
-Got it.
Is that it?
-That's it.
You did a good job.
-You too.
Where are my socks?
They're gone...
Well, I told the girls not to leave the balcony
except for your daughter, who's pretty colorful today.
Meirav, this isn't really comfortable for me.
Suffer quietly, it's just a coffee thing.
It's them. Get it together.
Alin, to the women's section.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat...
Shabana. Shabana, please, Shabana.
God have mercy. May God save us...
Mom, can I talk to you for a second in the kitchen?
Is this the match? We dressed up for this?
Are you talking?
-It's not funny.
When I was in the women's section and looked down
that guy was standing next to someone handsome.
I'm with you for seven days. I think
it was a trap by his mom.
Why do you dismiss right away?
-I'm not dismissing.
It's him who's cross-eyed.
-Everyone who's cross-eyed, in his own way.
Leave her alone, enough. She's nervous.
-No, I'm not.
Maybe under all that cross-eyed appearance
there's a handsome prince hiding...
Okay, enough with the jokes.
How do we get rid of them?
How did my socks get over there?
-You need to cut with a cutting knife,
take out the part and then glue it back.
-What "cut"?
If it breaks, the carpet will tear.
And there's no spare white one left.
Well, this part is staying under the bed anyway,
So come on, let it stay a little bump.
-What "little bump"?
It's a tsunami. Moshe, seriously.
-What, come on...
Come on. What, here, here. Here. Okay?
Better? Flat enough? Here.
Here you go.
-Did you see Justin Bieber?
Justin Bieber?
-Her hamster.
Because he's running that way.
-Hamster?
No. No, sweetie. We didn't see him.
No! No!
No, Justin. No!
Why? No! No!
No! No!
Well...
-I killed him!
I killed Justin Bieber, I killed him.
Moshe!
-I killed him.
Mouse! Mouse!
-You killed him.
I killed him. A lot,
Where are you? I killed him.
Can't we leave him there?
-If we leave the hamster here, it'll stink.
Well, then there's no choice.
We'll go for a cut and hope for the best.
Wow, wow. Bravo! Bravo!
I see you finished.
Wonderful
Ar
In
Not really.
-No?
The main thing is you finished. Shai, your mouse is running free,
he's causing a scene.
-Is he alive?
Recently he ran by the bathroom,
running free.
Yeah, yeah. Come, come, come!
The hamster is alive?
-So it must really be Moshe's socks.
Probably.
We told you there would be laughs in the end.
Great, laugh.
You know, Meirav,
there are whole other sectors you haven't tried.
Enough! Enough. Maybe instead of laughing and bothering
someone will find that hamster.
Here he is, the sweet one.
-Shai...
He's a bit scared. Don't worry, Justin.
You're in good hands.
-Good job, Dr. Dolittle.
You said I'm good with animals.
-How cute...
Come on, let's go see the room.
Don't bring him near me, Moshe.
I told you that part comes out from under the bed.
They’ll never notice.
We cleaned up.
-How nice!
Amazing!
In style!
Well, I understand I lost the bet.
-Partially.
You were right about the spare.
-What’s that smell?
It's... it's... Moshe's clothes.
He forgot them here so I...
Why? Why is the bed shaking?
The bed is shaking?
Yeah.
-Look, the clothes are outside.
Yeah, but the smell remains.
It... it smells like Moshe's essence.
The bed is shaking.
Maybe we really lost the bet.
Probably.
I'm done. I didn't even eat from the mezilof in the end.
My head hurts from the glue smell
and from... Moshe's essence.
Why? It was a fun Shabbat.
-That didn't end. At 00:21 the hatch opens,
Manny and I need to go buy
some PVC pipes for the repairs.
What, did you lose the bet?
-Yeah, but it's Moshe's fault.
Well, now Moshe has a different role.
-I don't get it. Why did you let him off?
For his part in the disaster?
-Why? Because he took Justin Bieber, maybe.
Uh... what... he's really not here.
-Right.
When Abu was about to leave and the girls came to get him,
Moshe started crying,
so they let him off. I don't know,
maybe because he was half-naked.
Who are you always spinning around?
-Orna.
What does she want?
-She wants to kill me,
what does she want...
Pigs! Shrimp in milk with potatoes.
Gross.
That's the cousin of the PVC.
This wireless babaji along with Justin Beaton.
Beaton?
Which Beaton?
-Bieber, Bieber.
Where did you get that from?
Well, we need to paddle around.
Sorry. No, because of that...
I suggest you don't go in there
because it smells really bad like garbage.
Do you want something to drink?
He didn't tell you to do...
No.