Short and sweet. We come, we bless, we eat, we leave.
Yeah. We don’t waste time at home either.
We bathe the girls, bathe you, and that’s it.
And good night to everyone.
-What happens at night?
What... we sleep. What could happen at night?
Don’t tell her about the babysitter.
-Why are you saying that in Hebrew?
Because she knows the word in English.
Ah... yeah, yeah, yeah—
We’re going out tonight.
And it’s really important for our "togetherness."
-Of course.
So don’t tell her about the babysitter.
Of course I won’t tell her.
What, do you think I’m crazy?
I care about it too... it’s important to me.
I’ve been waiting for this too.
Wow...
-Wow.
So what’s his "bet"?
Do you really want me to tell you?
Yes, please.
-If you’re asking so nicely.
What do you think about this:
You, me, music,
grapefruit vodka...
How do you say "אשכוליות" in English?
"Grapefruit."
-Grapefruit.
Do you think she understands?
-Yeah.
Great, babe. Great.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat shalom.
-Shabbat shalom.
Pinchas, what’s up, how are you?
-Okay.
We can’t stay long today.
-Yeah.
I hope Adam and Itamar get here soon.
-What happened?
I have a date.
-Something special?
The date is with her.
-Oh, that’s so nice.
It’s really important for the relationship.
Right. Don’t let it happen to you like it did to Itamar and Smadar.
I’ll go to the kitchen and speed things up for you.
I’ll help you with the schnitzels.
So where are you going to strengthen the relationship?
Me, wait a second. It’s from the babysitter.
-I’m sure she won’t bail.
No. Why would she bail?
-What, did she bail?
No, she didn’t bail. She just said
she’ll be late because her grandma is in the hospital.
Didn’t bail.
Good you came. I wasn’t comfortable around Shabi.
So what? You guys strengthening?
-What?
The relationship. Did she say anything?
No, why would she say anything? Everything’s fine.
Are you sure?
-Yeah. It’s just, Shabi and I haven’t gone out in a long time,
you know, the kids and all...
-The kids are not an excuse.
I never let the kids
get in the way of me and Pinchas.
Mom, mom! I know—I know—
Everything’s great. We’re having fun,
happy, everything... everything’s great.
Great. Awesome. It’s good you’re still in the game.
You know, marriage, you open the door for them,
they escape through the window.
-Yeah.
I think the schnitzels escaped through the window.
It’s good to break the routine. You never know
where the gray monster of boredom is hiding.
Speaking of hiding: where are the schnitzels?
Nothing, nothing on you
-Nothing...
Very healthy. Yeah. But tofu.
I wanted to break the routine, so you wouldn’t escape through the window.
How old was she, Grandma?
-Why was she? She's not dead.
Why would she die? She's just in the hospital.
Ooooh
'Ooooh
Ova.
Hey, glad you came. It's already a quarter past.
-What did we do to her?
Shani's anxious to work on the relationship.
-Did something happen?
Me! Shai and I are going out. Just kidding.
-It's really not just kidding, babe.
It's really not just kidding. It's super important for the relationship.
Me! Itamar insists, even if the guy's not really in the mood,
And even if we went out yesterday,
to clear our heads, work on the "togetherness,"
and most importantly, to...
Dance at least three or four times a week.
Good for you.
-Hey, if Itamar was like that,
three or four times with Smadar, everything...
-Come on, what's wrong with you?
What? What happened to Itamar?
-No, he has some issue with...
Never mind. Where did you think of going?
-It's not really important, what.
Do you know how long it's been since I
went to a good movie?
Want to come with us to "Jabaki"?
-No, I don't think so.
Never mind. The main thing is to work on your relationship,
and I'm sure the babysitter won't bail.
-Why would she bail?
Is that her?
-The babysitter?
Bailed?
-Sit down, can you wait a sec?
Boy
Sit down
It's great they're working on their relationship.
-Their relationship is just fine.
No, of course.
-Okay, excuse me for a sec.
What happened to him?
-His red light came back.
There's a problem.
-How do you know?
How do I know? There are no schnitzels.
-What?
No schnitzels, no shlaykler, no schweitz.
-Shai, what are you talking about?
About the food my mom made,
if you can even call it food.
Okay, drop it. There's a bigger problem.
They have an issue with the babysitter.
-She doesn't have shlaykler?
No, she bailed on them. Her grandma passed away.
Is that a reason to bail?
-I don't know. Your dad gave them the evil eye.
And you know who can fix this? Your mom.
-What do you mean?
I mean your mom can watch the girls for us,
and you can go ask her.
No, sit down, sit down,
you're just upset about your grandma.
No, I'm not upset.
I'm completely serious. Why can only my mom
watch the kids?
Your mom can babysit sometimes too.
Fine, I just think
it's not a good time to ask her
because it stresses her out that the kids are little.
-What little?
The kids are already big. Enough with the excuse.
It's not an excuse. I'm telling you, something happened.
-What happened?
Suddenly you don't have schnitzels?
-There's dandelion.
Do you even know what dandelion looks like?
-No. But I know what lamb's lettuce looks like.
Go talk to your mom. Now.
Hey, Riki, Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
What, is this millet? Wow, I'm shocked.
What? You made lupin?
-I decided to try. I'm almost done.
What, I'll help you, wow, that's amazing.
No way. You made maash?
Who has the energy for shlaykler again?
-What, Riki, is this for me?
You made vegetarian for me?
How sweet, you didn't have to.
Wow, this is great. I hope
you soaked the lupin enough in water.
Yeah.
-It's a bit hard to soften them...
True.
-But it's worth the effort.
Kind of like Shani. You know
they've started working on their relationship.
Yeah, I've been wanting to tell her for a while
that she's been neglecting herself
lately.
-True. But it's also kids and all, you know.
But kids are not an excuse.
-Yeah.
You know, I'm so happy
that we can talk like this.
Wow, me too, Riki.
-You know you're my favorite bride.
No, I'm dying. You too...
Wow, you're stunning! Wow.
Where's Mom?
-In the kitchen.
You know, Dad, what...
All week the girls won't stop talking about you.
"Grandpa, Grandpa."
-Yes.
So Grandma passed away?
Passed away.
-Passed away.
So what do you say? Help your son with the girls.
It's so important for his relationship.
-I get you,
I really get you, but you
have to ask Mom about these things.
It's important for my relationship.
I don't know if it's a fungus
or a rash, but this redness
is killing me... from what.
-Funny.
You think it's funny that I'm in pain?
-No, I just...
The girls won't stop talking about you all week.
"Uncle Itamar, Uncle Itamar..."
"Itamar, Itamar."
-Did she bail?
Passed away.
My condolences.
-So participate in the effort too.
Shai, it's not me, it's Michal.
She needs to deal with my monsters anyway,
so now she has to handle your... princesses?
You understand me, Shani?
-Yeah, yeah. Of course.
I'm red.
-So...
So... your mom is in the kitchen, by the chard.
Oh, do me a favor, Itamar.
Yummy.
-Bless you.
No, that's beans.
You have to mix it with the millet.
It gives it this aroma...
They'll love it.
-Michal, Itamar needs you. He's red.
He can be such a kid sometimes,
and I have a ton of natural ointments,
but he doesn't want to apply them. Ugh.
It smells really... what is it?
-Spelt pilaf.
It looks, looks great.
Mom, if you don't mind me asking...
Shai, I'm really sorry,
there are no schnitzels today, okay?
You'll live with it. Nothing bad will happen.
-No, come on, that's not what I wanted.
The... cup... the... looks great. It's nutritious.
Now you're making fun of my food?
-No. No.
I wanted to ask you for a small favor.
The babysitter bailed on my son,
and we really want to go out today.
It's so important for Shani. So I wanted to ask
if you don't mind the girls staying here tonight.
I'm sorry, Shai. It's really
not suitable for me. It's really not suitable for me
for them to stay here tonight.
-When is it suitable for you?
What did you say?
-I'm not saying,
but Shani is right.
-Shani.
Not Shani. No, me. Me. Me... Mom, look,
you never help us with the girls.
You helped Itamar when he got divorced. Right?
So why not for my girls?
What, do I need to get divorced for that?
I really don't understand you.
Once I'm asking you
to do something for me and even then you don't...
So that's how you feel?
-Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
Okay, so if you really want to know,
and I didn't want to tell you this
to avoid worrying you, then I
can't babysit your girls today
because yesterday
I had general tests done
!the result is crap. Okay?
What? So what's wrong with you?
The health fund's website
couldn't believe what I have in my blood.
So I'm sorry there are no schnitzels,
but there's healthier food instead.
And I can't babysit my girls.
So you and Shani can go dance.
Luckily, it won't take much longer.
Hey, did you talk to her?
I think he asked her.
-I'll handle it.
This red is driving me crazy. I don't know
if I suffer more sitting,
standing, or walking.
It's just driving me nuts, babe.
Enough, I can't take it anymore.
-Babe.
Ohh
Meet Sivan.
Hi.
-Michal.
And the uncultured one is my brother, Itamar.
-Nice to meet you.
Tell me, are you normal? We saw you.
It's fine, I'm used to people like that from work.
-You work at the safari?
At the hospital.
-Sivan's an intern.
That's how we met. You just came to pick up
my tests and... I'm healthy.
More than I can say
about some of my recent dates.
What, so you're a doctor?
-Intern.
Great, because I have just a little question.
Do you know anything about red?
I haven't been "ouch" for a long time,
but you guys don't even notice.
Rivka.
-Pinchas, give me five minutes.
Riki, come on...
Can't I be a little sad?
You can, of course you can,
but maybe now isn't the right time.
Oh, really? So when is the right time?
After I die?
Why would you die? Seriously.
We're going to the doctor on Sunday,
and he'll tell us what's going on. Okay?
-Yeah. What will he say?
You already know, you saw the results.
-Do we understand this?
He understands it. Come on Sunday
and he'll tell us everything.
Ugh, so unfair. All these years you were sick
while I was as healthy as a horse,
and now I'm going to die first
and the kids will starve.
-They won't starve.
Rivka, who can hate dandelions?
And they don't know what's wrong with her?
-No.
What should I do?
-Babe,
it'll be okay. We'll get through this together.
And the last thing I did was laugh at her.
-Enough, Shai.
You know it's all because of you.
-Enough, babe.
It's really good that you talked to her.
-She won't watch the girls. Forget it.
I'm not talking about that, Shai. I'm talking
about how good it is that she told you.
And now you also need to tell your brothers.
Why me?
-What do you mean "why you"?
You all need to know
so you can help her together.
Babe, in moments like this, family
needs to come together, be there for each other,
help each other, with no secrets and no lies.
You're right.
-Yeah.
Maybe a little with lies.
You should tell your brothers, warn them about the food,
so she won't get offended.
Do you want me to jump in the shower for a sec?
Itamar... boundaries.
-I don't mind looking.
He has a problem.
-What?
She's not a doctor.
-She's an intern.
Okay, that doesn't matter.
She's coming with Adam for dinner.
Are you going to show her your red?
Want a peek? Jump to the ER.
Isn't it more logical to jump in the shower for a sec?
-Adam, Itamar, come to the shower for a moment.
Can I go to the shower with Shai?
K'vour
'sh.'
Sivan.
Ohh
Chubinon.
In the air.
So what, every week Adam brings someone new?
No.
-No.
What do you mean?
-What's up with you?
Bo, where are the friends? Did Adam arrive?
-Hey, Sivan, meet: Pini and Riki.
Hey there.
Oh, so you’re Adam’s new girl?
I hope you last more than a week.
-Pini, why wouldn’t she last?
Why do you always think the worst?
-The last one was actually blonde.
Funny.
Bo, what’s going on? I’m dying.
-Listen, Mom’s not doing well.
What now?
-What nonsense now?
She had tests and the results aren’t good.
-What do you mean?
I don’t really know, but it’s not good.
Including that she needs to switch to healthy food.
So no schnitzels.
-What’s going on here?
Honey, did you hear? No schnitzels.
-I saw. Genius, right?
Not like always, when she fries my veggie patties in your schnitzel oil.
Mom’s not well.
-No, I’m dying.
I wonder who will go first, you or Mom?
-Itamar...
Hey, do you think if you’re all here,
Mom won’t notice you’re missing?
Hey, Dad, is this serious?
-If you’re talking about Mom,
apparently it is. And you better
not mention the food to her.
Eat and say it’s good. Got it?
What’s this green juice?
-It’s wheatgrass.
It’s fine, it’s rich.
-I see Shai talked to them.
Yeah, we tend to talk to each other.
Don’t worry, I’ll manage.
It’ll be fine, Riki.
-What will be fine?
I know you’ll get attached to that babysitter.
No, no, leave it. It’s nonsense. Don’t get involved.
No, no, no. It’s not nonsense at all.
If I were healthy,
I’d do that babysitting.
Never mind. Forget it,
don’t even think about it, it’s fine.
If there’s someone! I’ll miss,
it’s those babysitters.
Me, Riki. Really.
-You’re right, you’re right.
I don’t need to pity myself.
There’ll be plenty of time for that.
Can you please help me with the spinach balls?
Sure, sure. I’ll do everything. Don’t move.
And the bowls, the cups,
if you can take them out...
I’m taking them out, I’m taking everything out.
Let’s put the lentils on a flat plate.
Oh, it’s dirty.
-I’ll come clean it.
No, no, no. Riki, Riki, Riki, don’t you dare.
Sit, sit, don’t get up, sit. I’ll do everything.
I’m so glad we’re talking like this.
You know you’re my favorite bride?
Is everything okay?
-Are you hearing...
There’s probably going to be a problem with the...
-Is everyone here? Where’s Pini?
Everything will be ready soon.
-He’s still over there.
Here, I think he’s coming out.
-You’re coming to help.
Of course, of course.
In short, it turns out there’s some issue with his mom.
The situation isn’t good.
So the food changed too.
-No schnitzels.
But there’s amazing lentils.
Lentils.
-Lentils. Something.
Honey, I can’t take it anymore, it’s burning me.
Let her check me.
Okay, get on with it.
Good luck to you.
So
'Sivan'
There's something.
Smells like citrus. You can plant that.
This is seaweed salad and this is watercress.
Mom, are there hot dogs?
-I want some too.
No, sweetie. Hot dogs aren't that healthy.
Oh, I forgot the serving spoons. I'll get up.
-Sit down, sit down, Riki.
I'll bring them. Riki.
Alright, dear family,
I want to say a few words before the blessing.
As everyone knows, things aren't great,
It's something you can't keep secret in this family,
and everyone knows...
-Where's Itamar?
Tamar! Excuse me for a moment.
Can you pass me the cucumber?
Cucumber?
-Alfalfa.
I want hot dogs too.
-Shut up.
I think the professional term for this is "red."
-But what is it from?
From my guess, either a rash or a fungus. Are you running?
-Do I look like it?
Dancing?
Dad's about to say the blessing,
I'm dying here and this is what you're doing?
Mom, it's not what it looks like. It's red. Mom!
It smells weird.
-No, sweetie, it just smells like that.
Do you want to drink? What's this?
-Wheatgrass.
I felt at home.
-Shayka, she's coming.
The chard... is flourishing.
-Shall we say the blessing?
Mom, it's not what you think.
-Who said I was thinking anything?
In my life, I've learned
that it's always exactly what I'm thinking.
So it's not.
-What a family I've raised.
One son goes out dancing while his mom is on her deathbed,
and the other is doing things with the third's rabbit.
This is what I'm taking with me to the grave.
-Riki, we're not going out dancing after all
because we don't have a babysitter.
-And I'm to blame, right?
I'm stuck in your throat like this chard.
Shay.
-Right?
She'll be alone in heaven
because two like her would be hell.
What did you do?
-Nothing,
she caught us in the middle of the check in the shower.
-What check?
She's a doctor.
-Not exactly. I'm a resident.
Really? I just asked.
They sent you?
No, Mom. I came on my own.
You know you were always my favorite son.
What's going on with you?
-Did you do
Look for yourself.
See?
-I see, yeah.
Understand? Not really.
I checked online! It's a disaster.
Listen, Mom, Sali studied medicine,
she's now in her residency.
She's a doctor?
-Almost.
No, then give it to me.
-Don't you want her to take a look at it?
No, it's private. I don't want
a nearly-doctor to see this.
Give it to me.
Girls, I promise on the way home we'll stop at Burger.
So, what's this red thing?
-Honey, I think we need to
loosen up the relationship a bit.
-No, why?
It's red.
-Alright...
Give it to me. Give it to me.
-Rivka, let her see. Let her see.
So what's the problem?
What kind of doctor are you if you can't see the problem?
Look, from what I understand,
everything's fine and normal.
But I looked online and the result is crap.
Did you write down your age?
-No. Should I have?
Yes, the results relate to the patient's age.
So you're not 23, but you're healthy for your age,
I promise that's what
the doctor will say on Sunday.
Please.
-How nice, I didn't know that...
So can we take the shleiks out of the freezer now?
Yes, of course.
And Mom...
-Yes?
Oh no, I don't feel so good.
"Day of the Rose"
What did you tell them, that Dad is coming to pick up the girls?
We have five hours.
You arrived.
-You arrived.
K'
comfortable `
and
in a'
thus]
(y)
and'
thus]
N'
L'ben.
Stone and...
What, what is this? Where are we?
You see there, ahead.
-It's dark.
That's the sea.
-The sea.
Can't see anything.
-We're on a cliff.
Cliff. Are you taking me to a cliff before we leave?
I thought we'd start at the cliff, see where it goes from there.
Grapefruit vodka...
-Grape-fruit.
That was obvious.
-What an embarrassment.
So what do we do now,
now that the girls know English?
What, learn Yiddish? Oops, my glass fell.
Wait, I'll pick it up for you.
Good evening. Are you there, are you dressed?
I never let Pinchas
bother me and the girls.
You didn't let Pinchas...
I really don't want to hear about that, Mom.
She needs to switch to healthy eating.
Eating. She needs to...
Just bathe her and that's it.
-And have a...
And have a good night.
Grape... what...
Three, two...
I think according to... sorry.
Mom, it's not what it looks like.
It's red. Mom, Mom!
Mom...
Who made the blessing?
-Mom, it's not what it looks like, come on.
Who said I think it looks like that?
Sorry, sorry. My bad.