Excited?
Yeah, honestly, a little.
What, when is it airing?
-How should I know?
But it’s supposed to be in their next season.
Which starts soon! Like in a month.
Really? So how did Michal and Itamar get the tape?
Because a friend of Michal's works in production,
so she snuck them a tape before it aired.
Awesome.
-I wonder how it turned out.
Yeah.
This is my first time on TV. Oh my God.
I've been on a few times already.
I
My first time was
at a Kaveret concert in the park in '81,
it was huge.
-Really, what did you do there?
I was in the audience.
-You were in the audience.
They came to do a piece on those who arrived early,
I was there with a big sign in the back.
Did you see that?
Honey, I was five in '81,
how could I have seen that?
Okay, I was going crazy, like a maniac, what...
-Alright.
It takes forever to make
these reality shows, huh?
"Yo yo, I'm asking"
They filmed that a while ago, and let me tell you
since then I've lost a ton of weight.
"Yo yo, you’re answering"
Too bad they didn’t film it now,
I look totally different.
"You don’t know"
Come on, what’s happened to you?
My dad even recorded it on a VHS,
so every time we paused it,
I was like this with the video.
Alright, honey, honey, hands on the wheel,
What happened to you?
-I’m fine...
Look at me, look at me and...
Good evening,
tonight in the family, like Michal and Itamar Rosen,
we’ll learn together about the bitter taste
of water from the well they sang to
it’s so full.
Family, like, roll up your sleeves and let’s get started.
Alright, good luck.
So,
my name is Michal, I’m married to Itamar Rosen.
I’m a student and I’m also kind of a healer,
I took a course in communication.
It’s a course in medicine...
Michal, Michal, Michal, we don’t have time for all this,
I’m not really interested in who you are,
we’re on a short and efficient show,
I don’t see the need.
Who?
Just tell me about the problem.
Only one problem? I don’t know.
My husband doesn’t respect me,
his mom doesn’t respect me,
and he never stands up for me against her.
His kids don’t respect me,
he doesn’t respect them.
Everyone respects his ex-wife way too much.
Join the miserable couple for Friday dinner
to learn a bit more
about the issues in their family dynamics
that don’t allow them any peace.
What’s with the cameras? They have no problem.
No problem?
-Nothing urgent or that needs fixing.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Whoa.
Hey.
-Shabbat Shalom.
So what, you're late again?
You're funny, Shai, Tami isn't always late.
They probably had car trouble.
-Car trouble?
Can we do the Kiddush already?
You guys are late anyway! You're the ones who brought the cameras.
Kiddush.
-They probably had car trouble.
The car...
-Yeah.
There was no car trouble,
it's just because of Michal.
What about Michal?
Come on, you know it takes you
hours to get ready and do your makeup,
and now with the cameras, it's even worse.
-Why are you saying that?
Saying what?
-Saying those things about me.
Honey, you know
it takes you hours to do your makeup and get dressed
or should I lie just because there are cameras?
Okay, I get it, because there are cameras
you're trying to make it seem
like the problem is with me instead of you.
What?
You're stepping on her foot, come on, honey,
pay attention to the kids, even if they're not yours.
See, the problem's solved,
it just took them time because of the outfit and makeup.
If you're in a hurry with your makeup,
you could grow a beard, like Adam,
it saves time.
-Riki...
Never mind.
What? What did I say?
Maybe that she has a beard, Riki?
-Pinchas, do me a favor,
if you don't have anything smart to say,
talk about the weather.
I was just joking, of course.
Hilarious.
Let me tell you something, that's Michal,
she's just a really sensitive girl,
she always thinks everything that happens
is about her, she's a drama queen...
Itamar, stop.
If you bury your head in the sand, you'll never grow!
No, I'm fine, I just don't know
how to deal with what you're telling me,
you're not giving me anything I can...
-Alright then,
you know what? Let's talk it through.
-Go ahead, I'm listening.
It's because of her mom.
-What?
Maybe it's a cliché, but you only have one mom.
I really love her show, I really do.
It's been a while since there's been someone on TV
who doesn't feed us nonsense,
but comes and speaks clearly,
one, two, three.
I'm like that too.
Nowadays people are afraid to tell the truth,
they'd rather live in an unreal reality,
just like your Itamar.
That's how it is every Friday,
before the meal you always have to eat
a bit of their mom's schnitzels, yours.
Just a bit.
If I don't eat about five,
I can't handle it.
Itamar, it's a shame they didn't meet your first wife.
You could've made an amazing show
with depth.
Right, Tami?
-Right, right.
Not that I have issues with Michal,
on the contrary, she's a sweetheart,
she's vegetarian, and I make something special for her
every week,
but Smadar,
She was amazing with food,
loved my shleiks.
And she has no issues with her parents,
She's got her head on straight.
Everyone has their own dreams
and their own abilities. Right, Tamari?
Exactly, for sure, exactly.
I think Itamar divorced Smadar
because he feels inferior to her,
which is totally true.
Listen, she's a top-notch girl,
smart, she's got brains,
she's got money, she's got status,
and supportive parents.
No, I mean, don’t get me wrong,
he has a supportive mom too, yeah,
but she supports Smadar.
I hit my head, it threw me off.
You have to understand, I grew up like a princess,
I'm used to getting lots of warmth and love,
and now, with the nobles, it’s like,
I just want to die.
How many times can I hear:
Hey, Smadar. Oops.
What's up, Smadar? Oops.
No, you look nice, Smadar. Oops.
What about Smadar? We haven't heard from her in a while.
Like, maybe you want me to change
my name to Smadar and that's it?
Michal, sometimes in life
the cracked vase of others looks
better than our whole vase.
-Jealousy.
Jealousy? No, I'm dying.
I'm not jealous, ever,
jealousy is a really disgusting trait to me.
-Smadar,
Michal, jealousy, before it's a trait
is first and foremost an emotion.
So the emotion is disgusting to me, okay?
Look, if you ask me,
it’s all because of my mom.
Although if I remember correctly,
she only started acting like this
after they divorced.
I may have divorced him,
but I didn't divorce his family.
His mom! She's a lovely person, lovely.
Ever since we divorced, she just
kept calling and supporting.
I think it’s still hard for her
that we’re not together.
But you know, that’s life and it’s all for the best.
Why do you think it’s hard for her?
Because she keeps saying it.
Why create problems where there are none?
After all, if you look and look, you'll eventually find something.
Take, for example, our friends' daughter,
a single girl at 30.
They even took her to a psychologist.
This psychologist dripped and dug into her
and filled her head with bugs and problems,
and in the end, she fell in love with him.
Today she’s 42 and still single.
Lucky for me, I only have boys.
And you hugged them.
-By the book, exactly.
I raised them back when
you could still take off
a little shmear from the kid.
True, but! Raw, give me boys.
When I was a kid, no one thought
about maybe interrupting
their dad during Kiddush.
"On the sixth day
the heavens and the earth and all their hosts were finished."
Raz, Raz.
"And God finished on the seventh day His work which He had done
and He rested on the seventh day from all His work which He had done..."
You can tell him to stop with that already.
"And God blessed the seventh day and made it holy.
For on it He rested from all His work which God created to do."
Sabri Maranan.
Cheers.
"Blessed are You, Lord our God
King of the universe, who creates the fruit of the vine."
Amen.
Raz, sweetie, please pick the game.
"Blessed are You, Lord..."
-My stomach hurts.
"Our God, King of the universe, who has sanctified us with His commandments
and desired us, and His holy Sabbath with love..."
Raz, choose the game.
-"For You have chosen us and sanctified us..."
Okay, just shut up already.
"The sanctity of the Sabbath."
-Amen.
Cheers.
-Cheers.
I've been thinking for a while that there's a problem between them
and it needs to be either solved
or left unsolved.
I'm out, thanks for reminding me
why I don't need my own family.
Adam.
-Funny.
We're leaving too.
-Enough, come on.
Thanks, Riki, it was delicious as usual.
And you know, it was a bit weird
at first with the cameras, you know,
but once you get used to the cameras, you act normal.
Right, Shai?
-Of course.
Enough with this, enough.
Alright, thanks, bye, see you later.
Bye, sweethearts.
-Bye, girls.
Come here, my love, come.
Bye, Shabbat Shalom, thanks, Riki.
Great that you booked this show,
and I hope it solved all your problems.
Thank you very much.
-And thank God she has many.
What happened?
-She kicked me.
No, it must have been an accident.
Come here, listen to me! Listen carefully,
I'm not okay with you kicking Michal anymore,
did you hear what I'm saying?
No way... Look, you're in sandals,
you could have broken all your toes just now.
What is it?
One second. It's Smadar.
Yes, Smadari, what...
Yes, yes, we'll be there in a sec.
Okay, bye babe, b...
Alright, we gotta go, come on,
move it, move it, let's go.
Bye, bye, thanks.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom.
I don't want this to sound cliché,
but it's a shocking human nail.
Oudi, put this on your head.
-But my hair right now...
No buts, I don't have time for excuses. Put it on!
Nice.
Pay attention, in front of you there's a swing.
What you need to do is find it as a couple
and swing on it ten times.
Off you go.
Listen to me! Listen carefully,
I watched you on Friday,
and it didn't look good the second time around.
Okay.
Ah.
-A relationship is like a swing with blindfolds,
it's give and take when you don't know what you're getting.
Can you see me?
-It's me.
Ten.
Good job.
Listen, Itamar, from now on, Graneshter is Graneshter.
You have kids, you need to guide them,
show them how to behave and fit in.
A mom is just a mom! You only have one mom,
but sometimes you need to stand up to her
and spread your wings and fly.
And you, respect...
-Thank you.
Respect isn't something you take,
it's something you earn.
And the way to earn it is...
It's...
In the box.
-In the box.
Yeah.
Raziak
Bar
in
this is a given—
I think you got it.
We don't have time to waste on understanding.
From now on, I want to see actions.
-Actions.
I want to see them starting this Saturday,
clear? Yes.
Come on
and pass.
Pass me the salt.
Please.
Tamari.
Pass me the shleikler.
-Sure.
Thanks.
Can you?
Please?
Honey?
-I love you so much—
Wow, don’t talk to Michal like that, got it?
And you, enough with the nonsense, come on, enough,
take off the headphones, start eating with your mouth closed.
Act like well-behaved kids,
you didn’t come from the jungle.
Please.
What’s this? I don’t understand why we
have to do this.
Don’t you want to help your family?
-Of course, of course,
but why are we sitting here?
-That’s the plan.
What’s the deal? Explain, come on.
Shai and sit down!
Are you sure you’re the center of the universe
!that everything revolves around you,
when really you’re just on a carousel
with your eyes blindfolded.
Do you feel the energy?
-We feel it, we feel it.
And enough, enough...
Where did she go?
-Get up off the floor, you loser.
This is family! This is a big family, not a tree.
I don’t like this talk
because I don’t think there was a problem,
not with Itamar and not with his mom.
I keep my winter clothes up here.
But why didn’t you ask Shai to help you?
-Because I asked you.
Ugh, I’m going up with shoes.
-Take them off.
Mom.
-I keep the clothes in vacuum bags,
what Smadar bought me, it keeps the clothes nice.
Smadar knew how to buy me gifts.
-Yeah, true.
And Michal...
-No, she doesn’t have that.
No, what are you doing?
That’s your wife, you’re supposed to protect her.
No, Mom, just so you know, Michal is really trying.
What’s going on here?
-Mom, listen to me,
Michal is my wife, !I’m sure
there are sides of her you do like.
Sure, but this isn’t the place
and it’s not the time to say them.
Riki, being a mom is like riding
a springboard with your eyes closed.
I don’t get what’s going on here, we need to solve problems.
And we need to open a new front with the mother-in-law.
Guys, look him in the eyes,
What did Janusz Korczak say?
-More food?
No, kids are just short adults.
What’s the connection? How does that relate to Michal’s problems?
I just don’t get it.
I believe you. I called you here
first of all, because I wanted to say thank you
and I also wanted to invite you
to come with me tonight to a show.
Honey, it’s Saturday today.
-I know it’s Saturday,
but we need a break from the kids, so I thought...
Give and take.
-Sure, sorry.
You’re right, honey, it is Saturday.
So what can I do for you?
-No, you’re right, honey,
and what do you want to do...
-No, no, no, what do you want to do?
Hey, it’s Smadar the pest.
Hello, yes, what do you want?
Yes, they’re still filming.
Okay, bye.
What a leech.
Itamar, just a reminder,
that’s the mother of your kids, okay?
And kids...
They’re a heavy financial burden.
No.
-No...
And sometimes it’s...
Joy.
-Yeah.
Two weeks later, our camera
followed them like my shadow and me.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
-Hey.
My dear.
-Hey there.
Itamar.
-Dad, hey.
We missed you, even though it’s just been a week.
Wow, what a change Itamar made, a complete 360.
Yeah, but how do you feel?
-Happy,
pure happiness.
A Shabbat of...
My sister-in-law, Shabbat Shalom, Shabbat Shalom.
Honestly, he really is a new person,
wonderful, you wouldn’t recognize him.
But how do you feel?
Honestly, not great, a bit painful.
Not the head, the family.
-Ah.
Honestly, not great, a bit painful.
You couldn’t do a show like this
with Smadar and Itamar,
only Michal could organize such a farce, believe me.
Mom, I demand you stay out of his wife’s business.
I think that was a compliment.
Are we eating today too, Mom?
Of course, I didn’t just make tongue for nothing.
Everyone went crazy from this experience,
it was really, really nice,
heartfelt thanks
!you turned us into a warm, united family.
"Peace be upon you, angels of peace
angels on high
from the King of Kings
the Holy One, blessed be He"
Shabbat Shalom.
!It says in the tractate of Shabbat:
Don’t do to others what you hate for yourself.
Since every Saturday has a Saturday night.
I asked the couple: what are you taking from this together?
Listening, focus.
-Love.
A lot of love.
And really, the advice we got here
We’ll apply it forever.
-From now on.
Wow, babe, you crack me up...
But what's the most important thing?
Family, you know.
Good job.
-Bravo, Michal, bravo.
How cool.
Good job.
Just so you know, I thought this turned out well.
Really?
-Yeah, you all look very successful and nice.
No doubt this show opened my mind.
Tell me, those looks
you did in '81, in the beehive?
No, back then I didn’t know they were filming.
The ending was so emotional that I admit, I teared up.
No way, Pinchas.
Riki, you look stunning on screen,
You photograph amazingly, really.
Everything I said,
It’s just... the blow really confused me, I don’t...
-It’s okay.
It’s fine, sit down, things get out of context.
What does it matter? The main thing is you look amazing.
No one remembers what you said,
it’s important how you look.
So do you really think we came out well?
Because we totally rushed the ending,
We told him: okay, okay, okay,
just let him go already.
It really doesn’t look that way.
-No?
What, you both look perfect for each other.
I’m glad it’s like that between you, really.
-No, thank you.
Awesome and even better.
No way, Smadar.
Smadar, babe.
Babe?
-Shh...
Yeah, of course the kids are clean, of course.
Yeah, I remember your brother's wedding,
your husband’s brother today at...
Yeah, sure, bye.
-Say hi.
Like you didn’t just watch the show?
Babe, I saw it. Come on,
I don’t have the energy to be
assertive and all that right now,
Besides, I think she got a breast enlargement.
Her breasts?
-No, her ears. Of course her breasts.
I hugged her and I felt
something growing there.
You felt her breast?
-In the context of a hug. It’s not like I did...
That’s it, at the finale? Can we eat?
Tell me, do you think we need a coach?
For what?
-To tell us what our problems are.
Why, do we have problems?
One serious one.
-What?
That we don’t have problems.
-Yeah, no problem, come on,
Let’s get a coach,
I’ll tell you exactly what he’ll say to us.
Come on, let’s see you.
-Please.
First of all, you suffer from a self-esteem issue,
Your partner doesn’t give you self-respect,
Better one bird in the hand
than putting all your eggs in one basket.
And then kill a Turkish guy, why not?
Also, put that cloth bag on your head!
Because a relationship is like a lava flow
with your eyes closed,
It's a sure pleasure.
I didn't know you spoke in clichés.
-Please, drive.
Son...
-Son of what, hands on the wheel.
I don't want to.
-Sweetheart.
Step on it.
I can't handle this.
Or...
(A man
No problem, I'll tell you
exactly what he's going to say to the kid.
What's a coach?
-How do you say?
Just tell me about the problems.
Sorry.
Our cracked vase
makes other people's vases, which are more cracked,
look like their vases are whole
while ours is broken.
What did he say?
Respect isn't something that...