She's blinking again.
-What?
The neighbor downstairs. Who?
-She drags her leg. She blinks too.
Who would marry her?
-Come on, are you crazy?
The little one.
-So what?
So what? Honey, it's starting to worry me.
Enough. Come on, stop it. It'll pass.
-What if it doesn't pass?
You know I was looking
through the window, focused?
She can't sit for a minute in kindergarten.
-Because her teacher is boring.
Maybe she has attention issues?
Oh, really? And in ballet class
does she have rhythm and dance issues?
Come on, that's not funny.
Maybe we should give the girl Ritalin.
What? Seriously, did you hit your head?
I don't know where you grew up
but drugs aren't the answer.
It's not drugs, it's Ritalin, it's common.
It's drugs.
-It's medicine,
And there are people it can really help.
Like your mom.
-Parent involvement?
You started it.
-Everything's on you and you're clueless.
What an idiot.
-Maybe I need Ritalin too.
For you, Ritalin wouldn't help anymore.
Look at me, look at me and...
So, what's up?
-All good, really good.
How are the parents? Did you talk to them?
Yeah, they're good. Having fun.
Well, of course! A trip around the world is amazing.
I've always dreamed of doing something like that.
-You can.
Just say "trip around the world",
I'm out the door, no packing.
But Pinchas is a different story.
-You don't like sailing.
Pinchas doesn't like anything.
-Not true.
I love the kids.
And I don't like being away
from my kids and grandkids for so long.
Nice.
-Nice, nice, but what about me?
Shabbat shalom.
-Shabbat shalom.
Shabbat shalom, you already look worried.
Shabbat shalom, girls. Come here, come here, sweetie, come.
Einav, meet my oldest son, Shai.
Nice to meet you, Shai.
-The girls! This is his wife.
Sit down
Riki.
Einav is the daughter of Yoel and Nili from the cafeteria.
They went on a long trip, so I invited her
to eat with us so she wouldn't sit home alone like a dog.
I know that from my son. You're in the same boat.
He's a great guy, lives alone in Tel Aviv...
Mom, can I have a minute in the kitchen?
-Why?
Pinchas, go change your shirt.
Why do I buy you shirts?
What's wrong with what I'm wearing? Shai bought it for me.
If it's for me, really no need.
-No, no. There is a need.
You should see
how my little one dresses, like a model.
Mom...
-Okay, I'm coming.
Excuse me, Einavi, my baby needs me.
Alright, I think I'll go change
my shirt. Otherwise, she won't leave me alone.
Are you a boy?
-Boy-
Welcome to the Rosen family Shabbat dinner.
With us, it's much worse.
-Wait. You just got here.
So what's the story?
-What story?
Mom, we didn't make you with a finger, you know.
I know, Shai, I'm giving her a name
-Ew.
Does she know she's coming to a blind date?
-What blind date?
She's coming to have a meal with us
and on the way, she'll meet Adam.
What's so terrible about that?
-So Adam doesn't know either.
He'll kill you.
-Don't mess with my head.
She's a lovely girl, she's a clinical psychologist,
she's an only child.
Do you know what her parents do?
What?
-Millions. That's what they do.
They own the biggest concrete factory in the country.
And when they die, God forbid, everything will go to her.
So excuse me
for worrying about my kids' future.
Wait, are they going to die?
They went on a cruise around the world.
What's that got to do with it?
-Ships sink sometimes...
God forbid?
It's hot today, huh?
-It's not the heat, it's the humidity.
Yeah, what's humidity? You take a fish,
you put it in the air, it swims.
Because of the humidity.
-Yeah, the humidity.
What, what, what are you doing?
At work?
-Let's say.
I have a master's degree, I'm a clinical psychologist.
Wow, cool.
Uh... clinical, that you have...
By the way, I had a debate like that
with my husband just now, in the car.
A kind of theoretical debate, of course,
about Ritalin. What do you say
clinically about Ritalin?
What's your opinion?
-It depends.
On what?
-Why, for whom, why.
For the girl, for the girl.
-Has she been tested?
No, no, you know, it's kind of theoretical,
hypothetical.
-Look, on one hand,
there are a lot of people and studies
that are very much in favor of this medication.
Wow...
-But on the other hand,
there are also those who are very against giving drugs to kids.
Wow...
Hello.
-Adam?
Ah, Dad, what's up? I'll be at your place in a few minutes.
Great, great. I just wanted to warn you, Adam.
Mom brought someone here,
and I think it's for matchmaking.
Why?
-Why?
You know how Mom is with her nonsense,
so I just wanted to give you a heads-up, be ready.
Okay. Thanks, Dad. Bye.
-Bye
Honey, here's a cancellation. I'll drop you off at home.
I'm starving.
I'll buy a pita on the way.
Either yes or no.
-Yeah, but at some point
you need to form an opinion. Right?
-That's the most important thing.
Yeah. It's either give Ritalin or not.
Right, but on the other hand, you don't have to form an opinion.
You can wonder, investigate, see
what the best way is for you and your daughter.
So not to give it to her?
-Or yes.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
-Bye
Hey there.
-Where's Mom? I'm starving.
Meet Einav.
-Hey there.
Are you friends?
-No, no. Riki invited her.
And you came?
-I'm the daughter of their friends,
Yoel and Billy.
-Ah.
You're Yoel and Nili's daughter from the kibbutz?
-Yeah.
Do you know them?
-Only from the stories.
Mom! Where is she? I'm starving.
She's with Shai in the kitchen.
-Come on, he probably already finished my food.
All the schnitzels.
How does he always manage to get to me?
So, what's up, Shani?
-Good, what about you?
Good, what about you?
-Great. What about you?
Great, what about you? What?
You know I'm a clinical psychologist?
Who?
Me.
Oh, what a coincidence. I had a classmate
in high school named Einav.
Really.
No way.
But she's good.
-Clinical.
You're lucky you didn't finish off all my schnitzels.
)Y
Len and
Nani
..and
the
why Marivanl
K'
son Y
Mom, how did you manage to drag
the millionaire's daughter from the kibbutz here?
How do you know about them?
-She tried to set me up with her after I got divorced.
Everyone knows you got divorced.
You don't need to shout it out.
Now she wants to set her up with Adam.
-Why set her up?
She's a lovely girl, she's a clinical psychologist,
and you know what her parents do?
-Millions.
From what?
-Insurance.
And she?
-Only child.
What will happen when her parents die?
-God willing.
God forbid.
-God forbid.
Who will inherit all the millions?
-She will.
Wow...
-Mom's doing her homework.
And you went and married a shoemaker's daughter.
Tailor.
-Tailor, shoemaker, what's the difference?
Neither of them has a dime to their name.
And then Einav, my friend, told me she
doesn't want to and she'll wear what she wants,
so I told her: "Sorry, that's not acceptable to me."
In the end, look what came of her.
Anyway...
-I need to use the bathroom.
I'm in the middle of a story.
Fine, I know the ending,
you two argue and don't talk.
Come on, great, you ruined my punchline.
-Sorry.
Why...
A psychologist, huh?
-Clinical.
Yeah. So listen for a second,
I have a bit of a problem.
-No way.
Yeah. I mean, not me, my husband.
But it's about him. Right?
-If you want.
Every time we get into elevators
or crowded places
he immediately sticks to me
and starts touching me and kissing me.
He's your husband, he loves you.
-Yeah, but why in front of strangers?
Why in front of his kids?
No, he's kind of a perv in elevators.
And you know why that is?
-Why?
Because of his mom.
-Seriously?
Yeah. Riki. I mean, it's not
based on anything but that's how I feel.
What do you think?
-Look, it could be
that it really is related to his mom.
-I knew it.
On the other hand, it might not be.
-That...
Okay, she's coming, we'll talk about it later.
Anyway, I told her:
"Wear what I say and that's it."
Sit down, it's fine. I told him.
-What? To whom?
To Adam, that his mom is not normal.
Well, he already knew that. Right, Pinchas?
He knew that,
but he didn't know that there's a match waiting for him in the living room,
he didn't know that.
-What, is it a match?
Like a blind date?
Does she know she's being set up?
-No way!
Riki dragged her here with promises of homemade gourmet food.
Schnitzel and mashed potatoes is not gourmet, Pinchas.
-She's not normal.
We closed the circle.
What?
-I need to pee.
Oh, go ahead, go ahead. I’ll run to the living room,
to do some damage control.
Who were you talking about? You were definitely talking about me.
No way, Riki?
-No, we were talking about my friend,
the loser from high school.
Einav.
Not you, the whore.
Stop with this brothel. Einav, are you hungry?
We’re already sitting down to eat.
-Come on, come on,
you’re a psychologist, right? Because I have a dream
that keeps repeating itself.
-No way.
Yes, yes. I fall
into a tiny, tight black hole,
and a bunch of dwarfs come and start touching me all over.
What does that mean, you think?
-That you have a problem
with tight spaces. Right?
-No, that’s not true.
It means he’s messed up.
-Well, she’s not at work right now
and keep your perverted dreams to yourself.
Who’s perverted?
-Me.
Oh, of course.
Is the pervert the pianist?
-No, it’s the opera singer,
and no, it’s not.
-Are you sure?
Shai, come here for a sec.
-What..
Come here!
Coming, coming.
Wha_
Wait, wait, but I have another dream,
a really good one, too.
I dream I’m in an orphanage and I’m happy.
What does that mean, you think?
-Laugh, laugh at your mom,
but not for a second would you survive without me.
You’d be left in the dark like a dog.
Riki, he has a wife.
-Why are you putting words in my mouth?
I said he’s alone like a dog,
I didn’t say you’re alone like a bitch.
Honey, it started small
and now she’s blinking all the time.
Maybe she has Tourette’s or something?
-Maybe it’s just tics?
I had those when I was a kid.
You’re not giving her drugs.
Aren’t we having this conversation?
-Okay, okay.
But since I met
that Einav, the psychologist.
What, the heiress?
-Yeah, Adam’s match.
And what, what did the wise one say?
-She said Ritalin is great,
that sometimes it can work wonders
for those who take it.
That’s what she said?
-Yeah, yeah.
She also said Ritalin is a type of drug,
that sometimes it can hold back
a child’s creativity.
-So she said that too,
on the other hand, she also contradicted herself.
Of course, she’s a psychologist.
What, is that what they learn in their first year?
So she’s a really smart psychologist.
-Probably.
Great, honey.
-And on the other hand?
Also.
-Honey?
What tics did you have when you were little?
-Forget it.
Come on, tell me. Come on, you and me.
I used to hug boys in the showers.
Einav.
I have a dream too.
-No way.
Yes, yes. I dream I’m in a hug
and when I wake up I really struggle to sleep.
So maybe you should see a doctor.
You’ve studied for so many weeks and you’re not a doctor?
Einav, don’t pay attention to what he says.
You don’t have any hug. It’s just psychosomatic.
Sounds more like psychonazimat.
-Funny, babe.
What’s this, who’s that? Who’s asthmatic?
-Me.
You, obviously.
Babe, wanna come with me for seven minutes
in heaven in your parents' room?
No, I married a 12-year-old girl.
Sure, babe. Let’s go.
Michali, you only have five minutes,
not seven. We’re eating soon.
Seriously, what about the food? I’m starving.
Where’s the groom?
-Shh!
Who?
-Adam.
Adam?
-Shabbat sh...
Shabbat shalom.
-Shabbat shalom.
Adamika.
-Where have you been? I was really worried.
Meet.
-Einav?
Adam?
What are you doing here?
-What are you doing here?
This is my parents' house.
-What, do you know each other?
Yeah, of course. How are you, Einav?
I’m great. And you?
-I’m great.
All good, good vibes-
So, are you listening?
-Yeah, come on.
So I talked to that Einav, the psychologist.
-The millionaire.
She’s a millionaire?
-Yeah. For real.
What, is there a saying, “millionaire for real”?
What? No, not the weight, the material.
What? Never mind. Listen.
So I talked to her, and she says
there’s definitely a chance,
fifty percent, that your elevator phobia
is because of your mom.
What?
-Every time you’re making out with me,
when we’re in the elevator or tight spaces,
it’s because of your mom.
What? What?
I don’t... I don’t really know
how to deal with what you just said.
Never mind. I’m just letting you know
there’s a maximum chance of 50 percent
that every time you touch me,
it’s like you’re touching your mom.
What?
-Yeah, but only in elevators, babe.
The rest of the time, it’s me.
-What?
Yeah.
Alright, so food?
-What?
What?
What are you doing to me?
-Why am I suddenly to blame?
What did you do to her?
-I didn’t do anything to her.
Oh, I saw the looks you two were giving each other.
He had a thing once, okay?
It happens.
-Do you know who she is?
The daughter of the concrete millionaires, she’s an only child,
when her parents die, God forbid,
with God’s help, all their money will go to her.
I know. Come on.
What, did they wipe out all my schnitzels?
What did I raise? Is this how you know me?
I saved some for you.
-What...
Tell me, what, are you normal? What did you say to my wife?
Shai, right? Can I talk to you alone for a sec?
Yeah, sure.
-What..
What’s this, what did she say to her?
She made up that I have some fear
of tight spaces.
Oh, that? That’s trivial, Michali. Forget it.
I actually think all his problems
started when he was born...
Mom wanted a girl, after all.
They should call her Tamar.
-So she called him "Hey Tamar."
Right. Itamar, you were always
wrapped in hugs and kisses.
He was as pretty as a girl until Adam was born...
Bo, enough already. Don't mess with my head. That's enough.
Honey, there are percentages saying it's this.
But what is she even doing with my wife?
What... she messed with her head.
-It's okay, turns out Adam messed with her first.
What's going on?
-Listen.
You seem the most sane here.
Now, as you already understand,
Adam and I have a bad history together.
-Yeah.
Since you know her better than I do,
How do I get out of here without offending Riki?
No. No way.
Are you sure?
On the other hand,
No. No way.
She'll get offended.
That's nice.
Bo, why did you break up?
Tamari...
-That was a long time ago.
Who remembers?
-Thanks.
Drop it. It's been a few weeks.
There was.
-Seven-thirty. But who remembers?
Why didn't you tell me about her?
I actually told you guys,
about the one who took the test.
Yeah, but who remembers?
Do me a favor.
Alright, I'm out.
Riki, can I have a minute with you?
No way.
Look, Riki, I love you
but really, I have to go.
What test is he talking about?
-Pregnancy test.
I have a test I do
for guys I like.
I have a positive test from a friend,
I show it to them the morning after.
No way, I don't believe you.
I think that's a genius idea.
Is that what they taught you in university,
in clinical psychology?
No wonder you're alone, Einav.
No, you don't do that.
-What arrogance...
What did you do?
What do you think?
No, I said from the start that something's off with her.
Am I interrupting?
Yes.
-No, no, no.
What do you mean? We're just about to head out.
Because four people in this room is super cramped.
And I was already afraid Itamar
would start hugging me, touching me.
Shai, big problem. I...
Is this from Mom too?
-What did I do now?
Nothing. Shall we go to the table?
Yes.
-Yes. Kids, food.
Come on, come on kids.
Wait, sweetie. Come here, come here, come to Grandpa.
Why is your eye red?
Wait, wait, keep it open for a sec, honey.
Oh, you had a hair. That's it, go to the table.
How long has she been blinking like that?
-Uh...
Nothing, it just started now, just now.
Come to the table!
Look, I'm here just to
not offend your mom.
Here we go again with the arrogance.
Oh, you're not pretending now?
-Come on, really.
Because even if I told you
that you're a bitter single girl from Tel Aviv
with a predictable cat, you'd say
I'm just pretending. Right?
I'm bitter?
-You stopped getting married.
Who even wants to marry you
with your nonsense at home?
Who wants to marry you? Who talked about marriage?
Who even wants to touch you?
-Who knows what diseases you have?
Pseudo-intellectual.
-Primitive.
We're not waiting for them.
-How long is this taking?
I'm hungry.
Itamar Marshmallow, go call your little brother-
-Why me?
She asked me to, Itamar Griva.
Like two little kids, huh?
Yeah, but this time I have kids of your own.
Raz! Raz!
Shluf Leaf, go call Uncle Adam to come.
So I understand that none of my kids
will marry a millionaire.
A concrete millionaire.
Rivka, that's it, I can't take it anymore,
I'm really sorry.
I took a pill half an hour ago,
I took "Globin",
I'm hungry, I want it now. I want it now.
Here she comes back.
Oh, come on, Shluf Leaf, come here.
Where's Uncle Adam?
What did she say?
I don't know, I think
you should have sent someone else.
Is everything okay, honey?
I understood "iPhone."
Yeah, iPhone everyone... she loves to say iPhone.
It has nothing to do with anything. She says iPhone.
She uses it a lot, on the iPhone.
Sweetie, what's on your iPhone?
I'm sorry but I'll pass on the meal.
Say hi to the parents if they come back.
It was nice to see you again.
Come on
let them come
Hello.
-Come on
Come on..
You think? What about the food?
Go wash your hands.
They're Bradman.
-Thanks.
No, I should thank you.
-For what?
For the little one's blink.
Nonsense.
-No, really, thank you,
for not making me do the "I told you so" celebrations
in front of your mom.
As part of us trying
to provide the girls a better world
I hope we're doing
the right thing for them.
Yeah, but it won't help you.
-What do you mean?
Because when the girl grows up and sits on the couch
of her clinical psychologist
in the end, she'll blame you.
-That's true.
But on the other hand, you're not less to blame.
That's true, but on the third hand...
There's no third hand.
-That's true.
Where's the groom?
Adam! Oh... Shai!
Why, what would you do to me?
Yeah
come on
She said being a messy person is a great thing.
And if you give it to someone, they
can work wonders for that person.
Is that what she said?
-No, I messed up the text.
That's not what she said.
What?
She really drilled it into her head.
-Turns out Adam drilled it into her first.
He really got to her!
So, what's up with you?
You know I'm a clinical psychologist?