Come on, sit down, what did I want to tell you?
-How should I know, babe?
I still can't read your mind.
How do you call it?
The thoughts.
-Funny.
It made me laugh, what do you want?
Come on, I wanted to tell you something.
Fine, dude, so I guess it’s not that important.
-What an idiot I am.
Stop, don’t say idiot in front of the girls,
they’ll think that’s what you are.
Oh, I remembered.
Anyway, it wasn’t that important.
Come on, what, now you’re gonna tell me.
No, I think my parents
had their anniversary this week.
What do you mean "think"? Why do you think?
Because my mom told me on Shabbat
that it would be or something like that,
No big deal, it’s just saying congratulations.
Tell me, are you normal?
I didn’t buy anything, why didn’t you tell me?
What happened to you? It’s not a silver wedding,
just a regular anniversary, nothing special,
no need for a gift.
-What does that have to do with it?
You know your mom will never forgive me for this.
Babe, my mom has three sons,
she’s used to it,
she doesn’t even expect it, she says so herself.
Fine, but I’m a daughter and his wife
and she does expect it from me.
Because you’re a woman?
-Yeah.
So what are you really saying to me?
Tell me, are you crazy?
-Yeah.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Where have you been? I was really worried.
Riki, congratulations on the anniversary.
-Thanks, sweetheart.
Mom, congratulations.
And I booked a place for the four of us to celebrate the event
at the most popular restaurant in Tel Aviv.
Isn’t it a waste of money? You didn’t have to.
I thought so too, but...
Where’s the restaurant?
-Come on, it’s that philosopher guy from MasterChef.
The philosopher.
Oh, I love his place.
Shabbat Shalom.
Meet my baby.
-Oh my.
This is my brother and his wife.
Sit down.
-Shh, nice to meet you.
Baby is a serious name.
What does it mean, that you play the violin?
No.
Because that could’ve been funny.
Think about it, baby...
I play the viola.
What a beautiful bouquet, Riki.
I got it as a gift for our anniversary.
-Really lovely.
I have an artistic trick for arranging flowers.
There’s something really calming about this arrangement,
very round, very nice.
Feng Shui?
No, today it’s Tao.
You’ve probably heard of yin and yang
but not of wei wei wei.
Oh wei wei?
It means "doing without action" in Japanese.
I’d love it if you could bring me a bouquet like this on Wednesday.
Wednesday?
-Yeah, Wednesday is my birthday.
Did you forget that?
-Just kidding with you.
Of course not, what, could I forget something like that?
I already bought a kitchen and everything.
-Really?
Let’s just do it straight, it’ll be quicker.
Mom.
-And even sex.
Interesting.
-Sex with...
Mom, where are the flowers from?
-Where do you think?
You won’t believe what he did to me.
-Pinchas.
He took me on a flight over the country
with a picnic parking spot.
-Wow.
What a cool gift, that’s romantic.
I wouldn’t wish that on my enemies.
Where’s Dad?
-In the kitchen, looking for a marker.
So I’ll go say hi and ask where the bouquet’s from.
That sounds like an amazing gift, what is it?
-Do me a favor,
it was a nightmare.
I didn’t believe I’d survive
to tell you this. Sit down, sit down.
Hey, Dad.
-Hi, Shai, what’s up?
Want an egg?
-No, no.
No?
-No...
Listen, I messed up,
I just found out Shani has a birthday this week
and I have no idea what to get her.
Shai, relax, you didn’t mess up,
you’re not supposed to remember dates.
Chill out.
Your wife’s birthday?
-Not at all.
It’s her job to remind you,
you have enough on your plate,
you’ve got a family to support, a house to manage.
No, Dad, it’s 2011
so I’m not sure your theory holds up.
It’s not about theory or the year,
it’s about evolution and nature.
A man doesn’t have the gene to remember dates...
Yeah, yeah, we don’t have
access to that part of the brain.
And women do?
What do you think they did in the cave
while we were out hunting mammoths?
What?
-They sat and doodled on the walls of a calendar.
What, were there dates back then?
-They invented dates.
Look, this month, for example, like a cycle,
four weeks, 28 days.
I didn’t know that.
And how do you think I remembered
my wedding anniversary?
Did Mom remind you?
-She wrote it on my forehead in mirror writing.
So you took her on a flight over the country.
Yeah, so I could enjoy a bit too.
But what should I get her? Something for her, something for the house.
With your years of wisdom, you have no insight on this?
Whatever you bring will be wrong.
So how do I get out of this?
-Take her on a flight over the country,
an amazing, romantic experience,
Mom screamed the whole flight, it was something else.
No, no, I don’t think so.
-And the view from above...
What am I saying when you can see everything.
Look, we filmed everything,
our wedding anniversary on the ninth of... the year 5772.
No, no, I missed one thing, Shai.
-What?
I should’ve hired a photographer to capture
the nausea from the night after.
I was nauseous all night.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Where have you been? I was really worried.
-What were you worried about?
I know...
Don’t ask what Dad did to me.
No, don’t tell me he also
washed your dry cleaning in the machine.
Next time you get close to the washing machine.
Jerk.
-Trash.
What do you mean? He took her on a flight over the country.
What, did he win "Philobi"?
-I'm serious, babe.
What do you mean? That's my gift for our anniversary.
Come on, when did you have it?
-This week.
Not on purpose. Itamar, I'm dying here.
It's fine, I don't expect Mambo
to remember stuff like that.
Why didn't you remind me, babe?
-What?
So, when are we eating?
Is there schnitzel? I'm going to grab some.
Babe, don't fill up,
just a reminder we have another dinner today.
I remember, I remember.
Come on, so what happened?
What?
Long story short...
Mom, just a reminder we've heard this story already.
Yeah, but you haven't heard how Dad came
and told me he has a surprise
and that I shouldn't eat anything.
Yeah, but you told that, Riki.
Yeah, but Michal didn't hear.
-I didn't hear.
I thought he was going to
surprise me with medical tests,
otherwise, why fast?
-Why indeed?
Buy her some jewelry.
-Jewelry?
Why is everyone swimming in money like you?
I'm telling you, take her on a flight in the sky.
Come on, come see how beautiful this is,
I'm going to put it on DVD.
Dad, Dad, not a word to Shani, okay?
Because she doesn't know anything.
Of course.
What's the rush? You finished the schnitzels.
Michal is dragging me to dinner at her friends' place.
Not fun.
-No.
I hate her friends,
a bunch of freeloaders.
Living together in some room, five roommates.
A filthy room where just sitting there
you could catch a disease.
They're all vegetarians, only eating the food
they grow
in the 'filthy room,
you get what I mean?
What’s going on? Where are you?
Why are you leaving me there alone?
Can I have a schnitzel?
-Take one, here.
So, who’s that girl?
-Flute girl.
Like a flute.
-Like a flute. Wiping in its shade.
And viola.
Really?
Cute.
-Yeah, yeah.
I've been with her for two days.
-Right.
And it's serious.
-Yeah.
Until now, we've only hung out at my place,
but she wants to go out today,
I have no idea where to take her.
You know, she's a bit...
What, flexible?
-What, makes a lot of noise?
Also. But no, I meant she's...
A hipster from Tel Aviv.
-Hip...
What's a hipster?
Is it related to the trio?
-No, no, come on.
What you used to call a philosophical Tel Aviv girl.
Honestly, I'm disappointed.
I had nausea all night.
That's it, it's ready. Where are the boys?
Shaiko, Tamari, Adamkia,
come see the horror movie.
Why like that, Riki?
I wasn't wearing makeup, I didn't know they were filming,
Seriously, Mom.
Come on, we're here, let’s go.
So, as you already know
I planned a surprise for Mom.
We know-
-we know-
We know.
What I'm telling you now happened before the movie.
Early in the morning, I covered her eyes
and drove her in the car.
I sat the whole way, it was great.
-Yeah.
On the way, she told me she didn't do an enema.
He told me to fast, I thought
we were going for a colonoscopy.
In hindsight, I regret we didn't do it.
Then we got to the airport,
I took off her eye cover...
Here you go.
Press it.
-I'm pressing.
-I pressed.
Oh, it's starting.
That's it, Riki, you can take off the scarf.
Huh? Huh?
Pinchas, where did you bring me?
Riki, I know you think I forgot
but I didn't forget,
how could I forget that 43 years ago...
-2, 42.
Where did you bring me, Pinchas?
Like the cooking holiday of old,
that was full of joy,
that's how I want to lift you up.
-What?
Pinchas, where did you bring me?
Riki, I want to lift you up
high to the sky like my love for you.
How sweet.
-Meet Omram, our photographer and pilot.
Oh wow.
Where did you bring me? Why didn't you tell me they were filming?
Right, Pinchas, it's so romantic, it's lovely.
Now I understand why you felt nauseous, Mom.
Looks nice, Dad.
-Right, it's stunning, Pinchas.
Really beautiful, Dad, good job.
It would have been nice if you guys! Now
turn around and go home.
But that's where the nightmare began.
For an hour, I was stuck
in a matchbox in the air.
Good thing our country is tiny, I'm telling you,
Give more back to the Palestinians.
Here comes the takeoff.
What's that noise?
-That's the engine noise.
Yeah, I forgot to tell you
that the engine was with us in the matchbox.
Pinchas, this thing is dangerous.
I told you: this is the perfect gift.
What is it, Mom, are you yelling or yawning?
-Both.
It was scary and boring at the same time.
Why boring? The view from up there was amazing,
it's a really interesting way to see
all the places you've been
in the last year from a bird's eye view.
Look, now we're passing
over Assaf Harofeh Hospital.
Honey, with all due respect to your dad,
if you do something like this to me
I’ll look better than the plane.
I think I’ll jump myself.
Wow, I can't stand this music,
it's so '92.
-Right,
even though there's something about the combination of the engine noise
that makes it interesting, right?
For sure.
-Absolutely.
If you're Helen Keller.
Now we're flying over Beilinson.
A very interesting way to see Beilinson.
What’s this meal?
I'm just happy to see your mom.
Just kidding, just kidding,
That’s the chimney of the Beilinson laundry.
Seven.
You know, I have an acquaintance
who does modern classical music.
And he sampled a loop from that piece.
N'
!And `
Rabbi
Munir
your]
0 .
Classic
It flows in classical music,
Music that’s atonal,
meaning it has no melody.
It’s also aharmonic, with no harmony,
And also akinetic, with no rhythm.
A-music, like there’s no music.
Moshe! Just like that.
Honestly, someone recently burned me a CD
of an Israeli, it’s amazing.
Tal Lebanese?
I can’t believe you know him.
He’s amazing, he plays the organ,
mixing in a sound like an air drill and...
!Texts from the yeshivas.
-Texts from the yeshivas.
What a piece. No, you’re kidding,
we’re going to dinner tonight
where Tal Lebanese is performing
with stuff from his new album.
No.
-Yes, yes.
Is he going to perform "Yimloch"?
-Amen.
"Yimloch, God, forever, your God, Zion..."
What’s that? What’s that? No, what... what...
-How cool.
Honey, come into my office for a sec.
Where to?
-To the balcony.
Okay.
"Hallelu..."
Wait, wait, wait,
Now we’re right above
Beit Levinstein, where I was in rehab.
How nice.
Where was the picnic in the end?
-By the beach at the Banim.
So Dad, call me when you’re
over Laniado Hospital in Netanya, okay?
Adam, come for a brother talk.
Sit down, sit down, sit down,
Now comes the part where Riki almost throws up.
Oh, God, God.
What happened?
-Listen for a sec, bro,
What should I buy Shani for her birthday?
How should I know?
What do you mean how do I know?
You’re out and about, you’re dating,
you know what’s trending, what’s cool,
Awesome, stylish.
Definitely not you with those '80s phrases.
What did you buy a girl recently?
-You think I buy gifts?
No, that sends a bad message, no... not right.
Hey, maybe you have an idea for me
where to take Kinneret?
I need to impress her.
The last time I went out it was
to a pub in Petah Tikva.
-Stylish.
Perfect.
I don’t understand why you’re getting upset.
-What? What?
אני לא מבינה מה אתה מתעצבן.
-מה? מה?
It's not enough that I have to sit
in this tiny, stinky apartment.
With your pathetic friends.
And eat a salad of rotten leaves
they grow in the middle of the room...
Their apartment isn't stinky.
-Honey, they have a pile of trash on the balcony.
It's not trash, it's compost.
-Honey, compost is trash.
Speaking of trash,
There's no way I'm sitting there
listening to your Syrian friend
playing a drill
and singing cantorial pieces, that's not happening.
Wait, hold on, what are you telling me here,
that you’re thinking of canceling?
I'm not thinking, I'm canceling,
I'm not going to that crap.
You know what, Itamar, fine, don't come.
No. I have to go to every boring event
you drag me to
with your boring friends.
And once it was my turn...
But you know what, you don't want to come?
Fine, don't come, just don't come.
Here’s Laniado Hospital.
Sh.
Just imagine I’d rather
be at Laniado than on this flight.
What’s up, Dad, did you get to the hospital?
Just now, you almost missed it, it’s a small hospital.
Ugh, I’m going crazy from the noise of that black "Spitfire."
It’s a "Cessna."
-It’s loud.
What did you talk about with Adam?
Just that he’s looking for a place to take Alin the baby.
What’s wrong?
-Itamar.
What did I miss?
You’re aging thirty years.
Here, look at this.
-What is it, a health fund?
No.
-An X-ray clinic?
Hof HaBonim.
-I’m dying.
What, what happened, honey?
I’m leaving Itamar.
-What?
Yeah.
You’re joking.
-No.
I’m serious as Riki’s face.
What, what did he do?
-He doesn’t want to come with me to my friends.
That’s it?
-That’s the straw that broke the camel’s back.
Enjoy your meal.
-Thanks.
What?
-No, no, nothing.
You know, Michal, if you two break up,
it would make Riki very, very happy.
Oh, I didn’t think of that.
Well, the flight and landing went pretty smoothly.
That was the good flight,
now comes the picnic.
-Classic picnic. A blanket,
breakfast fit for kings.
The pilot is also a chef, he served white...
Wind, sand, cold, and noise.
What’s up, what did I miss?
-Landing.
And arriving at the devil's meeting.
-Lovely. Itamar, come here for a sec.
What?
-Come, come, come.
Horrors of the world,
the butt hole of Israel.
Tell me, what are you doing?
-About what?
About the fact that Michal is leaving you.
What leaving?
-Leaving, leaving,
and she’s available to anyone.
והרי היא מותרת לכל אדם.
What, because of dinner
at her annoying friends' place?
Shani, I can't go there,
I can't stand that music,
I just can't...
And if your brother comes with you, will it be a bit easier?
What, are you guys coming with me?
How sweet.
No.
Eggs Benedict and a mess.
That's why I fasted.
Rotten eggs and white with nonsense,
I can't believe you brought that here.
Riki, can you come here for a sec?
Hey, is there any chance you want to go
to that concert of that drill guy?
Lebanese?
Lebanese.
-Of course, but Adam has plans.
No, that's nonsense, Adam's a considerate guy, come on.
He'll definitely compromise, he's flexible.
Yeah, I know.
Adam, can you tell me for a sec,
is there any chance you want
to go to a concert tonight?
His plans can be for another day.
Yeah, because...
-I promise.
Okay, fine.
Go.
Babe, I'm sorry.
I'm afraid "sorry" this time is too little, too late.
Enough, babe, enough,
I'll go with you to your friends
and I'll stay for your concert.
Really?
-Yeah.
Why?
-What do you mean "why"?
Why? What's the sudden reason you want to come?
Because I want to meet them, babe,
I want to know your world,
I want to know who your friends are, what you like,
what music you enjoy listening to.
If I get to hear some strong episodes along the way,
then wow, that's a huge bonus.
Mamo
Amam
Hey, is there any chance
you could bring Riki too? She really wants to come.
Babe, I already know them so well
that I invited her already.
-Enough
I love you, you're perfect.
-Thanks, babe.
What thanks, be ashamed.
Babe.
Can't argue, your wife is great.
You know, you have to know how to choose them
when they're ready.
You need to buy her something nice, okay?
-Sure.
Don't be stingy, jerk.
That was a terrible picnic.
We've already been through a few disasters.
Okay, I'm done.
-You're done?
I can't take this anymore.
Here they go.
What's wrong with you?
I'm dying.
Don't you have a concert to go to?
We're already heading out.
Aren't they already done with this house?
Unzai
Beni
Can I bother you with a problem?
Go ahead, sweetie.
-Okay.
It's about the gifts.
-Are you talking about Dad's gift?
No, no,
I'm looking for a gift that comes from the heart
and shows my love for my wife.
Just like you're your father's son.
I'm happy, I think.
Do you have any ideas that you...
What happened, Mom, where are you going?
I need to talk to Pinchas.
Pin...
-Why do the kids have to think
it was so terrible?
Okay, it messed up,
it wasn't accurate
like their ads online,
but I did it with all my heart,
I wanted to surprise you.
Sorry.
-Sorry.
Sorry?
I know you're not used to seeing this but...
Turns out I was wrong this time
and I should have told everyone
what’s nice and good about your gift.
I love you.
!I love you more.
Thanks.
-What "thanks"?
Shame on you.
But not a word to Shai.
-Of course, of course.
So, what should we buy?
I'm thinking maybe Tal Lebanoni's new CD,
maybe with some cute little jewelry on the side
and then I got this huge mushroom by my knee
not exactly but kind of, bam bam bam,
!I have to put on some cream
because it was really gross.
No, she...
So what's going on?
-Just a standard Friday.
Not standard at all.
I'm saving your whole family.
I can't take this noise anymore.
Come on, let's turn it off.
-Yeah. Bam bam bam.
This is the way back home, you didn't come back the same way.
You see? That's Hillel Yaffe Hospital in Hadera.
The engine's about to fail.
Yeah, you can already see
the lights of Rambam Hospital from afar.
Dad, when are we getting back to Ichilov?
-In about fifteen minutes.
Can we maybe turn down the sound
of this engine noise?
Wait a second.
-Thanks, Riki.
And right here,
suddenly the plane's engine shuts off.
-What?
The engine shut off.
I love you.
-I love you too.
Okay, I fixed it
but we have to try to land.
And after that, we rushed to the airport and home.
For this moment, it was all worth it.
This is the most beautiful wedding gift I've ever received.
Okay, I have to quote you. No, I'm dying.
So, are we eating today too?
-Honey?
A little.
I'll go tidy up.
Maybe in the meantime you want
me to play Tal Lebanoni's CD for you?
I happen to have it with me.
-Of course, come prepared for the show.
I love rehearsals.
I'm telling you, it's a wonderful gift.
How wonderful, Pinchas? You could've been killed.
What's new?
So, have you found something to buy her for her birthday?
Dad, I could kill you myself right now.
Isn't it wonderful?
Tell me, what is this horror?
Sorry bro, you're going alone.
So how much money were you thinking?
It's not about the money, it's about how you feel.
So how much do you feel
you want to spend on the gift?
According to the respectable gift.
-Yeah, that you don't know what it is.
I've already embarrassed myself, haven't I?
Yeah.
Do you want me to help you solve the problem?
I guess you know way better than I do.
What do you like?
-Got it.
So congratulations, babe.
-Thanks.
Do you have an idea yet?
How much money were you thinking?
-It's not about the money,
it's about how you feel.
I'll feel wonderful.
Well, I'm already not feeling so good.
No, no, no...
You drilled that into my head,
into my head, my mind, my brain, my forehead.
It would be nice if we were going home now,
taking a detour and going back home.
What?
Isn't it enough that I'm going to sit in the apartment...
Dad, aren't they already knocking on this house?
What happened?
Did a hair get stuck in your throat?
Wow, this schnitzel is divine.
What are you a...
Oh, this is the first time.
Tom is no longer a virgin with schnitzels.
Tom lost his schnitzel virginity.