It's a workshop on thinking outside the box.
The bummer is it's in the water in Eilat.
-What, cool.
What's cool?
It's logic puzzles for kids,
like how to connect four cubes with nine lines,
Really, what? I'm great at puzzles and riddles,
Do I need a course for that?
Plus, those puzzles have nothing to do with reality.
The course isn't cool, it's the water in Eilat that's cool.
Think about it, I'll organize it with the girls,
we'll go down to Eilat together,
we'll all be at the same hotel.
Bye
Hotel in Eilat.
While I'm stuck in those boring courses
and dumb lectures,
you'll be busy doing
impressions of shawarma by the pool?
So here you go, babe, here's your first exercise
on how to think outside the box:
How do you skip the lectures for the pool?
I don't want to skip, I don't want to go at all.
First, they should teach everyone to think inside the box.
Just so you know, I'm great at that.
At thinking outside the box?
-No, at skipping.
You know what, I'll give you a riddle.
-Come on, give it to me.
And if you manage to solve this riddle,
we're off the whole Eilat thing. Okay, girls?
-Cool
The evil king was in love with the beautiful miller's daughter
who obviously didn't want to marry him.
Forget about them for now, come on, I'm good
at practical stuff, not spiritual nonsense.
And then the king said to the miller's daughter,
Very much, sh'.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Please.
Babe.
-What's with the cardboard?
It's a table we ordered two weeks ago for the dining area.
Enjoy.
New.
-No, nice table.
Yeah, it's nice,
we saw a picture of it on the computer,
we bought it on "Buy A Bye Bye."
What, you bought a table online?
-Yeah, why, what's wrong with that?
No, great, welcome to this century.
Welcome to this century.
We got it today.
It arrived completely unassembled.
And it's not complicated to put together?
Do you know how much they charge for assembly?
What nonsense, Dad. Shai will help you,
he'll do it in two seconds.
What? Shai is great at puzzles and riddles,
but not at skipping.
-Thanks, thanks,
I believe we'll manage.
What are you doing with the old one?
We need to...
Leave that for now,
next week I'll assemble the new one.
For now, the old one is fine.
No, no, no, you're not assembling it alone.
You guys put it in the hallway
and assemble the new one here.
How in the hallway? It'll block the whole hallway.
No, there's no place to put it here either.
They'll be here soon! Moshe's coming, we'll take it down together.
תכף מביאים! משה באים, נוריד אותו ביחד למטה.
What, throw it away?
What is this, no one will buy it,
it’s got a defect, you know.
What, like Dad, are we really throwing out the old table?
We’re not throwing it away,
We’re discarding it. It is what it is.
It came with instructions.
Came with instructions?
-Yeah.
Okay, that’s doable.
-Doable? That’s page A.
There’s a page B.
N'
Nanny
Nl
You, 'bo'
And there’s a page C too.
S Sason,
. ְ
Sh
A
4! ,
Z'vun
Rannai
It continues like this, it goes up to Z.
-Right.
No, no, no, wow, I said that.
-Wow, wow.
This table has a history,
it’s not just an object.
For men, everything is just objects,
they have no feelings about anything, nothing at all.
Do you know how much food has been served on this table?
Every Friday, every Saturday, all the holidays.
Weeks upon weeks.
Mom, you talk like it was back in the day
when tables were still in black and white.
I remember when you bought this table,
it was in '95 on the shopping channel, right?
-Yeah.
It was the first thing we bought on TV.
-Right.
Honestly, I wasn’t that crazy about it.
I’ll tell you a little secret,
Dad always tests
every new partner one of the kids
brings by the wobbly side
to see how they handle it.
Please tell me,
is Shai from the word gift
or is it an acronym for Shmuel Yosef?
It’s from English. Sh’, shy.
Oh, you’re shy?
No, that was obviously a joke.
Oh no, the table is wobbly.
-What, can you feel it?
Can I have a moment?
-Sure, sure.
I think I have a solution.
It’s perfectly fine.
Alright.
-Shai!
Right, how time flies.
As soon as he put down the five shekels
we knew he was for us.
Hey, Silvan, what’s up?
We’re assembling a new table for the dining area.
Thank God, it’s about time.
Come on, Moshe, help me
take the old one downstairs.
Easy peasy.
-Wow, enjoy it.
Where are Shai and Mom?
-In the kitchen. You have... never mind.
Well, if you need help with the assembly, just say.
-We’ll manage. Don’t worry, I’m here.
Shabbat Shalom.
Enjoy! What’s going on?
-Nothing.
What nothing, Mom, why are you sad?
-Because of the table.
It’s not clear, Mom, it was fine.
Someone from the street probably adopted it.
It’s not the table, it’s...
it’s everything that happened around it, it’s...
It’s memories, 16 weeks is a long time.
Wow, I remember the first time
you brought Moshe here,
he sat on the wobbly side.
Please tell me,
Katz is from the word Katz
or is it an acronym for Cohen Tzedek?
Acronym! Moshe is named after Mike Barbat.
My mom was a fan.
The table's wobbling.
-What, can you feel it?
Can I have a moment?
-Sure.
Do you happen to have a screwdriver?
I can take off the second leg,
that’ll fix the issue.
At first, I thought he...
He's really funny, right?
-Yeah.
Totally, he's hilarious.
What, it was just a check-up.
A check-up, like your spicy one isn't enough.
It's easier to survive in a special forces unit.
I made the good stuff just for you two.
And honestly, you both did pretty well
with your husbands.
I think maybe we should turn this
upside down.
It needs an angle, it should go like this.
So an angle but with the legs up upside down.
No, you need to take out
both right legs first
and then the rest will come out.
Heavy as hell.
I really don’t think they got
this table through that door.
Right, when Rachel bought the table on the shopping channel,
she ordered a helicopter
to land it here on the balcony.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom, Shabbat Shalom.
There's a problem.
-What's going on here?
What, are you taking this table out of here?
Yeah, come help, or we won't get out of this.
No need, I have a genius idea, come on,
let’s just flip it here like this.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
-What?
Why flip it? I say Moses! better,
I say set it on fire.
-Better.
Stand it on its side and it’ll pass.
That’s exactly what I was thinking next.
Hold it up.
Pull.
-Wait, wow, my back.
Great.
-Wow.
That came out smooth.
-Easy peasy.
You guys need to think outside the box.
Do me a favor, don’t say
that phrase around my wife,
or I’ll have to sleep outside the box tonight.
Come on, Manny, help me lower it down.
My back.
Moses.
-I have an exemption.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
How are you doing?
What happened, is it Tisha B'Av today?
No, there’s a little emotional thing around the table,
may their memory be a blessing for "Come on, man."
Didn’t you see the boys over there
trying to assemble the new table?
Not really, but I hope
they know how to put tables together
better than taking them apart.
-Why?
Because if I hadn’t helped them,
they would’ve flipped it and set it on fire.
Why set it on fire?
-Ash is easier to clean up.
Yeah, and then we can spread it on the roof.
Why flip it?
-No, no. Don’t worry, Rachel,
they didn’t flip it, they took it out whole.
Of course, the table deserves a final salute.
What final salute? It was a broken table.
I remember coming to you for the first time,
you still thought of me as the odd one out.
Can you tell me, please,
is the name Alin from the word Alin
or is it an acronym for "I love you"?
No, it’s always Alin.
Oh, that’s rude, but the table is wobbly.
-What, you feel it?
Can I have a moment?
-Sure.
In a nutshell
also
already
and it looks bad
We could sue the company that did this
and make a few thousand shekels.
She’s perfectly fine.
She’s fine, really fine.
Now it’s going to rain on him, sunshine,
he’s "ruined."
I didn’t think a table could be so sad.
What a packaging. Just opening the package like this
needs a packaging instruction sheet.
It’s hermetic, buddy, it comes in the sea.
In swimming?
No, in running.
So why all the plastic?
What, isn’t it a shame for the Earth?
If it falls in the water, it should float.
It was a disaster operation from the manufacturers.
-The hardest part was the turns.
And where did you put it?
-In the lot across,
where the neighbors put their boxes.
Ah.
-Yeah.
Alright, mission: assemble the new table.
We need to eat dinner on it.
No problem, bring the instruction sheet, we’ll manage.
Silvan, if I do the "A, B, C" joke to him,
will it make you laugh again?
Here are the instructions.
No problem, nonsense.
-No problem, nonsense. This is page A,
this is B,
this is C,
this is D,
this is...
What’s going on, why are you all here so down?
It’s because the dining table got thrown in the trash.
No way, what’s so bad about that?
Ugh, what memories do we have
from that old table?
Just failures.
Do you know how many men that table has seen?
We know, we know.
Can you tell me, please,
is Eli from the word Eli or is it
an acronym for Eliyahu Lulu Israel?
Earthquake.
Ruby is from the word Ruby
or is it an acronym for Reuven Nissim?
What, is it noticeable?
Sammy is from the word Sammy?
Why, do you have a problem with my name?
-No.
Just because I’m Burmese, you’re doing this to me?
I didn’t get it.
Did he come through Burma?
-I don’t know.
Can you tell me, please, is the name Dan from the word Dan
or an acronym for Davi Din?
You know what, there’s something to that,
it was really funny around that table.
My sons.
This is the best way to work,
we lay everything out neatly, follow the instructions
and go ahead, build by the book.
-They didn’t put an Allen key here.
What didn’t they put?
-No Allen key.
So Silvan, do you maybe have one at home?
The key that I don’t have in my toolbox hasn’t been born yet.
Wait here, I’m going to get
the toolbox, okay?
Alright, according to the diagram, the start
is to take part A1 and part C1.
What about part B1?
-Later, we’ll follow the instructions.
Assemble part A1 and part C1
with these big screws like you see here.
I don’t understand how they didn’t put a key like this here,
they’re usually organized and precise.
Give me a second with the diagram.
Wow, what a scam, they put a totally crooked screw here.
Here, it’s right here, B1 is across from D1.
Shantal is studying in D1, what a coincidence.
Alright, come on, with all these memories
it’s getting late.
I think they’re getting tangled up over there.
Come on, maybe you should go help them?
No, no, no, let them try.
You know how boys are,
it’ll hurt their ego.
Look, have you ever seen something like this? Look at the order,
like soldiers on Independence Day.
Adobe.
-What is it, Silvan,
have you ever used something like this?
Yeah, I’ve used it. When it’s needed, you use it.
Dad, is there also an Allen key in all this?
No, no, wait,
you don’t need to take everything out, you don’t need to,
just tell me what you need, I’ll give it to you.
Allen, Allen, what size do you need?
Here, this looks like the right size.
-This? Here you go.
Thanks.
-You’re welcome.
Just like the crooked screw that’s here in the box, what a coincidence.
Same thing.
Great, so now it’ll be easier to build,
it’ll be faster.
Alright, come on, guys, let’s start.
Okay, we need to connect part A1 with part C1.
I think we’re getting tangled up.
Should we call Alon?
Oh my, if you’re so upset,
why did you agree to change the table?
I don’t know, Dad wanted it and...
It’s one of those little compromises
you make for your partner.
Of course.
-Of course it’s obvious.
Who understands like Orna.
Excuse me? What do you mean?
Nothing, I’m not in the Holocaust, what do I know about it?
Okay, never mind, never mind.
A new table, new stories,
as they say in Arabic, tabula rasa.
No, that’s in Latin.
-What?
Because I saw it on the Hollywood channel.
Hold this here! Don’t move,
so the holes fit into the holes.
What do you mean "the holes fit into the holes"?
So the bottle goes into the bottle.
-Oh, now I get it.
Now a leg needs to come here,
that’s how it is according to the diagram.
I think it should be the other way around.
-Moshe, don’t move.
No, he's right, it's upside down but upside down mirror.
Moshe, no.
-Shai, they're right, fine, turn it around.
Why turn it?
-It makes sense.
What makes sense? That's nonsense.
Turn it around.
-Turn it.
The male "enter in this male...
Did you hear? Did you hear what I heard?
I don’t know about you, but I heard
a tree breaking, that’s what I heard.
No, no, it didn’t break, I saw it on TV,
it’s the differences between cold and heat,
the tree is stretching.
Moshe, why does a tree need to stretch?
Because it’s been packed away for a long time.
Laugh, laugh, these things happen.
We’re laughing, you can’t see it on us
but we’re crying inside.
That’s it, time’s up.
Alin.
Maybe I’ll go instead of Alin?
I’ll take Shai aside, I’ll check what’s going on,
I’m not such a threat to their dominance.
Great idea.
No.
Whose is this?
What is this... it belongs to...
Well, I think we made a big mistake.
I think we need to take everything apart, start from scratch.
No way, we need to do Kiddush soon,
What are you talking about?
Honey, come here for a sec.
You...
Didn’t you tell me you’re good at puzzles?
When the designers put this puzzle together
they didn’t consider
the destructive interference of the Hasson tribe.
No, aren’t you exaggerating a bit?
We need to make a bold decision.
How’s that?
Do you have a saw in the box?
-Of course, I have everything.
My family is always to blame, right?
What’s that noise?
Moshe, what are you doing?
-Taking initiative.
But to saw?
-Trust me.
Well, this isn’t good.
-What happened?
I don’t know, I just see them sawing parts over there.
We’re not eating on the new table today.
Well, son, that was expected.
It’s a shame they took down the old table,
we used to eat on it.
I want my old table back.
Now it looks more like a table, right?
Isn’t it a bit...
low?
What? No?
-Why? It’s fine,
Moshe sawed the chairs too.
What nonsense to saw.
-Why saw?
If it needed sawing, wouldn’t they put a saw in the kit?
How do we get out of this?
-Nonsense, nothing happened,
we tried, we failed, we’ll return it, Silvan.
How to return it? You ruined the table,
how can I return it to the store?
Why? Why? Because of the sawing?
No, because we bought it
from "Bye Bye Bye", okay?
Go find them now.
Wait, we need to think outside the box.
What box, Moshe?
Do you have contact glue in the box, Silvan?
This is the table we bought.
Or is it a really, really big tray?
Right now it’s...
Thin.
Rachel, there’s no table and no plaster.
They didn’t follow the instructions.
I hear you.
I
think
that I
Okay, I want you to go now
and bring the old table.
Why would they take it?
-What? Take it?
Just bring the table now, that’s it.
-Now.
We were so close to it.
-In the end, the instructions.
I’m going to Mom.
-No, no, now I’m going to Mom.
What?
Alin, I’m sorry, excuse me,
I wanted to call you.
You’re right, I should’ve paid the assembler
to put the table together.
Sali, I...
I’m sorry to disappoint you, but...
We can’t give up
the old table, it’s...
It’s part of us, it’s...
I don’t know, I feel like
they’re amputating a limb.
I feel exactly the same way.
I just wanted to be strong for you.
For me?
But you said it was old.
-No.
You sat with Meirav on the computer
and you were looking at furniture, remember?
Yeah.
-And you asked me if we need a new table,
so I thought that’s what you wanted, that’s all.
I thought you weren’t happy.
-No, come on, who needs a new table?
I want our old table.
Turn left.
-It’s not at the conference.
So try with your left foot first.
Not yours, Moshe, the table’s, dummy.
Slow down, slow down, the mezuzah.
Be careful, be careful, be careful, be careful.
-Go, go, go, go, you’ve got more.
Come to me.
-Good, put it here in place.
Pull it towards you, pull it towards you.
-Lower it, put it where it was.
What’s this?
-What happened?
Not so good.
What is this, who managed to burn it?
I noticed it’s a bit lighter.
-Not true.
What do we do?
-Okay, let’s get a tablecloth,
put it on, no one will notice.
-What tablecloth? And what about the hole?
No, we need to think outside the box.
Let’s put the two boards of the new table
and put a tablecloth on that.
-Brilliant idea.
Great, and no need for courses
and grinding puzzles about the grinder’s daughter.
Come on, quick, let’s work, before Mom comes, let’s go.
Come on, bring the saw.
Is everything okay?
-Yeah.
Say, do you want to switch beds maybe?
Are you kidding me?
-Of course.
Wait, wait.
What’s your story?
Do you always interrupt in the middle of a conversation?
Everything’s ready, the table is set, the blessing, let’s go.
Why do they always send me?
Is this the old table?
-Yeah, plus minus.
Where's the new guy?
-There's some folks downstairs making a bonfire.
That's nice, I'm happy.
What's that burnt smell?
Maybe something's burning in the kitchen?
No, it's from the bonfire.
Mom.
-Dad, come on, it's time for Kiddush.
Here you go.
Mom, come on, Dad started Kiddush.
Creator of food, everything's fine, there's no smell here.
Cheers.
Come on, you coming?
-Alright, since I'm here, I'll grab the fish.
No, I'll get the fish, you go.
No, no, just go inside.
"Sanctuary of the Sabbath"
Amen.
What food, there's that smell again.
Hear, O Israel.
What, babe, maybe you should take that course after all?
I have a technical sense
and I know how to think outside the box.
It's not my fault your family's box
is too big.
Okay, fine.
But I want to go to Eilat.
-But I don't need that course.
Alright, fine, then I'll tell the riddle from earlier.
The evil king fell in love with the beautiful miller's daughter
and wanted to marry her.
Okay, he built her a time machine, sent her to the future.
She'll sue that king
for sexual harassment, that's it.
Sexual harassment.
Shai, that's a big problem.
Excuse me, are you hinting at something?
-No, I'm not hinting at anything,
I'm saying: Shai, that's a big problem.
Shai... Shai, so it's a big problem for me, Shai-
Okay, enough with the embarrassment.
-With what?
Leave it! The embarrassment.
-The embarrassment.
Give me a second with the sketch.
Cold and heat of the wood,
the wood needs to stretch.
The wood stretches.
-The wood stretches.
Cold and heat of the wood,
the wood is stretching.
Stretching.
-Stretching.
The differences in cold and heat.
We just wanted to make you a joke.
A joke, in the style.
Not so much in the style.
What a mistake.
I noticed it wasn't that easy.
Did you feel it was a bit more...
I noticed it was a bit lighter.
You said it on purpose.