Unbelievable.
You remembered to take the PlayStation.
But you forgot to turn off the water heater.
You definitely told me to turn off the water heater.
-What water? What are you talking about?
I didn’t shower. Why would I say something like that?
How should I know? You said it, I did it.
And you didn’t smell the cake burning?
-No, I thought that was how it was supposed to smell.
Maybe at your mom's, that’s how the cake smells.
Sit down...
Great, now I don’t have a cake either.
I didn’t even wash my hair. Are you happy?
Your hair looks just fine.
-Maybe at your mom's.
Hair looks just fine like this.
-Sit down...
Do me a favor, leave me alone, don’t talk to me.
-No problem.
Look at me, look at me and...
Butterfly on the left.
What is this? What kind of thing is this?
I don’t understand how this is happening to me.
Me? I really don’t get it.
Butterfly, butterfly.
Mom, mom, what’s wrong? Are you okay? Drink some water.
Girls, run to the cousins
on the balcony to play. Come on, come on.
I won’t let anyone talk to me like that at home.
Of course, of course.
-I’m not okay with it.
This is ridiculous.
If I’m living in a movie, then it’s a horror film.
I’m telling you.
-But I don’t understand. How did this happen?
Where do I start?
-From the beginning.
Okay, so the beginning is like this,
It was a Wednesday,
the day the butcher's delivery guy comes,
and I had nothing left at home, no chicken breast
no ground meat, no liver,
I wanted to make a stew so I ordered hearts too.
And for that, you need to call him
a week in advance and pray that his cross-eyed son
doesn’t come because you don’t understand a word
of what he’s saying.
-Mom, mom,
Leave it, leave it, mom.
-Yeah, yeah-
So, anyway, the cute delivery guy arrives,
the tall one, the limping one...
Ah, Nissim, cutie...
-Yeah, the cutie.
So, anyway, that day they hung on our door,
you know, like, on the handle,
a Toto ad and a form to fill out.
Hey, Nissim.
-Hey, what’s up?
Good. How are you?
-Just hanging in there.
It was hanging on your door.
-What, is it Lotto?
It’s Toto. The prize is big this week.
-Come on, really, what nonsense.
Sali, what? A few million can’t hurt.
Fine.
-Give me, give me, give me, Nissim.
I’ll take it. Thanks.
-Bye, have a good day.
Come, take a look.
And then the cute Moshe arrives.
I always place an order for them
because you know how much
half a kilo of ground meat costs at their butcher.
Hello, Rachel.
-Hi, Moshe.
This is for them. Just saw them and thought of you.
Here you go.
-How nice.
You’re such a gentleman. I always tell Orna
she doesn’t know how lucky she is.
-The luck is all mine.
You came just in time. The bourekas are warm in the oven.
Come, come, come eat something small, come.
Hey, Silvan-
Move along, move along.
-Yeah.
The smell of the bourekas is killing me.
Do you want radish salad? I made it just for you.
I love radishes.
-Tell me, Moshe, what do you know
about this fruit, feijoa? The greengrocer tried
to convince me over the phone to buy some.
Is it the one you eat from the outside or the one with the spoon?
Good morning.
-Good morning.
What’s this, a break fast?
Moshe popped by to grab his meat.
-And his fridge contents.
As if I don’t know he’s here for me.
What’s up with her?
-Look, on Wednesdays she’s used to
getting the first pick. She. The girl?
-Oh!
What are you doing?
-Eat, eat nicely.
Sorry, I didn’t know you were here.
You’re usually in the armchair.
I have a master’s in mirbology
!a PhD in silvabology.
Why don’t you ask me
if I want you to sit on me?
Maybe I don’t want to? I just
wanted five minutes to rest my head here,
to relax. Not to sleep, to relax. Again.
I know I need to make them
think about something else.
Otherwise they just sit, get annoyed, and sulk.
Meirav, can I get you to help me fill out a lotto?
Toto.
-What’s Toto?
They put this form on my door,
and I thought it was a sign from above.
Marked for you and all the tenants? Cool.
What do you both even know about soccer, huh?
Meirav, it’s the big prize this week.
I have a good feeling.
Like you had a good feeling about every
guy I dated that he was the one?
No, come on, Meirav,
what we mean to say is that...
you, you, you are special,
you’re a taste in acquisition, like
like a feijoa.
Feijoa?
-Exactly.
Exactly, feijoa. What’s a feijoa?
Is it that, the star shape?
Or is it the... like a banana but...
straight?
Meirav, are you coming to help me fill out?
-Who even understands soccer?
I do.
-Okay.
Beitar Jerusalem, Maccabi Tel Aviv?
-One.
One.
-Yeah.
Beitar Jerusalem, Maccabi Tel Aviv?
-One.
One.
Yeah.
-Blackpool against West Ham?
What, aren’t these just games from Israel?
-Okay, I’ll put down two.
Two is great, two is very good.
-Show me that.
Alright.
-Mönchengladbach...
Gladbach.
Mönchengladbach against Kaiserslautern?
-Come on, whatever.
Now I’m doing it blind, whatever happens.
Blind, so fill out the lotto.
-Come on, enough.
One, X, two, two,
X.
-Why?
Feeling.
X.
-Write down Beşiktaş.
-What? One.
X.
-Okay, enough, that’s it. Done.
I have a good feeling.
-So let’s send it.
It was so delicious, Rachel. Oh, did you fill out a Toto form?
This week’s the big prize.
-Yeah. Suddenly I felt like it.
She has a feeling.
-It’s so nice that you still have feelings, Rachel.
Moshe, how are you?
-Good.
Do you want me to put this
in the booth? I’m going down anyway.
Oh, yeah, yeah. That’s a good idea.
Here, I’ll give you money—
No, forget it, forget it.
-No, no, it’s fine, it’s fine.
I’ve got some change here
that wants to get rid of me. Take it.
Okay. So thanks for everything, Rachel.
-The meat goes straight to the fridge. Run, run.
Okay, bye.
-You go.
Bye, Silvan.
-Move it, move it.
Love you more.
-Bye.
Ben! Ben!
-Meirav, do you want something to eat?
What does it even mean that I'm like pajamas?
That no one knows how to handle you.
Now they're claiming it's them.
-That's not fair.
Meirav, come on, fine. Just tell me what happened.
If it's justified, I'll help you get offended.
-Everyone knows Wednesday
is my lucky day.
Good evening.
-Finally, you got up.
Isn't it time to do something with your life?
I'm only here for the meat.
Really, Moshe, everyone knows you're here because of me.
It's like it's obvious Moshe has a thing for me. It's transparent.
Maybe you should stop talking nonsense and go,
find something to do with your life.
So I decided to take a nap in the living room.
What, are you crazy?
You're really nuts, sitting on me.
Sorry, I didn't see you were here.
Tell me, isn't it enough that you live
in my house, you also want to live on me?
I'm sorry, I... look, nothing happened.
What... I'll go rest somewhere else.
-Rest somewhere...
Rest? You, rest? From what? From what to rest?
From what? Resting from work? From your husband? From your kids?
Resting. From what? From making my life hell, that's what.
Well, I have a feeling you're a bit cranky today.
-Oh, really?
So I'll go somewhere else. What's this, a lotto form?
What a coincidence, exactly today, on my lucky day.
Bad luck.
You're not filling out that garbage.
-Why not?
Because you don't understand anything about soccer, that's why not.
I have basic concepts down.
She understands soccer like she understands men.
She understands men
like I understand nuclear physics.
And I understand global economics.
-You guys are lucky it's Wednesday.
So I'm calm. Tell me! What
do you want, I'll fill out the form.
Come on, Bnei Yehuda, Bnei Sakhnin.
-Write it down.
One.
-Why?
Because that's how I feel.
Give her a break, please, give her a break. Yeah.
-Beitar Jerusalem, Maccabi Tel Aviv?
One. Blackpool against West Ham?
-Write down two.
Two. Mönchengladbach against Kaiserslautern?
Okay, now you're making things up.
-No, look.
No, it's real, it's from the Bundesliga.
So put an X.
-X.
That's it, from now on I'm filling out for life and death.
X, one, one, two, X,
One, X.
-Who fills out a lotto like this?
Someone who has no life, that's who.
-Okay, I'm done with you guys.
We need to send this.
No, why are you looking at me
like I'm a piggy bank?
Forget it.
-I don't need you.
Moshe! Moshe!
Now they have the nerve to say they're partners.
Wait, is that why soccer is on TV?
-Of course,
and friends, not a word to Orna about the story
and that Moshe is a pain in my ass.
Sure, sure.
-So let me tell you what happened.
I was lying there in the living room, I was resting.
Resting, not sleeping, resting.
Rachel! Someone's at the door, interrupting my rest.
Can't you open it yourself?
-I can, but I don't want to.
Yeah, I swear.
Hey, Nissim, hey. What's up?
What's up?
-I'm good. How about you? How's your leg?
It's heavy. They put the Toto on the door.
What, is this the form? Rachel, bring me
the form. I haven't filled one out in ages.
What, can't you take it yourself?
-I can, but I don't want to.
Yeah, I swear
No, no, let me, let me.
Thanks, thanks, Nissim.
-Bye, have a good day.
Rachel, the door! It's turning into a bus station here.
They're interrupting my rest.
Hey, Rachel.
-Hi, Moshe.
Hey, Silvan. It's me, Moshe.
-What do you say? Is that you, Moshe?
Wow, how nice, how did you know?
I knew because I'm Moshe.
I brought you flowers.
-How lovely.
Wait, wait. Where did these flowers come from?
-I found them downstairs,
someone threw them out, they're brand new.
They just need a little water.
Rachel, throw those flowers away,
you don't know who touched them first.
It doesn't matter, Moshe. It's the thought that counts.
What thought?
-It doesn't matter, Moshe.
What?
Want to eat?
-Are there radishes?
Yes, come.
-Rachel, the form. Rachel, the form!
Just a second.
It's the week of the big prize.
I thought I'd buy a little boat,
we'll sail on the Kinneret.
We'll catch fish, I really love nature.
What, you can see.
Yeah
Come on
No, but okay, I get that you’re a bit overwhelmed.
And then, then the problems started,
serious problems.
Oh!
Bubala, bubala, what happened to you?
What, you almost sat down...
-By mistake! What's wrong with you?
No, bubala, my little bird.
Dad just wanted to rest a bit, that's all.
I can't, Dad.
-I, I
Moshe keeps trying to hit on me.
-Moshe?
Moshe is nothing. You should see
how Shai looks at me all the time.
Stop the story.
Meirav said I'm trying to hit on her?
And that's just the sane part.
Are you sure?
-Of course I'm sure. It's stronger than them.
They can't control themselves.
They're waiting for me by the bathtub,
by the bathroom...
-Of course, of course, of course.
Rachel!
-Here, here’s your Toto.
It's not Toto, it's Lotto.
-Toto.
Unlike Lotto, Toto has an element of understanding.
Of course
we'll see
Yeah, of course we’ll see. I'll explain to you.
Bnei Yehuda, Sakhnin, one. Why?
-Why?
Because they replaced the whole team. Got it?
Beitar Jerusalem, Maccabi Tel Aviv, one. Why?
-Why?
Because the goalie pulled his groin.
Blackpool, West Ham, that's two.
One.
-I'm writing two. Got it?
There are Bundesliga games here.
Kaiserslautern is winning, of course.
Ah!
There are Serie A games here too.
Please, X, one, one, two,
X and last...
two
You think so? They’ll lose at home?
Come on, just one. That’s it.
All that's left to do
is send the form.
And collect the money. Miravi...
-I can’t.
The guy at the booth keeps
hitting on me and I’m not into it.
He’s 82.
-He can’t help it,
it’s beyond him.
-What’s up, guys? What’s going on?
I’ll explain it very simply.
You take this form, go straight to the booth,
yeah
got it.
Rena
yeah
that’s it
go on
yeah
dude
oh boy
Dor to the booth. Please.
Rachel, give him some money.
-No, leave it, Silvan.
-Why? Can’t you give it to him yourself?
I can, but I don’t want to because I’m lazy.
Here, take it.
Listen up, Moshe. The meat goes straight to the fridge.
But first to the booth. Okay? Dor.
And send him my regards.
But they’re claiming it’s theirs now,
those cheeky ones.
But I don’t get why there were screams.
-Money always leads to shouting.
It started with money, then it got messy.
Good morning, what’s that noise from the TV?
What morning? It’s already noon.
Maybe put something on?
I don’t remember the last time
I saw you dressed.
Silvan, chill out.
What’s Dad watching, soccer?
-Why? Do you have a problem with that?
What, is this soccer?
-Yeah.
Yeah, it’s soccer, what a revelation,
how did you figure that out? So clever.
We have results now! No interruptions.
Here are the glasses.
-What excitement.
On the side of the screen, you can see
the results of the 11 games played so far.
Now’s the time to compare the forms.
One, two...
Wow, everything’s right. I told you
Wednesday is my lucky day.
All 11 are correct. Do you win something with 11 guesses?
No, no, only with 12. So there’s a chance.
Shh! Be quiet for a bit!
What game is this now?
Mönchengladbach vs. Kaiserslautern.
I wrote two. I remember writing two.
I wrote two.
This is a Bundesliga game! I clearly remember
I’m the only one who understands this.
How much, how much?
-Write it down! Write it down!
Zero-zero, injury time.
So we just need Kaiserslautern to score
and then we can decide what to do with my prize.
Just a second! You walking around all day
in that robe doesn’t mean
you deserve a prize. And excuse me,
but most of my guesses.
This is my house and this is my form!
And you, before you play soccer and tennis,
go play with some husband.
Do me a favor, Sali.
God, let us win the Toto,
quietly, someone take her away.
-What?
Rachel, come on! Don’t you get it yet?
We’re stuck with her in this house forever!
Forever!
Shabbat Shalom.
-And this is where you came in.
This is very serious.
-This isn’t right.
But why did it blow up now? Did you win something?
Listen.
Where can we hear the results?
-On the radio, you can hear it on the radio.
I had a transistor here.
What, babe, can't we watch it on TV?
-No. We can't. What is this?
It's pay channels. What about you?
-What, how much does it cost?
I have relatives. Okay?
Fine. I'm going to turn on the TV.
That's how it is, Dad. I would argue with him,
he would never order the channel.
What’s that? Is Dad watching soccer?
I went to turn on the TV,
he did exactly what I said.
What's keeping me from this game?
-Listen up!
On the side of the screen, you can see
the results of the 11 games played so far.
It's time to compare the tickets.
-Two, two, X, X,
One, one, one, X... We won!
-Yeah?
No, no, we didn't win.
We have 11 correct guesses.
We have a chance. Because with 12 correct guesses
we might win something.
I can't handle this suspense.
What game are we even watching?
Mönchengladbach vs. Kaiserslautern.
-I remember you filled in two.
-What "I"?
I filled out the form.
You barely made a guess.
Calm down, calm down. Speaking of which,
I filled out the form.
Okay? You stood behind and made noise, as usual.
I can't believe what I'm hearing.
As if I don't have enough living with you
and putting up with your nonsense,
now you're stealing from me too?
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
What’s that? What are we watching?
-If I tell you the names of the teams,
then "the game is over."
Goal. Kaiserslautern won!
Yes!
-That's mine. Mine!
Meirav, you need to calm down.
-I'm not calming down.
You ruined
every relationship I ever had.
Because of you, I'll never find anyone.
You're really crazy!
I'm crazy? I'll show you crazy!
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
And then you cried.
-Wow, that's not fair.
How did it escalate?
-Not good.
Very not good.
I feel like treating myself to a pay channel.
I'm really going crazy watching the game results.
What, isn't it a waste of money? Just listen on the radio.
Rachel, Rachel, what's up with you? It's not like us
to be stingy over a few bucks.
Come on, Rachel, I'm surprised at you.
Fine, go ahead, do what you want.
I'm going to turn on the TV.
Just don't cry later that we don't have money.
And then I ordered the game with the remote.
It's my first time, it's not that complicated.
You know, if you want, I can explain it to you.
What is it, soccer?
-Yeah, my little bird.
Yeah, soccer.
-Is it pay-per-view?
That's nothing for us. Payment.
-We'll be generous, just like your dad.
Here he is announcing the results. Please.
On the side of the screen, you can see
the results of the 11 games played so far.
It's time to compare the tickets.
-It's all correct.
What, did we win?
-No, but so far everything's correct.
What do you mean "we won"? I won!
Excuse me.
-That's my ticket!
You guys are so funny...
I can't believe it, goal for Kaiserslautern!
This is where World War III started.
And again, it's because of the Germans.
And then you guys came in.
We have to sort this out.
You have to forgive them.
-Yeah, I do live here after all.
Mom, you have to give them a chance.
Yeah, you're right.
Come on.
So what?
Divided by three?
Three.
-Three.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom. Shantal, you have five minutes.
Hey, what happened here? What broke?
A vase broke here.
-What's that in soccer?
Fenerbahçe betrayed Beşiktaş?
-We called it a draw.
Who filled out the form?
-Don't get into that. They, together,
The three of them filled it out together.
-Oh, listen to this.
Forget it, it's three shekels, nonsense.
I'll cover it.
Put the meat in the fridge, Dor!
As soon as I left your house,
the form fell into the heavy stuff.
I couldn't send it like that.
So I filled out another column and sent it automatically.
So basically, it's Moshe's form.
-Yeah.
Yeah, but...
-So it's not...
But it was my lucky day.
-If we win, it divides by four.
I can feel it.
-For sure.
Beşiktaş is losing. All the games ended this week.
The prize won't be given out,
not even to those with 13 correct guesses.
Honey...
-I'm not talking to you.
I'm sorry I burned your cake.
-And...
And that you didn't have water to rinse.
I promise that after I put the girls to bed,
foot massage.
I love you too.
Honey.
-I thought you weren't talking to me.
Okay, come on, I'm sorry
I got mad at you. It wasn't your fault.
It's fine, I've forgiven you long ago.
-I'm sorry too
for saying your mom doesn't rinse.
-Okay.
I promise that after I put the girls to bed,
yeah?
-I'll let you give me a foot massage.
I love you too.
Crazy...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Money always leads to shouting.
It's unbelievable, it's just unbelievable,
to remember to take the sub...
It's just unbelievable, the sub' PlayStation...
What, the PlayStation.
It's just unbelievable,
to remember to take the PlayStation.
Idiot.
Again?
-No!
What, are you crazy?
It's okay, it's okay.
-Moshe keeps trying to hit on me.
My darling, my darling, you're just...
What do you want?
Adva!