Why do you think they can't manage without me?
-I don't think so, honey. I'm sure.
I’m gone for one day,
and everything falls apart.
Calm down, not everything falls apart that quickly.
Honey, some people are irreplaceable. Period.
Cemeteries are full of people
who thought they were irreplaceable.
It's obvious you're your mother's son.
It's amazing. Every conversation with you
ends up at a cemetery.
Sit down, sit down, can you take
the turns a bit slower?
I don't have gyro, and with every turn I feel
the sauce reaching the edge of the pot,
and in a second I'm getting a shower of cumin.
-It's not cumin.
So what's in the meatballs with cumin?
-Turmeric.
But...
-Okay, honey, I know what I'm doing.
Watch out, bump.
Look at me, look at me and...
Okay, I'm going to set the table.
-No, no. No. Uh...
Help me get up. I want
to set the table with you.
No, no. I can manage on my own. Come on.
The doctor told you not to step
on your foot for a week, so what...
No need to insist.
-What, but I'm not going to help you set the table?
Helping you... no need to make a drama out of it.
Table.
-What drama?
I'm setting the table with you,
I'm clearing the table with you
together for so many weeks.
-Okay, so one time not,
so one time I'll do it alone.
Next week you'll be healthy
and then we can do it together again, like always.
I'm sure he won't get mad.
Who?
-The table.
Okay, but I don't agree to let you set
this table alone, with your back.
Wait for the kids' backs.
-Okay.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
-Mom, what's up? How are you?
We need to help Dad set the table.
-Sure, sure, Shai...
I'm going to the kitchen.
-Sure, I'll help with the table.
Thanks, Shai, thanks.
-How's your foot feeling?
It's fine. Nonsense, it'll pass eventually.
-Yeah? Are you eating a lot of cheese?
What cheese?
-No, because at this age
all the calcium starts to slip away.
What age are you talking about
when you say "at this age"?
Thanks.
-I... I mean around the age of...
Exactly the age of... much younger too.
That's nonsense, right? A hernia in the foot.
It has nothing to do with calcium loss.
Shai said there's a friend
who knows about these things.
Yeah, he knows about feet.
-What, is he an orthopedist?
No, no, he's kind of...
-A rheumatologist?
What did this rheumatologist say? Is he coming?
Okay, rheumatologist.
The rheumatologist said he’d drop by later
to see what's wrong with you.
It's really nice to have someone at home who can drop by.
-Great, Sali.
Funny. Thanks, Shai, thanks.
I really don't trust that girl who took care of me.
Okay. Come on, I'll show you how to set the table.
Silvan, I've already set
a few tables in my life.
Not this one, not this one. This one has a specific order
that's very, very special and needs to be done
exactly in order. If not, it won't open.
You know what? It could even break.
Okay?
-What's the order?
Please. Put your hand there, right in front of you.
Yeah, navigate
come
and touch this
Okay, take the little piece, pull it to the left,
now lift it up and to the right.
Okay? Now pull, pull the... this.
It's not coming out.
-Please.
No, Sali, he's on my side.
You need to go right
then up, then left, and it’ll come out.
And Shai
Kai.
Go to the right now. Same thing.
Same clip, go up and turn right.
Pull them and...
For the first time,
I think it looks really nice.
Hello sis, Shabbat Shalom.
-What's up, sis?
About what?
-About his tasks.
Are you talking about the lettuce salad?
-Yeah, that’s what they gave you to make, right?
You caught me just as I was going to wash my hands.
I've been with this lettuce dryer for two hours,
I can't get it open,
and I’m stuck with lettuce inside.
We asked you to make a lettuce salad,
and you got stuck with that too?
I didn't get stuck with the lettuce,
I got stuck with the dryer.
Why complicate everything?
Have you seen Shai?
-Great.
What happened, Rachel?
No, it’s nothing, just my leg. Come on.
Sorry, excuse me, sorry.
I'm just worried they won't manage
to get everything done in the kitchen on time.
-No, don’t worry, don’t worry at all.
Someone's taking care of it. Trust me.
They’re already on Wednesday, they’re already busy
and washing whoever is whatever. You get it?
Everything will be ready on time and in place.
Right?
-True. Rachel, sit back and enjoy.
All day she’s cooking, she’s cleaning,
she’s doing this...
So what’s the surprise she fell from her leg?
-Funny.
Well, I can't just sit here,
I want to see what's happening in the kitchen.
Shai, take me to the kitchen, please.
I’ll just sit. I’ll just sit.
I promise.
I’ll help you.
-You promise not to touch anything?
No, I won’t touch, won’t touch.
Careful, careful.
Is there a chance you could switch with me?
-No, sweetie. I’ve already finished my tasks.
-What did you make?
The green beans and the meatballs.
-Let me taste.
Can I too?
-What are you doing here?
Shai, why are you bringing her here?
-She wanted to see how it’s going,
she promised not to do anything.
-She can’t not do anything,
I know her.
-Come on, sit, sweetie. Relax. Here,
I’m just sitting and watching. That’s all.
Mom, I’m not doing well with this lettuce salad.
Yeah, she has lettuce with claustrophobia.
-It’s allowed, there’s the little thing,
move it to the right.
-Oh.
You see?
-Okay, I’ll take the lettuce.
No, no, no. No way.
-What’s wrong? I’ll make a lettuce salad sitting down.
No. Shai, get her out of here now.
-Rachel, you promised not to do anything. Come on...
Okay, enough, but look at the lettuce.
-It’ll be fine.
Wash it.
-Get her out!
And put oil, lemon, and salt, so it has some flavor.
Now listen to me carefully:
You’re immediately making the lettuce salad.
-Okay.
I wanted to check the clock, see
how long it’ll take until they bring you back,
I didn’t get to check the clock...
-Come on, Rachel, sit here,
and don’t worry. Okay?
Everything, everything will be fine in the kitchen.
Okay? Did you see what a mess there was with the lettuce?
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom, Shabbat Shalom, my sweethearts.
So what, Mom, a week off?
Forget it, I don’t want a break, I want to be healthy.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Come on, it’s just a leg.
You won’t believe what Alin did.
I made mdurasa in the special pot you bought me.
-Mdurasa?
Yeah, I’m going to put it in the kitchen.
-How did it turn out?
Mdurasa is the red stuff, right?
As much as it looks like a cast, behind it
are many weeks of kitchen wisdom.
You won’t believe how delicious it turned out.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Mom, you won’t believe what I made,
mdurasa in the special pot you bought me.
I’m putting it in the kitchen.
-You won’t believe how tasty it turned out.
Shai, take me to the kitchen.
I need to see how Alin and Orna
are mdurasa-ing each other.
Slow, slow, slow.
Here, Mom.
This is funny.
-What a scene. Okay, come on, let’s go.
Can we officially declare
International Mdurasa Day?
-Yes.
Totally.
-We achieved our goal,
Mdurasa for every worker.
-Ugh, it still doesn’t taste good to me.
What?
-The poor lettuce?
What’s the problem?
Add a bit of vinegar, a bit of olive oil.
It tastes like grass with fertilizer.
-Is everything okay here?
Honey, why did you send her back?
-She insisted because of the mdurasas.
What, did you both happen to make mdurasa?
Yeah. In the pot you bought me.
-Yeah, in the pot you bought me.
Her too.
-Her too.
Come on, it’s fine, Mom. Nothing happened.
How nice. Can I taste?
-No. Shai!
I bet you that Orna’s mdurasa
beats the Russian version hands down.
It’s easy to check. Want us to ask
everyone whose mdurasa is the tastiest?
I love competitions like this.
Orna’s is more attractive, that’s clear.
I’m saying this loud and clear.
Yeah? Then I hereby declare
the “Mdurasa Showdown.”
You’re going to have a problem. You know
what the problem is? The pots are identical.
Maybe you should mark them because you won’t know
which mdurasa belongs to which pot?
No, no, no. I don’t need to mark anything.
I can spot our mdurasa from 100 meters away.
What, it’s not obvious that Orna cooks better?
-Not at all.
Look at her! Look at her.
It’s because I switch ingredients
faster. That’s all.
What ingredients is he talking about, Dad?
-Come on, the essential nutrients, how do you say that?
Metabolism, metabolism.
Yeah, metabolism.
So mine is faster.
Rachel, come on, we’re going back.
-When is the foot doctor coming?
Doctor? Does a doctor need to come?
He’s a foot specialist, because...
Doctor! Move out of the way.
Come on, have you tasted the mdurasa?
-Which one did I taste?
They wouldn’t let me near the pots. They formed a human shield.
Better this way. It’ll keep the tension until the mdurasa finale.
What finale?
They’re having a competition for which mdurasa is better.
Tell me, what do you think about Mom’s voice
counting as three votes?
No problem, Orna is her daughter.
-Good luck to you all. Break a leg.
It’s just a crack!
Wait, if you made mdurasa
and you made mdurasa too,
So, Mom says no one made rice?
We don’t need rice, there’s plenty of food.
-What a mess.
Of course it’s a mess. You think?
No Friday without rice.
I know your mom too, she’ll sneak and buy some.
Alright, let’s get the rice going.
Alin, rice isn’t a quick fix.
Alin, you make rice with love.
Just like you make mashed potatoes.
Mashed potatoes? Mom will kill you.
-For sure.
Okay, listen up.
First, you fry the onion.
What’s frying onions got to do with rice?
Not every dish starts with frying.
You can boil water, add some rice,
a bit of salt, fresh.
Is that a recipe from the book "Everything's Bland and Olive Oil"?
No, it’s from "Fry, Spice, and Get Grossed Out."
Heartburn on the house.
No way I’m washing rice here
like in a hospital.
Or like at Shai’s mom’s place.
So what? When’s your doctor friend coming?
He’s at a soccer game.
He said he’d come when the game’s over,
so don’t expect a doctor in a white coat.
He’s actually a paramedic.
But here’s the thing, he’s a massage therapist for soccer teams.
From the national league, from League A,
so he’s a real foot expert.
Who got cold feet and isn’t coming.
I don’t get it. What is he? A paramedic?
A doctor? A medic?
Is he a nurse?
-What? No way, he’s a medic,
a senior medic. That’s half the studies.
Got it. It’s medical studies on one leg, basically.
Just so you know, those masseurs
you see on the fields are like magicians.
Yeah, except instead of a wand, they have a spray.
-Well, honestly, he’s seen a lot of feet
in his life.
-Tell me, his Achilles heel... heels?
What’s up?
-No, I just had to get out of the kitchen.
What’s going on? Alin’s taking over everything.
Thinks she’s Stalin.
That’s the lettuce.
-No, no. That’s the rice.
I’m not responsible for what happens to that rice.
Everything’s fine in the kitchen, Mom.
Shai, take me to the kitchen.
But Rachel...
-Take me there!
Oh, he’s here.
-Blessed is the healer of the sick, blessed is the healer of the sick.
Hello.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Doctor "Mabatus"?
-Oh boy.
Don’t disturb the rice.
-But it needs stirring.
You don’t stir rice.
-But then the flavors won’t spread and the bottom will burn.
My rice has never burned.
-No, no. You need to add water.
No, no, what do you mean water?
It’ll be too sticky. Maybe oil.
How much oil can you add?
It smells like a train station restroom.
Seriously.
-Okay, okay. We need to turn off the heat.
Maybe a small flame?
-No, no.
You need to leave the lid on and let it cook itself.
No, you need to cover the pot with a towel.
-If we’re covering this mess,
then with three towels, so no one sees it.
Sit down, hold me.
Yes, Doctor Mabatus?
-You have nothing to worry about.
Today I’m not drooling.
-Good, because I didn’t do any drooling today either.
Shai, help me get up.
-Where to?
To the recovery room, check my leg.
In terms you’ll understand, she wants to go to the dressing room.
It’s fine, I’m sorry,
I’m just used to an audience so...
Slowly, slowly.
Stop the clock for injury time?
-No need.
Is that a doctor? He's a quack.
An orthopedist, sure.
-Come on, let’s see what’s going on.
K'
m
sh'vrka
b'ni
Delicious.
-Seriously.
What is this? It’s just like Friday rice.
See, I was right, I told you.
-Sorry, cheeky. I made it.
Oh, sit down...
-Oh, girls.
I don’t want to get into this silly argument, yeah,
but if I wasn’t here,
you’d end up with a lump.
Honey...
-Speaking of honey.
Sali, give me the...
Here, you see, this is my calcium level,
I had tests last month.
I have to. You see, the chart doesn’t lie.
I have one: so what, is her leg offside?
I have a better one:
Tell me, do you think you can
hold out for another half?
I have one too, I have one too:
the spray lasts from Shabbat to Shabbat.
Hey, what are you all doing here?
With so much crowd and a football massage.
I feel like I’m at Bloomfield.
Red card, everyone out.
Alright, come on, move them...
Nice.
-That’s the other leg.
Oh, really? That’s related.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah—
-Sounds positive.
Y hen".
"Ravi
z and say
Aa
Yeah. Well,
it’s a matter of not stepping on the leg for a week.
A week? That’s a long time.
That’s what they told me at the clinic too.
Ben, you see? That’s exactly what the doctor said.
So he knows what he’s talking about.
-Look, what you need
is to take painkillers.
-I have: the pill is round.
A week? That’s a long time not to step on the leg.
Yeah. A week. After that, gradually,
you can get back to training.
Cheers. To your usuals.
Where’s the doctor? Has the doctor arrived yet?
He’s not a doctor, he’s not a doctor, he’s a masseur.
A masseur with height.
Alright, I’ll move.
-Nothing to say,
you delivered the news on the field.
-Tzvi, are you the masseur?
Yeah. Meirav.
I have a muscle strain
in the collarbone of my right shoulder.
Well, I specialize only in legs.
Great, because the pain radiates to my leg too.
Look, my wife is on pregnancy bed rest
and I don’t want to...
fall asleep on watch. Exactly.
-Yeah.
So what, your mom’s in a cast.
-Your mom will be just fine.
Alright, so goodbye everyone. Thanks.
The doctor jumped on his horse because he cares about his health.
What a shame about the horse.
Anyway, thanks, Shai.
-Anytime.
You wanted another opinion, right?
-Yeah, he’s not just stupid, he’s also ugly.
So, should we do a Kiddush?
-Yeah.
Girls!
Shantal!
-Hey, do kids vote in the contest?
No, no, no. My girls will definitely vote for you.
They don’t vote.
-Good job, girls.
Look at the table they set. Good for them!
For this occasion.
-Shai, take me to the bedroom.
That’s it, girls, huh? Everything’s ready...
And on time.
-And tasty.
The truth is, in the end, I noticed a team for the event.
Yeah, uh. If one day we open a restaurant,
what will we call it?
I know: Pirushki Babushka.
No.
-That won't be its name.
You can leave me alone.
-Okay.
What's up, Rachel? Why are you alone?
We're doing Kiddush now.
Can we have a few more moments?
Yeah.
What's going on?
Did you see how they made everything by themselves?
-Yeah.
It's amazing. It's amazing because you hugged them well.
And what?
-What do you mean "and what"?
And what about me? Can I
rest peacefully in my bed?
Is that it?
-You think so?
You can rest peacefully in your bed.
Give them a chance, give them a chance.
They don't see it the way you do,
and they did everything,
everything was just for you. Really.
Wait.
-Sorry.
Everything's ready. Should we do Kiddush?
-Yeah, yeah.
Can you call Grandma?
-Sure!
And you don't recognize what's yours?
-No. They got mixed up in the kitchen.
This is it. No, no, no, no. This is it. This is it.
Come on, what does it matter?
Everything's ready.
-Alright, Kiddush.
"On the sixth day
the heavens were finished..."
Manny, come on, you say Kiddush today.
Me?
-Yeah. One-time thing.
Let's start warming you up.
"On the sixth day,
the heavens and the earth and all their hosts were finished...
Sabri Maranan."
-Cheers!
"With love and will, we inherit..."
its inheritance.
-Its inheritance.
"The sanctity of Shabbat."
-Amen.
Alright, enjoy.
-Come on, let's start with the medursa.
Yeah, yeah—what, whose is it—
Well, we don't really know anymore.
-I told them this would happen,
but why, why listen to the old man?
Alright, give me a piece of each and I'll taste.
And the other one?
That's Alin's.
How?
-How?
By the paprika.
-I put in two tablespoons.
Yeah, but that's Hungarian paprika.
It's the same paprika that wasn't really good
that you put in the goulash a month and a half ago.
-I thought the goulash was tasty.
The goulash was excellent, but the paprika wasn't great.
That's definitely Orna's. Of course.
You have no salt at all.
No, I told you, my sweet,
to put salt by eye and I forgot you have a lazy eye.
Mom, taste my meatballs.
They should be cumin meatballs, right?
-Yeah, but, really,
I just didn't have cumin so I used turmeric.
Yeah, turmeric is...
Alright, be careful with the turmeric.
It makes stains, oh my.
And this is Meirav's lettuce salad.
Somehow, my salad turned out okay.
My sweet, you're really in love, huh?
Because all the salt that's missing from Orna.
It's here in abundance.
-But it's great.
Great, great.
For a first time, it's really great.
The atmosphere is really excellent.
-And!
Why are you all looking at me? Start eating.
Dad, come, I'll put it
-Just a second, one more thing.
I really appreciate you! I really value
the efforts you made tonight,
each according to their ability, of course.
If you'll allow me a moment,
this Shabbat I sat on the bench
!You all gave your best on the field,
but I have to tell you, you have
a few more good weeks to run
and practice on the lines,
from the medursa to the lettuce salad.
And I don't want to mention names
because I love you all very, very much.
Full house.
-Yeah.
Wait, so you swapped the cumin for turmeric on purpose?
You just thought they were making the same stain.
-Just so your mom would feel good?
I didn't know Alon and Orna messed up
the medursa.
-Of course.
And Meirav's lettuce salad was doomed from the start.
But the rice turned out great.
-It turned out good, huh?
Look at that, even Alin, even Orna
and I don't know how it turned out.
So basically, everyone in the right place
at the right time has a substitute.
So you better be careful.
-Bam!
I made medurska in... no.
-Medurska is...
I didn't...
What final?
They're having a competition,
a competition of what,
which medursa is better.
My voice changed.
You don't have to have rice. You can...
-boil water.
Sorry. Sorry, sorry.