Why are you driving from here?
-Why not?
Because it makes the trip longer.
It's the same thing.
-No. There are a ton of traffic lights from here.
What does it matter? We get there in the end?
-Fine. Look, look, check it out,
On the right. A girl with a bomb is passing you.
-Do you want to drive?
No.
-Then let me drive in peace.
It can't be that every time we
go to my parents' place, you freak out.
I'm not freaking out, and it has nothing to do with your parents.
-No, what?
No, it’s not related. It’s your parents, and everything’s fine with them.
I'm just annoyed about the jeans.
-What's wrong with these?
Not these. The ones that didn't fit me at home.
-Oh, it's allowed,
You're as beautiful as the night I met you.
-In the army? When I was 10 kg heavier?
15. But 15 charming ones.
-Idiot.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Hi. Where have you been?
I was already worried. Hey.
-What's up, Riki?
Don't ask who died, and no one touch the phone.
Who died?
-Uncle Shmuel.
Would you believe it?
-Well, it was expected, right?
He passed away last night.
-Oh, poor thing.
That's how it is, sit down, you never
know when you'll die.
You look a bit pale, you know?
-No.
And the phone?
-From Miami.
Today they’re opening the will and will call to update me,
so no one touch the phone.
Tell the girls too.
-Okay.
Excuse me, I'm going to flip
the schnitzels so they don't burn.
Do you need help, Riki?
-No, sweetie.
I'm already used to doing everything alone.
Okay, I just don’t understand. Why does she
need to say things like that to me?
She can't help it, it's in her genes.
-Uncle Shmuel, huh?
She waited for this for weeks.
-Weeks is just the time we've known each other.
It started even before.
-What? You think there's a chance for something in the inheritance?
I don’t know. She took care of him really well all those years,
always insisted he stay here when he visited
even though he could rent out the whole
Hilton. She might get something.
Not for her. For the son. Does the son have a chance?
-No, no, I don’t think so.
We never got along.
-Really?
You and I met after
I started keeping my distance from him.
He always looked at me
like I wanted to hit him.
Hey, Uncle Shmuel.
-Hey, Uncle Shmuel.
It's not you, it's not you.
He just doesn't like kids.
At first, Mom explained to me
that it’s because he doesn’t like kids,
but later I realized it was something about me. So there’s no chance for cents,
not for rubles and not for zlotys.
-Too bad.
I'm going to steal some schnitzels.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Hey.
-Hey, man, what's up? How's it going, babe?
What's happening?
-All good.
Is there some new drama in the Rosen family
I need to know about?
Uncle Shmuel...
-Is he coming?
No, on the contrary. He’s dead.
No way. You're kidding me?
No, no.
-I'm dying.
Wow, what a story. You don’t remember
what he did to me at our wedding.
No, I wasn’t there, I was
postpartum but I heard the story.
Well, what you didn’t hear is that... okay, listen.
Remember I had that dress,
נכון הייתה לי את השמלה הזאת,
The amazing one with the...
-Yeah, yeah.
I saw her in the photo album.
-No, but you can't see it in the pictures either...
No, I also saw the video tape.
-No, no, you can't see it in the video either...
I also saw the slideshow you posted
on Facebook. It was just hilarious.
What was hilarious?
Hilarious.
-Right? It turned out stunning!
No, but you can't see
how Uncle Shmuel was trying to peek at my cleavage the whole wedding.
Now, from the moment you caught him, that little dwarf,
he was so stressed he just spilled a glass of wine on me.
Do you know how hot I got? I yelled at him,
I dried him out there in front of everyone.
I thought he was going to die right there.
In short, in my modesty! I'm definitely not in the clear.
-Hold on a second.
Hey.
-Hey, Michal. Where's Tamari? I was already worried.
Itamar is looking for parking, he's on his way up,
and... Riki, may you know no more sorrow.
Oh, yeah. Sure.
-Riki
Gershon, they left the flowers
at your place again. I really can't believe it.
I told them clearly not to send
flowers while I'm napping in the afternoon.
But go talk to the wall.
-Who sent them?
Me. If I don't send myself flowers, who will send me?
These are a bit too colorful.
I wanted something a bit sadder.
Sit down, my sweet,
could you take this vase
and fill it with water, if it's not too much trouble?
-No, no. It's no trouble at all.
I'll take these to the kitchen.
Hey, Gershon, what's up? What,
is this for me? You didn't have to, Gershon.
Oh, lilies. Why, who died?
-Uncle Shmuel.
Enough. How much did she get?
-We don't know yet. Waiting for Miami.
Enough. What a drama.
-No, I'm dying.
Wow!
Oh! I got scared. Pinchas, Pinchas, I'm so...
I'm sorry, I didn't know you were there.
Pinchas, I'm so sorry.
-It's okay. Sit down, nothing happened.
Wow, I'm dying. Pinchas, put something on.
No, I'm dying.
-Did you hear about Uncle Shmuel?
He drained the juice until he left.
We heard.
-All good.
Get dressed, we're going out. Okay?
Sorry, in the...
-Sorry, in the...
Who yelled?
-No, it's okay, it's okay.
Shabbat Shalom, Mom.
Wait, are you guys okay?
-Physically yes, mentally a bit less.
Riki, I'm so sorry. I went into the shower,
I didn't know Pinchas was in there.
-No, I'm dying.
You don't die that quickly.
I was also scared when I saw Pinchas
for the first time in the shower.
A week later, I married him.
Yeah, just that, from the shock, my vase fell.
Did it break?
-Yeah. I'm so sorry, Riki.
There's a lot of glass there but I'll cry
about it, I just need to wait for...
Pinchas to get dressed.
-Nothing happened. It's just a vase.
The main thing is that everyone is healthy.
What an embarrassment, God.
-What a relief it wasn't me who broke it.
How weird that it happened
on the day Uncle Shmuel died.
I couldn't stand that Uncle Shmuel.
Why?
-You know the first time
I saw him was
when Shai and I started dating.
It was the first time I sat here.
Early in the morning, I went into the shower before everyone woke up.
My mom hears a girl from a mile away.
What we didn't know, Shai and I, was that
Uncle Shmuel was also visiting here.
Hello.
שלום.
Hi.
No, I would’ve died.
-And since then, every time we saw him,
he would wink at me. And the craziest part is
Shai didn’t believe me,
he thought I was imagining it.
-No, I would’ve died. Died.
You said he was a problematic guy.
I’m taking this course now,
Introduction to Psychology. He fits
the definition of a problematic person,
by definition.
-Can someone take these flowers from me?
Because I’m starting to feel like
a beauty queen and I’m not into it.
Tell me, what’s going on there?
-Dad got glass in his foot.
Where?
-What do you mean where? In his foot.
And where’s Shai?
-Taking care of the injured.
Ouch, ouch, ow, ow.
-Why are you yelling? I haven’t touched it yet.
Why are you yelling? He hasn’t touched it yet.
What do you see, Shai? Is it serious?
Needs stitches, right?
No, not at all. It’s just a small piece of glass.
-Oh.
Ouch, ouch, ow, ow.
-Stop yelling.
The neighbors will think we’re killing someone.
Ouch, ouch.
-That’s it. I got it out.
You got it all out? Do me a favor,
check again to make sure you got it all.
For sure.
-Definitely.
Yeah. Just a small piece of glass.
-See? You’re still alive.
I’m going to flip the schnitzels,
so they don’t burn.
Schnitzels? That’s what’s important to you?
I almost lost my leg,
and she’s only thinking about schnitzels.
-There, done. I put on a band-aid.
Thanks, Shai. By the way, have you heard about Uncle Shmuel?
Yeah. It was about time, right?
-Yeah, but still, it’s sad.
Just so you know, he was the only one
from Mom’s side that I really liked.
We had amazing conversations.
-What?
Of course, very deep conversations.
Ariel Sharon scares them.
They say he came in with bandanas
to the Knesset. He talks in a funny way.
Here, here, here, here... I can’t do impressions,
but I do animals really well.
This one is very economical. Do you see the engine?
But this one, it’s really good for long
trips. Not that I travel far,
but, you know, sometimes I want
to get to "Asaf Harofeh" hospital
or "Yarkon" cemetery...
I tell him, listen, I’m the angel of death.
How come you’re not afraid of me?
And he says, why should I be scared of the angel of death
if I’ve been married to his sister for 35 years?
Uncle Shmuel had a great sense of humor.
-What are you saying? Are you serious?
I don’t think I ever heard him
say a word besides yelling.
He didn’t like kids.
-Even when I grew up.
That was just a phrase Mom would
say to calm me down.
It was Mom who forced him to talk to us.
He wasn’t a big talker, but he knew how to listen.
How old was he, actually? Because even
when we were kids, he was old.
Even when I met him 50 years ago, he was old.
Everyone thought he was going to die
any minute. He was loaded with money,
and that’s why your mom’s whole family
was kissing up to him.
Forgive me for the expression.
It sounds better in Yiddish.
-I doubt it.
Why? Kisch zayne tokhes
-Please.
I cleaned the glasses, Riki.
-And I washed.
Really?
-No. I was keeping an eye on Shabi.
Nonsense. I’ll go over it
later anyway. You shouldn’t have.
I’m really sorry, Riki, I really am. I...
Just tell me where I can buy one
and I’ll get you a new one.
Forget it, Shabi, it’s not necessary,
and besides, there’s nowhere to buy one like that.
What? I’m sure I can get you one like that and a vase.
She got her degree in shopping, Mom.
This is the vase I got as a gift from Uncle Shmuel.
That's why I wanted to use it.
Besides, it's an antique vase.
-Ugly. You’ve been hiding it since Shavuot.
Itamar, if you don’t have
anything smart to say, it’s better to stay quiet.
Wow, Riki, I’m so sorry.
I really feel bad about this.
Forget it, sit down, it’s nothing. Just a vase.
Anyway, I wasn’t planning to take it with me to the grave.
The main thing is everyone is healthy. Everything else is nonsense.
-Riki, I really...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Hey Adam, what’s up? What’s this, alone?
Bar Refaeli is parking the antenna.
Really?
-Yeah.
No. So what’s going on? Have they called
from Miami yet? Did we get anything?
How did you hear the dwarf kicked the bucket?
-What happened to you? Mom called me right away.
Nothing. Every time something happens.
War, revolution in Egypt,
plane crash, tsunami in Japan, dog in a dress,
Mom calls right away to check if I’m okay.
-Wow.
She never calls me.
I always have to call her.
They haven’t called yet.
-So what? It’s nice here.
Not more than usual.
Tell me, do you think there’s any chance
you’ll get a piece of the inheritance?
Where? Uncle Shmuel hasn’t liked me
since that thing at the wedding
of mine and Michal’s.
-Why? What happened?
I was at the wedding, I was dead drunk.
It was a great wedding. People came in droves.
But at some point, when I was standing
next to the... what’s her name,
the second cousin, the one with the lazy eye...
Never mind, anyway, I lost
my balance and crashed there.
Pervert! You pervert!
He noticed I was pointing at him and before
he could say anything to me,
Michal opened her mouth at him...
all the nerves she had
about the catering she took out on him.
-Yeah, the food was terrible.
Yeah, but the alcohol was top-notch. In short, there’s
no way I’m seeing anything from his inheritance.
Hey, aren’t you ashamed?
-About what?
Couldn’t you have told me you did
that? You know what a scene
I made about him? You know
what I said to him?
Wow, poor guy. I’m dying. What an embarrassment.
I called him a "smelly dwarf."
But, Mom, he really was smelly.
-I think I’m going to fall!
I kicked him in the leg at some point.
I hope it was the leg.
No, I’m dying. What an embarrassment.
Don’t talk to me anymore.
Mom, come on, I was drunk.
Out of joy, Mom, out of joy. Mom! Mom!
And he got the vase from his mom, my grandma,
and she got it as a gift from her mom.
Wow! That was a really old vase.
-Yeah. Very.
That’s why I was so excited when he gave it to me.
You know that this vase
was with them throughout the Holocaust?
I don’t understand how he managed to do that.
And it’s not like I haven’t heard stories
about a ring, at most a watch,
but a vase? And he was such a cheapskate, Uncle Shmuel.
How he managed to hide it, I don’t know.
That’s why I was so excited when he gave it to me.
So it had sentimental value too.
-You bet.
At first, I didn’t know how to appreciate it,
and Uncle Shmuel, who was a sensitive man,
got a bit offended, I think.
Uncle Shmuel, look. I cleaned.
Uncle Shmuel.
Just a few weeks later, I found out how much it’s worth.
Was it expensive?
-Very.
I have a friend who studied appraisals and treasures
and he checked the vase.
He said not only was it expensive,
it was also very, very rare.
It was made in the East using a very ancient technique,
and the workers who made it used lead paint.
Most of the workers who produced
these vases died,
which is why they stopped making it.
-Lead...
That's why it was so rare.
When I insured the house, I insured
that vase for 2,500 shekels.
That's how the insurance expert valued it.
-How nice!
So you’re calming me down a bit.
That means the vase is insured.
You’ll get your money back.
-You’re so sweet sometimes.
The vase was insured against theft.
Human error isn’t covered.
Where's Pinchas? We need to do the Kiddush.
Wow, lucky it wasn’t me who broke it.
Get your hand off me.
Come on, Dad, you’ll be fine.
Pinchas, what are you doing here?
-Oh, my goodness.
Get up, you need to do the Kiddush.
-Rivka, I’m not feeling well.
What, because of the glass in your foot?
-It hurts.
Oh come on, it’s just a little cut with a band-aid.
What, are you a little kid? Come on, get up already.
Rivka, it hurts. Maybe there's still a shard in my foot.
I can feel it moving
in my veins. It’s heading to my head, Rivka.
Oh, what are you talking about? It’s just a scratch.
Stop being such a baby and come help me a bit.
Don’t you understand that it hurts?
I’m telling you, it hurts.
I don’t know why. Maybe the wound got infected.
I feel like the infection has spread to my other foot too.
How could it have gotten infected already? It just happened three minutes ago,
and besides, Mr. Rosen, my floor is clean.
Yours is cleaner than an operating room, come on.
-There have been cases where they had to amputate.
What will I do without a leg?
Rivka, promise me you won’t let them
take my leg. Promise.
-Oh, dear.
If it comes to that, remember,
you promised. You’re my promise.
No, no, no. I don’t mind dying.
I’ve seen and done everything.
Okay, fine. I promise.
They won’t take your leg. Okay?
Thanks.
-Come on, get up already.
And Rivka, after I die, you can
go out with Giora. I give you my blessing.
Which Giora?
-Giora, Giora. The one you used to hang out with.
The one you met at the disco, "Calypso."
-Giora Habakin?
Giora Habakin.
-He passed away ten weeks ago.
See? First Giora, then
David Shmuel, and now it’s my turn.
Okay, fine. Your turn has come.
But if you don’t mind first
coming to do the Kiddush... after that
you can die as much as you want.
And when you get up there, you can go out
with Giora. I approve.
I’m sure you haven’t done that yet. Get up already!
Are we eating today too?
-I’m starving!
Was there a phone call? Did I hear a phone?
-No, it was probably from the TV.
So answer it, I don’t want to miss that call.
Besides, there was a death in the family.
A little respect for the deceased. What will the neighbors say?
Mom, it’s fine. We’re all
on phone standby. We’re on a mission.
Okay, Shai, go get your dying dad
from the room. I want us to start.
The food is getting cold.
-Okay.
So, Adam, what are your chances
with David Shmuel’s will?
I think they’re around zero.
-Why? What did you do to David Shmuel?
Did you call me?
-No.
Did you call me
because there’s no way I’m going back
to the kitchen for vase stories anymore.
Okay, sit down. Adam is just telling us
what he did to David Shmuel.
So... I don’t know if you remember
but at your wedding, I was pretty drunk.
Total loss.
So I went to the bathroom because I had to relieve myself.
I drank a lot.
I didn't see he was there and... I had to.
No, I'm dying. I told you
he didn't smell good.
I told you he stank.
-Uncle Shmuel was around a lot at the wedding, right?
You're not normal.
-I was drunk.
Come on, Dad. Come sit here.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Hey, Pinchas.
-Hey, Dad.
Shabbat Shalom.
What's up? What are you talking about?
We're assessing who has a chance
to see something from Uncle Shmuel.
For now, the situation doesn't look good.
But, Dad, Uncle Shmuel
kind of liked you, right? So there's a chance...
No chance.
-Why?
I said I liked Uncle Shmuel.
I didn't say he liked me.
What did you do, Dad?
-Well, at Tamari and Michal's wedding...
I was drunk.
-No, I'm dying.
The alcohol was flowing at the wedding and everyone had a great time.
When I'm tipsy, I love to talk
I felt like hugging the little beggar.
Pervert! Oh, you stupid pervert!
Sorry to pull you away
from the family's story time
but there's a problem.
-What happened? Talk to me.
Turns out I broke your mom's
lead vase in the apartment and it's toxic.
And it turns out that vase is worth 2,500 shekels.
-What? Are you sure?
What?
-I thought that vase was worth nothing.
Tell that to Uncle Shmuel.
That's what your mom says it's worth.
And I have to pay you back
because otherwise I won't be able to
look her in the eyes for the rest of my life.
-What's true is true.
And where are we going to get 2,500 shekels now?
-Oh, where have you been?
I was already worried. Come on,
we're starting. Everyone's already seated.
Ben, come on, come on. I'm not feeling well.
Let's wrap this up, Ben.
"On the sixth day, the heavens were finished..."
Did you bring wine?
-Where? I was stuck in the office all day.
When could I move?
-What a bummer with you.
Well, let's drink "and hammers."
I'm starting to feel like your family has a serious
problem.
-Quiet.
No talking during Kiddush. A little respect.
-Sorry.
"Sabri Maranan."
-Cheers!
Shh.
-Sorry, come on. I can't shake this off.
The phone. It's the phone. Pinchas.
Pinchas.
-Come on, answer it.
Rosen family, hello. Regina!
Yes, Regina, open it now. Yes.
What?
What do you mean nothing?
He left everything to widows and orphans?
But I'm an orphan too. Why did he write that?
Come on, why? Why?
He didn't like the way I treated his vase.
Now I don't even have the pleasure
of breaking it.
Yes, Regina. Who is this?
Who is Shabi Hasson?
-It's me. I'm Shabi Hasson.
No, I thought Shabi Rosen.
-No, no, but I was Hasson.
No, but she's in the middle of Kiddush.
Okay, fine Regina. Hold on.
Hello. Yes, this is Shabi Rosen.
Yes, no, but when Uncle Shmuel
met me I was Shabi Hasson.
Yes. How much?
Seriously? Are you sure?
Okay. Thanks. Yeah, I’ll return it.
How much?
-2,500 shekels.
Regina!
What are you... uh.
Ben! Ben!
-What was that?
He didn’t leave anything for anyone
except 2,500 shekels for Shani Hasson.
What? Why?
-He said a few weeks ago
she brought him a lot of joy.
No, I’m dying.
-Rebecca, I’m not feeling well.
Me too, Pinchas. Me too.
My aunt, Regina, with the walker and the oxygen tank
would have passed you.
-Funny.
Do you think he’ll be okay?
-They said in the ER he’ll be fine.
He didn’t absorb much lead. Not fatal
but he’ll need to stay for observation.
Poor Pinchas.
My mom, on the other hand, I’m not sure she’ll recover
from not getting anything.
Yeah, at least you paid her for that poison vase,
so she won’t torture me for life
about breaking it.
I’m not sure she’ll recover from that either.
Yeah, the truth is you’re right. That’s your mom. She
will
always find something to complain about.
It’s in her genes.
The kids fell asleep.
-Did I tell you you’re as beautiful as the day I met you?
Shai. You know what I just thought?
-What?
If a peek at what I have to offer cost Uncle Shmuel
2,500 shekels, how much do you owe me?
I think I need
a few more peeks before I decide.
Do you have cash for tonight?
-Do you take credit?
Dov... Shai... you said Dvir.
What are you seeing, Dvir? Why are you saying "Dvir"?
This thing stuck to me.
You didn’t press well.
-My mom did something to the light.
A piece of glass got into Dad’s foot.
Where?
-Sorry. Sorry.
Have they called from Miami yet? Did we get anything?
No, no, no, this is the only place
Call! Have they called from Miami yet?
I told you no.
-Oh, shoot.
What a pavlova.
I’m sorry I pulled you out in the middle of story time
with your alcoholic family.
-Sorry.
Why are you laughing?
Phone.
Joy! Uh...