You know you look beautiful today?
What?
What’s this? Where’s this coming from all of a sudden?
Just felt like telling you.
Beautiful.
-Come on, stop.
Girls, isn’t Mom beautiful today?
-Yeah.
You’re the prettiest mom in your class.
And you’re the prettiest girls in the world.
Dad’s handsome too.
-Yeah, Dad’s handsome too.
Right.
Even Grandma Riki?
-Yeah, Grandma Riki’s beautiful too.
Tell me that today.
Wait, sweetie,
you’ll tell me that today,
but don’t say Mom told you
to say it, okay?
Even if she asks.
You came up with that yourself.
And don’t use the word “came up with.”
You saw it yourself, okay?
Sit down, what are you doing to the girl?
-What do you want?
Sending her off to battle
without any basic training,
it could ruin her life.
Okay, fine. I didn’t think.
I wanted her to get along with her mom,
like your mom gets along with Itamar’s little one.
No, they don’t get along.
-Oh, they get along just fine.
That little one just reminds your mom
of how she was when she was little.
I don’t think that’s a psychological reason,
I think the little one just scares Mom.
But they get along.
Do you want to help Grandma?
Do you want to draw?
Do you want to stop yelling?
Do you want to annoy Grandma?
Exactly, and for that you deserve a prize,
cake with whipped cream.
You’re going to eat it, whether you like it or not.
I’m telling you, it just looks like they get along,
something’s not right there.
I don’t know, maybe because she’s Smadar’s daughter.
No, where?
The girl is just as annoying
as Itamar was when he was a kid.
At least our dads turned out great.
-Great.
Great.
Not a word of what you heard here to Grandma.
Not a word.
Look at me, look at me and...
In short, I said it’s a disgrace
that half the city is walking around with a husband like hers.
Seriously.
-Totally.
And he’s not even that great of a husband.
Not those, Pinchas, those are the destroyers.
Oh, sure, yeah.
Did you?
-Did you put her to sleep? I don’t know, she got tired all of a sudden.
I just hope she doesn’t stay awake all night now.
She’s with us.
-She’s with us.
Where’s the baby?
-I don’t remember anymore.
After you went to put the girl to bed
I found myself in a shoe store at the mall.
How much did that cost me, babe?
Wait, so listen! Both of you.
So she told me I was right,
and as compensation, I walked out of there with
two pairs of totally amazing shoes.
So how much did it cost me, babe?
-Nothing at all.
She gave them to me as a gift, for free, as compensation.
Even the parking was on the company.
Come on, babe, how nice, you bought something! For free.
What, is this a historic moment?
I'm so proud of you, babe.
-Thanks, babe.
I'm proud of myself too.
Just two weeks ago I bought
this outfit that I returned for some...
On sale.
I had a good week too,
I got an appointment with that doctor from Ramat Aviv,
And there's a good chance I'll go for a check-up next week.
That's great, Dad.
Anything specific?
-My red one came back.
They think it's nothing.
But other than that, everything's great.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
What's up? How's it going?
What's new?
-Hey, girls.
We're all good, how about you?
-We're good, Dad.
Oh, Michal, those are beautiful shoes.
-Thanks.
I saw them at the mall,
Wow, that's 2500 shekels... on sale.
-On sale.
And a big discount, it's buy one get one.
I'll talk to Riki for a sec.
What... how's it going, Itamar?
-Fine, everything's great.
How about you?
-Everything's great, great.
It's great on my end too.
Great.
-Well, if everyone’s great, great.
-Great.
You know that's not a belt, it's connected.
Great.
-Great.
Hey, Riki.
-Hey, Shani.
Wow, what a nice shirt.
-Thanks.
It looks lovely on you.
What's up? What's new?
Great.
-Yeah? What did you make?
As usual, from my hit parade.
Cool, everyone loves schnitzel and mashed potatoes.
Wow, you're so quick, thanks a lot.
Babe, you’re exaggerating, I grew up with three sisters.
I eat
a lot
of beans.
So what's going on outside?
-Everything's great.
What a coincidence, just like in the living room.
What are you talking about?
-Food.
Yeah.
Don't worry, Michal,
I made you a green salad
and threw in some cranberries.
Wow, that's great. Thanks, Riki.
You know cranberries are good
for bladder infections, God forbid.
But I don’t have any.
-So for prevention, just in case,
that way you don’t have to worry.
Do I know where you’ve been hanging out?
Riki.
-What?
Oh, sorry, Michal, I didn’t mean to,
that was out of context! And it was below the belt.
That’s not even a belt, it’s connected.
Connected to...
What a funny little thing, you’re killing me, you.
You know I made a sabrina.
-Stop.
No parts of dead animals.
Wow, Sabreeva, what a joy.
-What joy?
A big joy.
-Wow.
Awesome.
-Awesome.
So, how's your health?
Oh, you won't believe it, the red one I had
just went to Dad.
What do you say? And you see
he’s not freaking out like you do when it happens to him.
I found the kids' dental numbing cream
that one of you forgot at our place,
I applied it, and since then everything's been great.
Awesome.
Did you know that "Zabam" in Russian means "Zubi"?
-Awesome.
How's work, Itamar?
Totally fine.
-Yeah?
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Adamka, great, Shalom to you too.
-Shalom.
What’s up, buddy...
Wait, I have... I have déjà vu.
Haven't you been here before?
Yeah, aren’t you the one who checked my red one?
-Yeah, that’s not something you forget.
Well, if I had a shekel for every time
someone said that to me...
So, would you have a shekel?
I, for sure, am the doctor.
What a coincidence,
next week I have an appointment for my red one,
maybe it’s for Ruby.
I’m not obligated to check it.
-It’s okay, you don’t have to, Tavasmi.
Guys, let’s all come together for a moment, okay?
Last time it was totally fine so...
Awesome.
-Awesome.
How nice, everything’s great, awesome.
Awesome.
-Awesome.
Dad, my battery's dead.
No way.
Let me see.
No, it’s dead.
Okay, Raz, Raz, Raz, relax, relax,
Tavasum, everything’s fine,
nothing happened, nothing happened,
Dad will take care of everything, it’s all good.
-Awesome.
Is that how his voice sounds?
I don’t know, I haven’t heard him talk
for about three weeks.
Here’s the business card,
I know her personally.
"Mariva Meni Padi"?
-Yeah, she also does mustaches.
What?
No, you don’t have a mustache,
she just says she does mustaches too.
Mom.
-What does he want? Why is he yelling like that?
If you want, she also does back and shoulders.
What?
I don’t know, I didn’t get that either.
For Itamar.
Itamar...
Mom, Mom, you won’t believe it,
Raz's battery is dead.
What battery?
-The "PSP" one.
What’s a PSP?
PSP, honey, only hearts have PSP.
PSP is his game,
it’s not good, you don’t understand?
It can go downhill really fast.
Wait, Mom, did you maybe keep that game,
the Tetris I used to have?
It’s probably in one of the drawers.
You know I don’t throw anything away.
Pinchas says it's a big deal.
Otherwise, I would have tossed him too.
'Naf' top, all good, big love.
Come help me find it before
the kids here go out of control.
And all the fun everyone’s having will end.
Okay, okay, why are you so hysterical?
Maybe you should come with us to the fun fair,
it’ll calm you down a bit.
In a fight.
-What's his deal, why is he so stressed?
I don’t know.
But the truth is, now that I think about it,
Whenever Raz is over, he’s glued
to those games of his.
Sometimes I totally forget he’s in the room.
Seriously.
-Yeah.
Once, Itamar and I had a huge fight, yelling and all,
and then we wanted to, you know,
keep yelling and all,
suddenly I realize Raz is in the room.
We moved to the service balcony, he didn’t even notice.
Cool.
So, what’s up, Raz?
Other than the battery, everything’s great.
-Awesome.
Have you gained weight?
-What?
No, not really.
Do you even remember us?
Since when do you have a beard?
-Two weeks.
It doesn’t suit you.
Is this your girlfriend?
-Yeah.
You’re tall.
-True.
Originally from Adam.
Good.
-So why are you dating him?
What, doesn’t it bother you that people laugh at you behind your back?
When you laugh, your belly shakes.
Raz, Raz, come here, you know what?
Here, play a bit with my phone.
-Thanks.
You have a really nice house.
Sorry for replying just now.
I’m free for you tonight,
whenever you want, just come already. A lot.
What?
-That’s an SMS you just got.
And she sent a picture of herself.
She probably just woke up
because she’s not dressed yet.
That’s Dad’s underwear drawer.
Why is it even there?
So look in another drawer and don’t make a mess.
Why don’t you give him a book to read?
-I wish,
he doesn’t even know what a book is,
give him a book, he’ll look for
the on and off button.
A book for them is just something
to throw at their sister when she annoys them.
She was sitting.
-Come on, really.
Tell me, are you normal?
-Tell me, don’t you see she was sitting?
Do you think if I were normal, I’d be
rummaging through Mom’s bra drawer?
Okay, listen to me carefully,
you need to do something about your kid.
He’s not normal.
You know, when he was little and came here,
I’d put headphones on him,
sit him in front of the TV,
he’d sit there for hours.
In the end, I’d give him a reward, chocolate.
Dude, that was predictable.
-Right?
And you still haven’t seen it coming.
Come on, go wash up.
-I need to drink something.
Want me to pour you some water?
-Do you have something stronger?
Oh, yeah, sure.
What’s this?
Weird creator, everything's done.
Water.
-Water.
Wow, it's so nice Adam brought you again.
-Yeah.
So great you came
even though you've been here before! You already know.
You know what?
-That this family isn't really normal.
I don't know, I must've missed that last time.
Major miss.
-Yeah, like my husband exposed himself to you,
Not mentally, of course
because he never does that.
But physically, he showed you his red.
Honestly, I didn't think about it then.
You know, I'm used to seeing a lot
because of my internship...
Reds.
-Come on, I would die.
No, so I have a ton of questions.
Can that red go away when you do it?
Okay, I'm going to do it in the living room.
Good, great she left.
So, do you see a lot, in the "K"?
So, does this apartment have a back exit?
No, I wish, it's a third floor.
There's a drain, but it's loose.
I see you thought about it.
-I've been here for five weeks.
What?
-You have to see this,
Itamar's Raz ran out of battery in the game,
so it turns out the kid is like the kid from the emperor's clothes,
showing everyone his underwear.
-Nice.
What did he say about me?
What else can be said about me? Too fat.
-Nice.
And true.
Come on, come on.
If you see a cross-eyed person,
you don't say to their face "hey, cross-eyed"
or "hi, dwarf" or "hello, Arab",
you keep that inside, in your heart,
or say it quietly to me
like Grandma Rachel does, okay?
Okay, Dad, with all due respect,
that's not how to deal with this problem.
Hello, Aunt Shvi, wow, you look great.
-Thanks, you're so sweet.
Wow, the kid's a genius, I don't understand
what problem you're talking about.
What's up, man?
-Boring.
Yeah, you're a hundred percent right.
What, do you want my phone?
I'll let you play with it.
I get that, it's not worth it.
What, so what's the deal, babe?
Aunt Shvi, you're beautiful.
Thanks.
-So how come you're with him even though he's fat?
You see?
-First of all, you should start taking care.
And Raz, I have a feeling you're a bit worried
because maybe deep down you feel
you're a bit like Shai?
I have no battery—
Forget the game, come hear something, Raz,
love is really something that doesn't depend
on size, not on length,
not on color, not on a girl's hair length,
it's just love between two people.
Like I love Shai! Shai loves you.
Yeah? So why does he always look
at Adam's weird friends?
What?
You always get to know them
at least three times every evening.
Shai, big problem, Shai, big problem.
You're so funny.
-Totally, he's right.
Aunt Shvi is also beautiful, why are you looking at others?
Dad, I need your computer urgently,
I can't find my Tetris anywhere.
What happened? What,
he said something already, right? What did you say?
Never mind, Dad, computer, kid, now.
No way, Itamar,
the computer's broken, it's got a virus.
Every time I open it,
feet pop up on the screen.
Who even films their own feet?
Adam, do you want to tell me something?
No.
Why did you bring the same girl twice?
Is this serious? Should I start looking for a dress?
Mom, relax, no one's getting married, okay?
So you went out twice with the same girl, it happens.
That doesn't mean anything. It's just nice to hang out together.
Adam, nice doesn't get you to the rabbi.
And I want to remind you she's a doctor,
Dad would be really happy to have a doctor in the family.
You know, you don't just find doctors on the street.
You'd be surprised, we met on the street the second time.
-What do you mean, on the street?
Like, literally on the street.
You want to tell me she's...
-No, Mom, she's not a hooker.
I didn't say she's a hooker,
but you know, there are stories about girls
who work the streets to pay for their studies.
Okay, so she's not, alright?
-Are you sure?
Because there are stories like that, you know.
Mom, yes, I'm a hundred percent sure.
I'm not marrying her and she's not working the streets.
Fine.
-We actually met at a juice stand.
Great.
I just want you to remember
that no one will ever love you like your mom does,
no one ever.
Mom, enough already.
-Fine.
I love you too.
-Great.
You know girls work too, drinking juice,
mostly cranberry juice.
What? Don't tell me you're upset about what Raz said.
Do I look upset to you?
What, do I look upset?
A little.
-No, not at all, it's totally fine,
so my husband looks at other girls, it's all good.
It's like Hanukkah candles, right? Just for looking.
You're not doing anything, right?
-Exactly, not doing anything,
nothing, I'm not doing anything.
I don't even do the dishes.
You think this is the time for jokes?
Come on, what's up?
-Sit down, I swear to you,
I don't even notice
that I'm looking at other women.
I'll tell you why, because I'm looking through them,
because I'm searching for you, only you, always you
and nothing but... you.
-Alright then.
And all the charm you're spreading
on every random girl?
That's just silly, you have a silly husband,
it's just a childish joke,
I don't even realize I'm doing it.
Fine, so stop doing it,
okay? Because it doesn't make me laugh.
I stopped.
-Great.
That's it, it's over.
Peace?
-Ceasefire.
Dad, what is this? It's all feet,
you can't get out of this.
It needs a password.
-It's not accepting the password anymore.
What, is this a virus from some pervert site?
Wait, wait, Dad, what's your password?
Itamar, enough, leave it, come on.
You need to change it anyway, right?
Try a pisalayer.
-Pisalayer? Is that a type of food?
No, it's legs, I know from Grandma.
Mom.
-Will I be bald too?
Yes, Raz, you'll be bald, big time.
But why?
-Because that's what I decided, that's why, what can I do?
Wait, hold on a second.
Do you see what you did?
-Adam, don't worry,
he'll be bald, big time.
Rzikiluli, look what I brought you.
-A charger?
No, better, a pocket calculator.
Now you can calculate how many weeks
you're cutting off my life.
That shirt looks really nice on you, honey.
-Thanks.
The friends look really nice.
Okay, I'm going to see what other damage
he can do.
Hey there.
Shai, big problem.
I just can't believe it.
What is it? What happened?
-Itamar's little one threw up.
On time.
Come on, is the girl okay?
No, she's not okay, she threw up like crazy.
She went back to sleep,
I need to clean the shower again.
Oh, maybe it's something she ate.
Michal, what did you give her to eat?
-Me? I never give her food,
she scares me, she's crying.
-Only you.
Like a moon... she hasn't eaten anything all day, Mom.
Grandma gave her sabrina.
Right, there's sabrina after the meal.
Wait, Riki, didn't you say you put
alcohol in the sabrina?
Of course, sabrina.
Sabrina, sabrina, but what kind of alcohol
did you put in there, Mom?
Rum, of course, and whatever I had at home,
a bit of cognac, a bit of Perno for flavor
and a bit of vodka from the freezer.
This isn't a kitchen, it's an active bar.
Riki, it's not good to mix alcohol like that.
But you drink a lot.
Who?
-You, every time we come back from Grandma Riki
you drink wine and say you needed it.
Okay, it's just a little red wine, it's healthy.
Also white, after you finish the red, it's created.
It dissolves the stones in...
Like a moon.
A bit...
It's crazy here.
Like always in the Rosen family.
You're really pretty, you know?
-Thanks.
But you must have been an ugly kid, right?
-No, actually not.
Really.
You must have a tendency to gain weight, right?
No, not at all, I actually eat like a cow.
I'm on a weight gain diet because I'm just a bit underweight.
Underweight, how nice.
Yeah.
-Why not.
And your hair, like...
-I wash it and go out.
Wash it and go out. Sure, why not?
What?
-Nothing, I just asked if you want sabrina?
Oh, no, I don't like sweet.
-Oh, I don't like sweet.
Of course.
Alright, if you don't mind, I'll drink
your Sabri too, okay?
What's up, bro? Second time with the same girl?
Why, does it bother you to tell her?
Shai, that's a big problem.
A big problem, Shai, Shai.
-Come on, let's go grab a Sabri, come on.
Shai.
-Come on.
No.
What’s that? Just go already.
Board games?
-You think so?
What, poker?
-But there’s no computer.
We have cards.
Real ones?
-Of course, for "Texas Hold'em."
What's going on?
-You can't let the kid play poker.
Come on, it's just a game.
Get up for a sec.
Babe.
-Come on, babe, let’s go.
Come on, what, playing?
-No, shh, Michal doesn’t let you.
You know you sometimes have a valley girl tone, right?
Okay, okay, come on, just deal already.
He's a kid, you don't need to teach him to play poker.
I don’t think as an alcoholic
you can preach to me.
Well...
Not great, not great at all,
I warned you! This is just the beginning.
Two pairs of queens.
Three of a kind.
He's cheating.
-I'm bored.
You adjust your glasses when you lie,
you laugh and apologize
when you have good cards.
And you don’t really know how to play.
-Come on, fine.
Well, what does it matter?
We're not playing for money anyway.
Let’s play again.
You're doing what you always say
about Grandma Riki: that meddler...
Thank you very much.
Find him a battery for heaven's sake.
-Mom, Mom.
Valley girl, huh?
Mom, he's a kid.
You don’t interfere in my relationship with Pini
just like I don’t interfere in yours with Shai.
You don’t...
Sorry.
Don’t think I didn’t see your initial reaction.
Roko, Rolo, Rolo,
I said that as a joke
and I didn’t think the kid was listening,
he had headphones on.
What, he hears with the headphones?
And you, for example, everything you said
around the kid, did you mean it?
What, when he was little I talked to him a lot.
Or
'or
One of your brothers is always introducing himself,
his wife wishes I’d die,
the other brother shows me his red card,
his wife tells me about her sex life
and their kid is always making fun of me
and your mom keeps pushing cranberry juice on me.
But babe, they’re just showing you they love you.
I came for a follow-up check.
Just kidding, I’m just desperate,
I don’t know what to do anymore.
Help!
Does anyone have a PSP?
I do.
Wait, don’t move, I’m coming down,
don’t move, I’ll be right there, don’t move.
It scares me.
-But I know who’s more scared.
Who?
-Mom.
Turns out she told us
what she thinks about each of us.
So just in case you get confused...
Thanks, thanks, thanks.
There are plenty of situations where I drink,
it’s not aimed at them.
Like, I drink when I go out with friends,
I drink after class, I drink
when I meet the girls for lunch,
In the mornings, hardly ever.
-Sure, sure.
Only on Saturdays.
Wha...
No problem at all.
-We talked about this earlier, right?
Why are you surprised?
I heard you talking
to your mom on the phone about the Rosen family.
That’s not nice, I’m sure they
didn’t mean for us to hear that.
Grandma is right.
-Not bad stuff, I hope.
Are curses considered bad?
-Shai, can I?
Hey, Raz, didn’t Grandma ever tell you
what she thinks about each of us?
Of course.
-Move, move.
I bought this from some kid for 2,800 shekels down below.
Wait, nothing, don’t talk now.
Here, Dad’s connecting, yeah.
Here, please.
This is great.
-Awesome.
Should we go eat?
You drank the leftovers earlier?
-Yeah.
I have a feeling they need this.
-Cheers!
Sh’, that’s a big problem.
That’s a joke that got out of hand.
Okay, I got it, I’ll remember, it won’t happen again.
Alright.
Everything’s good.
You really look beautiful today.
Wow.
Adam’s girlfriend is prettier because you’re older.
We need to buy her a PSP.
A bimbo, huh? Great bimbo.
Wow, how nice, sweet, sweet.
Sorry.
When you laugh, your belly shakes.
What?
-Raz, Raz, Raz, come...
I’d be looking now
in the underwear, for the bras...
You have to do something about your son,
he’s not normal.
Michal doesn’t agree with you.
You know sometimes you have...
Does it make you laugh that I got stuck?
-Me too.
It doesn’t matter the size, the length...