Nice.
Weird.
-Why? It's nice to break the routine a bit.
I'll say it's nice when we're on our way back home.
Listen, it was a complicated week,
what’s it like taking Mom and Dad
out to dinner on a Friday?
It's like pulling a wisdom tooth from a stubborn person.
Yeah, I don’t get why they’re so glued to home.
Like two turtles.
-Yeah.
Speaking of being glued at home,
you’re not exactly a free spirit yourself.
What are you comparing? I don’t really have anywhere to go,
mainly I don’t have anyone to go with.
Okay, you need to think about what came first,
the fact that you don’t have anyone to go with, so you don’t go out,
or you don’t go out because you don’t have anyone.
Isn’t there a third option?
There is, but I don’t want to offend anyone.
Hey, have you ever thought about writing questions
for the psychometric exam?
-Of course.
A couple goes out to a restaurant on Friday
night to celebrate their anniversary.
Meanwhile, a turtle leaves Binyamina, who will arrive first?
Why don’t you take the girls tomorrow
to the turtle bridge at Alexander Stream?
It’s going to be a really nice weekend.
Oh, oh, Moroccan,
are you planning to take the girls to the turtle bridge?
Seriously, I’m not leaving the house day after day.
So don’t make suggestions, no turtles, no stress.
Anyway, tomorrow they’re going to Grandpa Pinchas,
he looks like a turtle himself.
Do you think Shai will manage?
Shai? You mean the driver of Mr. Miss Daisy?
Could you please close the window? I’m cold.
Of course, ma'am.
-Wow, wow, wow...
What’s this supposed to be? What, do you want to suffocate me?
Okay, look, close that window
and open that one.
And turn on the heat.
Mom.
Look at me, look at me and...
Do me a favor, next time I travel,
remind me to leave a quarter of an hour early
to adjust the seat back to my size and shape.
What happened?
They’re building wide roads here.
Why did we even have to go out?
What, can’t we do this at home?
Trust me, a bottle of wine would have been enough.
-True.
Believe me.
-Really, come on, what’s this? They want to celebrate you,
your kids want to pamper you,
Orna booked a spot at an amazing bistro,
it has great reviews.
Ben, boy
Benny
What happened?
The windshield, if you want to clean it,
you need to do it from the outside
because the sprayer isn’t working.
Forget it, forget it, the high beams are too bright.
Hey Shai, what’s this heat about?
-It’s on grill.
Want me to put on some music?
-The radio isn’t working.
Should I sing?
No.
-No.
And let’s go out a bit
the night was pale
in the expanses...
the lights.
And you were here without him passing by.
Are you sure about those words?
-Yeah.
"The jackal howled because he had no food."
May the name save us.
Hadar, we thought you wouldn't make it.
-No, here we are, all good.
I'm Gal, the shift manager.
Where... I spoke with Orna?
Yes, yes, I'm back, Orna is the older sister.
I'm Meirav, the younger sister,
the one who still hasn't left home.
Nice to meet you, I hope everyone is out and on their way.
-Yeah, yeah.
Is there a problem?
-No, no, God forbid, there's no problem,
It's just that when I booked the VIP room
I told you, it's yours until 8:30 PM,
after that, I have a very important event here.
What, are you implying ours isn't important?
No, no, of course not,
I'm just saying I can't
be flexible about this.
And on other days, is there room for flexibility?
Well, if you'll excuse me,
I have a few important things to sort out in the kitchen.
Cute.
So authoritative.
-Yeah.
And was there a client there?
The wine and the glass are here with me.
-Okay.
Is it still a long drive?
-No, just five minutes.
Silvan, what's that red light on the dashboard?
What, is it Aladin's light?
-What, is it out of oil?
Hit the dashboard.
No, at the air conditioning vent.
Not at...
Your side, over there.
Okay?
-Yeah.
But isn't that dangerous?
-No, what's dangerous?
Sali arranged for a car to run without oil,
it's a low-fat car.
Why the insistence that the parents arrive after everyone?
It's not a surprise.
Oh, right, but I think it would be nice for them to arrive
and everyone shouts "Congratulations." Nice.
Let it be.
I'm starving, where is everyone really?
Manny has a new baby, cool,
but where are Orna and Moshe?
And she even booked the place.
Right, you're absolutely right.
Here comes the cute authoritative one.
Is everything okay?
-They're on their way,
we're just a family that
is always late.
The family just isn't used
to leaving the house, so there's a bit of pressure.
But don't worry, everything settles down after the food,
which is 13 minutes after it's served.
-I get it.
-Not really.
Orna, honey, where are you?
Come on, hurry up,
in a minute they'll kick us out of the restaurant.
From the bistro, all good.
I understand that's
so tell Moshe to take a detour
barely any traffic light and just get here.
Do you have family coming from the far south?
No, they live in a Yemenite moshav, Moshe.
I don't know them but it sounds Zionist.
Hey, are you by any chance looking for a shift supervisor?
-No.
No, thanks.
But where are you guys now?
-No, no. Why did we leave here?
And just so you know, the next exit
is only seven kilometers away.
And my parents live ten minutes from the restaurant in Kfar Saba.
Honey, do me a favor, hurry up.
Ten minutes.
Really.
Since when do we have a private jet
that you measure in a straight line?
My parents are about to get there,
there’s a lot of pressure at the bistro,
and you’re taking us on a trip south.
But I’m telling you, the signage is terrible.
How can you understand where to turn here?
-Of course, terrible signage,
but for some reason, it only happens to you, right?
You think all those people driving ahead of us
aren’t making mistakes, of course?
They actually look pretty confident in their way.
Believe me, you look confident to them too.
-Yeah, really very confident.
You’re such a fool.
Hey, do you think you stressed out the cute guy?
I need to stall my parents.
-I need to change my approach.
(Unintelligible)
Are you managing with them?
-Yeah, yeah.
Oh, like you can’t expand.
-Yeah.
So you’re only answering me with yes or no now?
Are you really suffering?
-Yeah.
(Unintelligible)
Give it to me.
Hello, honey.
-Hey, Mom, congratulations.
What’s going on?
Look, I’m not sure we’ll make it today.
Why, what happened?
-I don’t know,
the lights on the clock board keep flashing,
I feel like I’m in a cash cab
with all the blinking lights.
I told Dad we need to sell this antique,
he insists on fixing the old clunker.
Mom, can you give Shai back to me for a second?
Okay, but make it quick
because he’s on the phone,
the hands-free is broken too.
Oh, honey.
-Honey, listen for a second,
just no one has arrived yet,
so I need you to stall them
just a tiny bit, okay? Just a little.
But, what...
-Try to calm them down,
I don’t know, play them some music.
No, the radio’s broken too, I’m singing to them.
It’s a great car.
-It was. Ten weeks ago.
It was a great car.
"Take a break
and don’t think..."
-In the meantime
"just go out
to the street..."
Okay, he’s stalling them, I hope.
What’s wrong with you? What are you doing?
Okay, how do you want me to be, like this?
Hasn’t anyone arrived yet?
-No. Look, I’m talking to them,
they’re really, really close.
Come on, really, Galchuk...
No need for equipment, just a wave is fine.
How close are they?
Shabbat Shalom.
-This close.
This is Orna, the sister you talked to.
Hi, Shabbat Shalom.
And this is Moshe, her husband, a tour guide.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
I'll send you a waiter.
-Really?
Here’s a fix, wait, a waitress to take the order.
So, how was the trip? Did you see an alpaca?
Look, we ended up being the first ones here.
What was the deal? Hey! Are you sure you didn’t get lost?
But just as we were about to enter
we suddenly saw the bistro sign.
I'm great at getting confused.
-Yeah, for sure.
Where are Manny and Alin?
-Hold on, I'm calling him now.
What, flirting with the manager?
No way.
-No way.
What's up, Manny, where are you guys?
Shani, what's the rush, have they arrived yet?
No, but everyone else is here except you.
If you plan to be late, you better turn around!
Why does the manager need this room at 8:30?
Well, we got held up because of the kid,
he had a stomach ache, diarrhea,
all the mess came out.
Okay, Manny, spare me the details.
And about the owner, tell him
it's been 13 minutes and the food is behind us.
Manny, get here right away and no third-grade excuses.
But Manny...
Fine, I didn’t want to tell her
I got stuck in the bathroom.
How long are you going to use Sivan
for your excuses?
How long will this last, a year, a year and a half?
So, what then?
-When he grows up, we'll have another one.
You’ll have another one.
I'm sorry, babe, Shani just stresses me out.
What, is she nervous?
-No, just acting tough.
You're really tough today.
-Yeah, I'm sorry,
but they're in the car with the parents,
I've been holding them up for hours.
They have car troubles.
He's already singing them old Israeli songs
part seven,
So you want me to stay calm?
Okay, fine, you're right, it's stressful,
but do me a favor, Shani.
Shani, Shani,
Someone once told me that to relax,
to relieve stress,
it's good to tell or hear a joke,
it's something! Biological that releases endorphins,
the brain laughs and it works on the nervous system.
Does anyone have a joke?
Alright, I'll tell one.
I'll tell one, I actually have a current joke.
Two guys at a restaurant conference, they order a waitress.
-What’s that?...
They're hungry, they order a waitress, two guys.
Hello again, everyone.
You said you’d send a waitress,
did you miss us?
They're all busy, I'll take everyone's order.
Yeah, the problem is not everyone has arrived yet.
I have an idea. Why don’t you call them,
ask each one what they want to eat,
and that way, when they arrive, the dishes will be ready.
Orna, take care of this.
I just noticed, this is the regular menu.
Do you have a business menu?
-No.
Am I in a joke? You're really making me laugh now.
Shani, what’s going on?
We’ve been driving around for hours.
Babe, babe, just drive around with them a bit longer, come on.
It’s just that Manny and Alin haven’t arrived yet.
You're not a mess.
-No.
Seriously.
-Am I a mess?
I can't take it anymore, I'm out of songs
and they're going crazy back there.
"In the Negev's wilderness, a fox roams."
I promise, I'll tell you when to come,
okay? Patience.
Well, I think it's because we're all hungry.
Oh man.
So think of a proper compensation.
Ask them what they want to order already.
What do you want to order?
What, should I recite the menu to them now?
There was a murder here, seriously.
Order, Moshe! Everything's fine.
Alright, I'm without a headset
and there's a patrol car behind me, bye, bye.
No, I, I, I, I'm fine.
Well, in the rest, just from him, and you can never
know what he orders.
He can look at the menu
and say "I want this."
Well, maybe you should call Manny,
check if there's any progress?
You call, you have the go-ahead.
Hello, babe.
-Yeah, Meirav.
He sounds far away.
Where are you?
-Here!
Shabbat Shalom.
-What are you doing? What's up?
-What's up, Moishe?
Alin. Nice to meet you, are you with Meirav?
Not really. More like, not at all.
I'm here to take your orders.
What would you like to order?
-One second.
Can we see the menu again?
-Orna, can you summarize for him?
Alright, everyone’s here,
I'm calling Shai to bring them.
What's up, babe, are you still singing?
So now you won't talk to me all evening?
-What do you want me to talk about?
Not really singing, I switched to digestion.
What's up?
-Everything's fine,
Everyone's here, you can bring them.
Thank God. Oops.
-What, what happened?
I'm without a headset.
Babe?
What happened? Shai, can you hear me?
You with the bald head, pull over, please.
I don't know. Well, he's on the way, they're coming here.
Alright, friends, I'm glad you all made it.
It's not really everyone.
-I don't really care.
I'll speed up your orders.
-Benny
In the meantime, bring some salads,
snacks, so there's something to munch on.
This is a respectable bistro,
it's not one of those tapas places.
No, no, no. Not tapas,
no, no. Salads, pickles, olives,
Here, sprinkle a bit.
I get it, I'll ask them
to bring you the appetizers.
Hungry.
Say, do you think they'll arrive on time?
Yeah, yeah, Benny, they're on the way, they'll be here any minute.
As soon as they walk in, "Happy Birthday!" everyone shouts, right?
What did you do?
-He probably saw me talking on the phone.
How much is it today in points?
-I don't know,
The points aren't for the car, they're for you.
Good evening.
-It can't get better than this. What's up?
Sir, didn't you notice what
a cloud of smoke you're putting out back there?
I need to take you off the road.
You see, now your car is smoking like a train too.
Wait, maybe that's why the red light came on.
There's not a single warning light that hasn't lit up in this car,
just the one for the headlights!
Rachel,
This isn't the time or the place.
Officer, this isn't even
my car. You see,
Those in the back, that's my in-laws,
and the family made me drive them
to their anniversary party.
May you know no more sorrow.
-Thank you.
Look, I'll let it slide this time
because of your delicate situation,
but on Sunday, the car's going to the shop. Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom, officer.
You see? He let me off,
so it's not that bad, right?
Alright, let's go, we're almost there.
I don't get it. Is there a code, a password?
What:
And a horse
boy
Only death can release you from this.
The invitation's in the kitchen, but I'm afraid we won't make it.
Manny, Manny, Manny...
We were chosen, is there a registered ear?
-Good.
Really give them a few minutes,
let it be background and we'll be done with the blessing.
They're here, you just talked to them,
I can hear them already.
Look, I can hear them.
I'm going to get the wine menu.
In restaurants, if you just order the wine menu,
they treat you nicely right away.
I'm telling you something's not right, it doesn't make sense.
Hold on, I'm calling Alin again.
R
bo% koro
b'tz y
honey,
You turned on the high beams. I told you it shortens the battery.
We're stuck with the car, honey.
Stuck?
-What do you mean stuck?
I need to check something,
I'll be right back, okay?
Alright, I need to peek under the hood.
You guys will be okay?
Alright, that's it. Enough, I can't take it anymore,
I want you to call me a cab, I want to go home.
Rachel, this is a rare coincidence, I'm telling you,
I'm handling this car with kid gloves.
What do you think, I'm an animal?
Sitting here on my anniversary,
stuck in the back of the car like this?
Is this a car? This isn't a car, it's a junkyard waiting to happen.
So what, this car
is doing this to you on purpose?
Alright, enough, it's not going to help you this time.
I'm trying, you see I'm trying, right?
Alright, I'm just feeling down.
Well, I thought I'd give this to you
in front of everyone, in front of the kids and all...
I don't see us getting anywhere today at all.
What is it?
Aristotle said:
"Love is one soul in two bodies,
here we all are sitting together at the bistro.
In front of me is the whole family, sons and grandsons,
and we who are united, two bodies in one soul,
and we're all filled with joy.
If love is a flower,
that no one can know when it will bloom,
I'm happy
to blossom with you and grow with you
and to nurture more flowers and leaves within us
and look, I brought you a pair of earrings."
Sali...
Wow, what a...
What, beautiful?
-Amazing, amazing.
I talked to "Direct Mechanic" and they're on their way.
Can you wait outside?
-I...
This is the wine menu.
Wow.
So, do you have any Israeli wines?
-All the wines here are Israeli.
Any direction?
-Show me for a sec.
Do you happen to have wine for Kiddush?
No, you said you’d bring it.
-Yeah, but that's with Shai and my parents.
And we'll wait for them.
Can I get cranberry juice in the meantime?
-Sure.
And put a plate of mushroom hummus
here for everyone.
Dad! How many pitas?
This is a bistro.
Rachel, I'm really sorry about what happened,
Can you forgive me?
-Of course.
Do you forgive me?
-For what?
So, can we? Can we already?
-What now?
Listen, I have an idea.
-Come on.
We won't make it to the bistro on time, right?
-Yeah.
And they're all there stressed and hungry.
Let's open the wine, call them,
and do Kiddush with them over the phone.
And what's the plus?
-What?
The wine is all ours.
That's a great idea.
I'll call Shani.
Honey, listen, we're stuck here, we called for a tow,
but we came up with a brilliant idea,
to do Kiddush with you over the phone.
Wow, they want to do Kiddush together on the phone.
Cool, cool, everyone’s hungry anyway.
Great, so gather everyone
and put the phone on speaker.
Alright, I’m putting it on.
You’re on speaker.
Silvan, ready?
Hello, can everyone hear?
Come on
come on
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom, everyone.
Here you go.
What, you don’t have... so give...
Do you have a choice?
-Well...
Here you go.
"On the sixth day, the heavens and the earth and all their hosts were finished.
And God finished on the seventh day all His work which He had done
and He rested on the seventh day from all His work which He had done.
And God blessed the seventh day and sanctified it."
Sorry to interrupt...
-Sorry, sorry, we're in the middle of Kiddush.
Where?
-On the phone.
"Sabri Maranan."
-L'Chaim.
"Blessed are You, Lord our God, King of the universe
who creates the fruit of the vine."
Amen.
Listen, due to scheduling conflicts,
I really have to clear you out of the VIP room,
I need to prepare it for the next event.
So here’s the food you ordered.
Is this a new service, "Take Away Go Away"?
Eat it at the entrance or take it
home, enjoy!
Here’s the bill.
Do you accept coupons?
That doesn't include service, got it?
So, can we go?
-Alright, have a good Shabbat.
Shabbat Shalom and thanks.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Wow, this wine is nice, you know?
So, we're heading home?
-Home, home.
Yeah, home.
Don't you prefer if I sing?
No.
-No.
Then move the "N" forward.
No, you don't drink while driving.
"When I'm sad and my heart feels heavy..."
Here, take the bottle and be quiet.
Congratulations.
What a wild one.
Those earrings, Mom—
Dad bought them for me.
It was a really exciting experience.
Yeah, I would have skipped it,
but there's no doubt it brought us closer and strengthened our love.
So, how was the bistro?
Were the reviews good?
They kicked us out of the restaurant over the food, Erez.
But they packed it nicely.
Mom, admit you won't forget
this anniversary for a long time.
No, no, definitely not,
it was the weirdest anniversary...
I've ever had.
They even packed my orange juice.
Did you think about compensation?
I brought you gourmet food, isn't that enough?
I'm not talking about food.
About other compensation.
So on my parents' anniversary
you take them to a restaurant.
No, no, no, no, just not that, God forbid.
Whatever you want, I'll do, just not that.
Okay, then I want you to let me
sleep until 11:00 tomorrow without waking me up.
Shabbat morning, nice day, huh?
Mom...
-drinks a lot of coffee.
Exactly.
And only at 11:00
Dad reads a lot of newspapers.
A lot of balloons.
What time did you tell the babysitter we’re arriving?
There's time, what’s the rush?
Three minutes, drive fast.
Close the window.
Open...
You need to say "open the..."
What is she doing?
"The jackal howled because he had no food."
Maybe that's why the warning light came on...
-Yeah, there's not just one warning light...
Officer, officer, move, move a bit.
What are you stuck?
-What are you stuck?
Why in a Persian accent?
The points are on the car, it's not...
What are you stuck?
"And he rested on the seventh day from all his work which he had done..."
I messed up the text.