I hope you won't forget to talk
to your mom about Saturday, okay?
Otherwise, it’ll cost a lot of money.
For sure, for sure, a lot of money.
-Yeah.
Remind me what’s happening on Saturday.
Oh, you forgot already? The girl's ballet performance.
No, no, I didn’t forget, why would I forget?
Is it happening on Saturday?
-Yeah.
Okay, okay, okay.
Time flies.
-Crazy.
Look at that, in two weeks,
basically, 14 days have passed, amazing.
And the babysitter?
-She can’t, she has exams.
And my mom is taking my dad for tests.
So you won’t forget?
-Forget what?
To talk to your mom about the ballet?
Maybe we should let my mom rest?
Why? Why always let your mom rest?
She herself says
she’ll only rest in the grave, God willing,
So until that happens, at least let her help us.
I really think it’s a bad idea
to ask my mom.
Wow, come on, aren’t you tired of yourself?
Seriously, aren’t you tired of yourself
that you can’t stand up once
to your mom and insist?
Because everything you ask her, she says no.
When it’s something really important
then I know how to ask and insist.
Yeah? So here, now you need
to insist, don’t you get it?
Let’s see you be a man, standing
in front of your mom face-to-face
not like some Arab baboon.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom, with my respect.
-Shabbat Shalom, Dad.
Shabbat Shalom, Shabbat.
How are you?
-What’s up?
Shai’s whining is coming soon.
You have a mission, right?
-No whining will happen.
Is Shai about to whine?
-A little.
He needs to go talk to Riki about Saturday.
What’s happening on Saturday?
-We have the big ballet performance
and I have no one to leave the little one with.
You want Riki to babysit.
-Yeah, I know,
I thought if it works out,
I don’t know, maybe she’ll agree.
You made me laugh. Since when does Riki agree to anything?
If it accidentally slips out of her mouth,
I immediately know she’s not feeling well.
That’s what annoys me, Pinchas,
you know how annoying that is?
I hear all my friends talking
about how grandmas run around the house yelling "take the grandkids."
And Riki, as you say, is a mess.
Oh, Riki is a mess,
that was her name before she got married.
Shabbat, you’re putting Shai in a deadly minefield
that no one has returned from with a yes.
Have mercy on him.
Where is she? Why isn’t she coming to say hello?
Shabbat’s in the living room, she’s saying hello to Dad.
Take it easy, Mom.
-I’m completely calm.
Are there any leftovers from the schnitzel butchers?
What happened? You can tell me, I’m your mom.
What’s wrong? Did she do something to you?
Do you need legal advice? Help?
-Help, yes.
Here it goes.
Mom, we need you to help us watch the little one
on Saturday
because the big one has a performance in ballet class.
Is that it? I thought something happened to you.
No, nothing's happened to me so far.
So why didn’t you just say it when you got here?
Why did you have to beat around the bush?
You know me, I like it
when people are straightforward.
So is that okay with you?
-How did you come to that conclusion?
If you were an only child, maybe that would be less likely.
But as you know, you’re not an only child
and if I agree to babysit for you,
your siblings will line up.
Especially Adam.
-Even one Adam is a lot.
Mom, come on,
why don’t you help out? They’re your granddaughters.
Shai, you know I love your granddaughters
and I have no problem with them,
but if I agree this time
Itamar will come with his kids
and ask me to babysit for him too.
His kids, let them stay with a babysitter, they’re a bit tough.
Not like your little angels, whom I love so much
and I’m ready to do anything for them.
So I take it you’re saying no.
Understanding has never been your problem.
She’s so negative
that this game of yes, no, black, white
for her it’s just no, black.
In the atoms that make her up
there are no protons or neutrons
just negative electrons.
What, Pinchas, are you telling me
she’s never said yes?
Maybe when I proposed to her.
-No, what, then she said yes.
Not exactly, I think she said:
"Well, at least there’ll be someone to bury me."
I’m just kidding, of course.
-Yeah, yeah, of course.
Shabbat Shalom.
Hey, Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
What’s this? Itamar is downstairs?
Why?
-Shabbat Shalom.
You’re not.
Meet Ravit.
My dad, Pinchas.
-Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, Ravit, I’m Shai.
You rascal.
-I...
Ravit, you look familiar to me,
haven’t you been here before?
-I don’t think so.
Awesome.
So Itamar isn’t here yet.
This isn’t an April Fool’s joke, right?
-No.
Unless they moved daylight saving time
six months ahead.
No?
-No.
Maybe... maybe this time, Mom,
just this once, you’ll agree.
Shai, I explained to you why not and it’s final.
But Mom, it’s really important to me.
I raised my kids and I raised them well,
now it’s your turn.
And they don’t know each other?
-No.
Who?
Ravit... Ravit?
Excuse me, what do you do?
I’m a lingerie model.
-Nice.
And you don’t mind the whole world seeing your underwear?
Not everyone thinks about nudity right away,
you know, underwear is like a swimsuit,
you don’t see anything.
Dad, anyone who wants to see underwear today
doesn’t need Ravit for that,
they just go online.
Do you have the address of her website?
-She doesn’t have her own site.
But you can just go
to any website and see everything there.
Any website?
Any dot co dot
Giorgio Armani question mark.
Hey, the girls are here.
Can you come to the balcony for a sec?
-Sure, Luli Shbaluli.
Sit down.
-What?
Wow, who’s that?
-That’s Shai, my brother.
No way, I can’t believe it, he looks just like my brother-in-law.
No, I’m dying.
Are you sure they don’t know each other?
-I’m sure.
Rascal.
I see you came back with your tail tucked in.
Should I guess the answer?
-No, the tail isn’t tucked.
I argued, I stood my ground,
but in the end, I considered her and gave in.
Oh, you gave in. What a noble soul,
truly a righteous among the nations.
I feel like planting a whole forest in your name.
Sorry, Shai, she gave me a logical explanation.
That’s why I didn’t push too hard.
What logical explanation did she give?
That she’s a misanthropic
obsessive narcissist?
Kind of, she just phrased it a bit differently.
You’re exactly what I
thought of you, you’re a wimp.
Wimp is too strong a word, you’re a softie.
What are we going to do about Saturday?
-If there’s no solution, there’s no ballet.
And just so you know, the girl has been
working on this performance for a week.
Aren’t you exaggerating a bit?
-No, it’s either your mom or everything’s canceled.
And just know that you’re the one who’ll go and tell the girl
that because of your mom, there’s no ballet.
Shabbat Shalom, Dad.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
What’s up?
-The crying of Itamar.
There won’t be any crying.
Sweetie.
Ohh
ohh
Amazing.
Ronit, meet Michal.
Hi, nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you.
That was your brother.
-That’s Itamar. Yeah, I’m his wife.
You look great with your hair.
What, this? It’s super easy, want me to show you?
Thanks, you’re so sweet.
It’s unbelievable, right?
-Gorgeous.
Shabbat Shalom, Itamar.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Did you come alone?
-No, Michal’s in the living room, she says hi.
Oh, then send her back.
And where are your cute kids?
-Scattered around.
Speaking of kids, Mom, we
need help on Tuesday night.
What’s going on with you all,
is there no babysitter in the world?
She’s not available, the babysitter,
I think it’s exam season,
and we have to go to Michal’s graduation
and we have no arrangement for the kids.
And Smadar?
That’s the day the kids are with me
and she won’t hear of an alternative.
-No.
Mom.
Wow, it’s so simple! It’s amazing.
I told you, you look great.
-Sweetie.
Hey, there you are.
-Hey, Shabbat Shalom.
I need to talk to you.
-Just a sec.
In private.
Shai, come here.
-Sure.
Hey.
-What's going on here?
Amazing, right?
Ravit, meet: Shai, my brother.
-Wow, no way, this is unbelievable.
Did you see the resemblance too?
-What do you mean, did I see?
You look just like my brother-in-law, like two peas in a pod.
He might be a bit taller
and has brown eyes,
but seriously, it's spot on.
-Same voice.
Wow, I'm dying.
Did Itamar see this?
-Not yet.
Where is he?
-Tell him to come.
Little rascal.
But why, Mom, why?
Itamar, when I was a young mom
no one helped me.
But what can we do if times have changed?
Nowadays, parents help their kids.
My dear, if I help you
and babysit for you,
your siblings will line up here.
-I don't get you, Mom, really,
they're your grandkids.
Itamar, you know I love
my grandkids and I have no problem with them,
but if I agree this time,
Shai will come with his kids
and ask me to babysit for them too.
And let's keep this between us, his kids are a bit tough,
not like your angels that I adore
and I'm ready to do anything for them.
You know what I'll do, Mom,
I won't tell them you babysat for us.
Itamar, you know I don't like
doing favors.
Come on, but Mom.
Itamar, the door is closed.
What?
-No, I can't deal with this.
You're right, it's really not fair of Adam.
What, why? What did Adam do?
No, I wanted to talk to you about Riki.
Oh, okay.
Please.
I need you to teach me how
you raised Shai to stand up to his mom
and ask for things and actually get them.
You think I raised him?
He's scared of her
more than he's scared of the tax office.
Just now, in the car, we had an argument about it
because we need a babysitter
for Monday and she's not willing to help.
No way, what a coincidence.
We need one for Tuesday too,
and I sent Itamar to talk to her, maybe she'll agree.
The chances are zero,
he went, he begged her,
she completely shut him down.
Well, then we're in the same boat.
With Captain Riki Rosen.
So what can we do?
-Now, nothing,
we should have drowned her with the albatross.
Now I've lost you.
But forget it, what did Adam do wrong?
No, you know,
still coming every week
with a different girl, it's not...
In the meantime.
Right.
Babe, we don't have a plan for Tuesday.
What?
-Sorry, I turned into a nerd.
His mom already beat me in the first half.
I don't know what you're talking about.
You sent me to talk to my mom.
And you're right, she’s not willing to watch the kids.
She said it’s because of Shai’s childhood
but he should stay in Yavivo.
I’m Ravit, coming in hot.
-What?
Who?
I’m Ravit, Adam’s friend.
-What’s going on here?
Well, she said no?
-Yeah, but...
No, yeah, I see the resemblance.
-Really?
Did you talk to her?
-I was busy with this event.
Wait, wait, let me try talking to her.
Later, tell me what happened here.
No, this is unbelievable.
It’s like that game.
-Find the differences.
What, there’s no difference, it’s exactly the same.
Look, look, you found one, the dot.
Oh, right, she has a dot, that’s big.
No, you’re not normal.
-Bro, I thought it would be good
But not that much.
What?
Rivka, could you make a real effort
to help the kids a bit?
Maybe we can watch the grandkids, maybe...
First of all, don’t speak in plural,
just do it, help, we’ll watch,
you know very well you can’t
neither help nor watch,
not even your own balls’ order.
Rivka, these are our grandkids.
Pinchas, you know I love our grandkids,
but if I agree to babysit them this time,
they’ll come back in a week asking
and another week and another week.
But it’s not about another week
and another week,
it’s about Monday, Tuesday.
-Pinchas, Pinchas,
And what will happen when we’re out of energy?
What will happen in a few weeks
when we can’t anymore? What then?
Adam will come with his kids and say,
why aren’t you babysitting me?
What will happen then? Pinchas, I’m thinking about our future
and theirs.
They need to learn to manage on their own.
-Okay, okay.
Wait, what are you talking about?
-About the resemblance.
Yeah, but which one?
Between Shai and Itamar regarding their mom.
What a coincidence, I was talking
about the resemblance between Shai and Gihan.
Oh, so we’re not even talking about the same thing?
No, what a coincidence.
-No, what a coincidence.
No, I’m dying.
-No, I’m dying.
No, this is a YouTube moment.
No, my sister-in-law, I’m one step ahead of you.
If I insist a bit more, will it help?
It won’t help, right?
Pinchas.
-Sorry, I was just trying to insist.
Since when did you become stubborn?
Go call everyone to eat,
I just want to finish this and run away.
-Okay.
Friends are requested in the dining room.
-In a bit, we’re not hungry.
Speak for yourself, I’m hungry.
-What’s new?
Tell me, babe, are you by any chance vegetarian?
-Yeah. Wow, how did you know?
Sometimes I see into people.
The outside she sometimes misses.
No, it kills me how similar you all are.
Ravitush, babe,
if there’s one small thing I’ve learned in my life,
it’s that no one likes
being told they look like someone else.
No one.
Well, I’m sorry to interrupt
this Boscilla moment here.
So, Pinchas, anything new?
-Not really, just the usual.
Pinchas, come on, are you calling them?
I’ll answer the phone.
Hello.
Yes, Fabiela, yes.
What are you saying?
So it must be really tough.
What, for four days? In two weeks?
No, no, I don’t think we...
It’s already time, goodbye.
You know what, it’s fine, we’ll take it,
No point in wasting it.
Thanks, Fab', here, your requests are already here.
So bye, bye, Fanny.
Is everyone here?
-Yeah, everyone came.
I see someone’s here twice.
What’s this?
-That’s Ravit.
This is my first time here.
Little rascal.
-I know you’ll love it.
Wow.
You look gorgeous!
Michal, you could learn from her.
-Learn what?
Okay, quiet, I have wonderful news.
Silvan had a tough surgery, it’s nonsense,
I’m inviting all of you
in two weeks for four days
to a suite at the "Fun Hotel,"
there are four big rooms
facing one pool and it’s all ours.
So no "I can’t," clear your schedules,
everyone’s coming, no exceptions.
Because if we don’t all come
then Fanny gives this vacation to Mel' Tavalet.
Ballet.
So is that okay?
Of course.
-Cool.
Why not?
Riki, it’s not that simple,
I need a second to make a call
to check if it’s okay, okay?
Ornit, call me, I’m waiting for you here.
Okay, I’m stepping out to the balcony for a sec.
Shai, come with me for a minute.
Why interrupt him in the middle of eating?
Do we need to pause for one phone call?
Mom, I’ll be right back.
Well, if we’re doing it, then let’s do it, Itamar, come with me.
I’m waiting for you here.
At least you’re not alone.
-And not in the dark.
Very funny.
Not like your friend, but it’s funny.
What’s funny?
So what’s Dad doing besides wandering around the country?
What?
-How cute.
Right?
Thanks.
What was so urgent that you had to
pull me out in the middle of eating?
Well, don’t confuse things, you haven’t even started eating.
Listen, this time I’m not ready.
Why? It’s a free vacation, it doesn’t cost a dime.
It’ll be nice to spend the weekend together,
it’s also great for family bonding, what’s wrong with that?
What’s wrong is that my whole body is already shaking.
Okay, sit down, you’re exaggerating a bit.
-Am I exaggerating or is your mom exaggerating?
Like every word she says
everyone has to stand at attention.
Why the silence?
-Why? Because you and your trained brothers...
Don’t say a word after
she says the last word.
Shai, I’m done with this, it’s either me or her.
Shani, don’t put me in an awkward position.
You’ll find a solution, Shai, just say
the dates don’t work for you,
Say it doesn’t fit with your study buddy.
-Shani, but...
You know what? Come on, I’ll make it easier for you,
If your mom helps you with ballet on Monday,
we’ll go with them to the "Fun Hotel."
You’re mixing things that don’t go together.
What’s the connection between ballet and the Fun Hotel?
Shai, you need to be strong now.
Stand up to her and don’t break.
Listen to me, find the connection,
I have no idea how,
if there’s ballet on Monday, there’s the Fun Hotel and vice versa.
I have no idea how. Make something up.
Fine, we’re not going to that Rikitours,
we’re not jumping for every one of her whims.
Shai, you don’t want to get into trouble with her,
my mom will never forgive you for this.
You’re on my mom’s blacklist
in the Knesset, that’s your end.
Sorry, it’s not just me, we’re in this together,
if I’m not going, then you’re not going either.
Sure, yeah, but let’s not make a big deal out of it.
It’s not a big deal, you just need to put
the Fun Hotel and the babysitter for Tuesday on the table.
There’s a babysitter, there’s the Fun Hotel, clear?
-Clear.
Listen, I can’t come
to that Fun Hotel, I have something.
Well, you told me you wanted
to get to know me better,
so here’s your chance
to get to know me and the whole family.
You guys have the overbearing mom syndrome,
if you don’t do what she wants, there’s terror.
What are you talking about?
So let’s see you tell her no to that Fun Hotel.
Come on, stand your ground, show me
you’re not just obeying her automatically.
Fine, you’ll see.
-Fine.
Now, now, come on, come on.
Mom,
look!
We’re not sure we can go to the Fun Hotel.
-Why?
I mean we can’t give you a positive answer yet.
Why?
-Because there’s the...
Babysitter on Monday
and only then we’ll give you an answer.
I get it, you’re giving your mom an ultimatum.
-What? No way.
What ultimatum? What are you talking about?
There’s just a connection between the two things.
Can you please explain to me what the connection is
between the Fun Hotel and the babysitter?
There is a connection.
An indirect one.
-I understand.
Riki.
-Nice.
I’m glad it’s nice here because mom...
Check this out,
we can’t come because of the babysitter
and because Michal has a graduation ceremony.
But that’s on a completely different date.
Yeah, but...
-What are you even talking to me about?
No, the...
Honey, I can’t do this.
-I’m not feeling well.
Wait, can someone explain to me
what all this nonsense is?
-Adam.
No way.
We’re not coming, Ravit has a show,
lingerie.
לא נכון.
אנחנו לא נגיע, לרווית יש תצוגה,
הלבשה תחתונה.
What, why are you involving me?
Because it’s not me, you think?
Mich... Ravit doesn’t want to come.
-I don’t care about anything,
Whoever doesn’t show up, raise your hand now.
The question wasn’t phrased accurately.
Rebellion?
Really, it’s not a rebellion, it’s just...
Those are your grandkids, right?
-I just want what’s best for them.
My cuties, what do you prefer, a ballet show
or a vacation by the pool in Eilat?
Girls, this isn’t up for choice.
But I just want you to know you can have both,
it’s just Grandma doesn’t want...
I’m willing to do the babysitting.
-And Avchan needs you on Tuesday.
Please, I told you. Your turn.
What about you, don’t you have any demands?
-Adam, I want to go.
With us to Fun Hotel?
No, now, home.
Of course.
Hello.
Yes, Fabaila.
So it’s just a short surgery in the end,
so he needs the hotel for recovery.
What a question, as long as he’s healthy.
Yes.
At "Fab," that’s perfectly fine.
At "Bi," may he be healthy.
In the end, he needs the hotel for recovery.
And the babysitter?
-Not feeling so well.
Because we lost the hotel.
Is there a connection?
-There is a connection.
Indirect.
From all this mess that in the end
there’s no Fun Hotel and no babysitter.
So I thought, maybe you’ll take the older one to ballet
and I’ll stay home with the little one?
-There’s a babysitter.
Where from?
-I knew your mom wouldn’t end up doing it.
You arranged it with Meirav.
Yes
Meirav
yes.
How much is she charging for that?
-300.
For everything.
-Per hour.
And after midnight it’s double the rate.
I told you it would cost you a lot of money.
Of course, a lot of money.
But for that price, even my mom
would agree to do it.
No, let your mom run away,
just run away.
What are we doing about the day off?
-There’s no day off,
no day off, no.
-No.
I won’t tell them you babysat him.
Itamar, you know I don’t like
those silly tricks.
What are we doing about the day off?
Why are you bringing this up again? Wait.
Are you giving your mom an ultimatum?
What ultimatum? What are you talking about?
It was in the rehearsal, it was amazing.
He loved it a lot.
I know, me too.
An ultimatum is huge.
I wanted to talk to you about Riki.
Yes.
No, sorry. Please.
What did I want to tell you about Riki?
You're giving your mom an ultimatum?
-No way.
Sorry.