Honey, maybe we should stop,
grab some bourekas, drinks, something?
No, Dad said we don’t need to.
-Not appropriate.
Not appropriate at all.
-No, Grandma Chava passed away.
So there won't be anything inappropriate anymore, that's what I meant.
Where do you go after you die?
Probably
After you die, you go to heaven.
Or, in Grandma Chava's case, hell.
-Shai.
I don’t want to go to hell.
You're not going to hell, honey,
we're going to Grandma Riki,
which is a branch of hell, not the real place.
But the kids' channel is the real place,
so Tal Musari is in hell?
If there is a God, then yes.
Look at me, look at me and...
Come on, Riki, did you manage to sleep a bit?
-Where...
I didn’t close my eyes, Pinchas snored like a horse.
Pinchas, you need to take care of this.
-Okay.
I told him to take care of it,
but it’s like talking to a wall.
Okay.
Pinchas, you really need to handle this.
-Maybe he doesn’t hear well either.
I hear, I hear.
I told him to go check his hearing,
but it’s like talking to the chandelier.
-Okay, I’ll go, I’ll go.
He’ll go when I grow hair here.
Oh, you know I had hair here.
I removed it with laser.
It’s unbelievable what you can remove today
with laser.
Really?
-Hey there.
What happened?
-Adam.
I was scared it was a stranger,
I don’t have the energy to host anymore,
I hope people will have mercy
and not come to comfort us after Shabbat.
You’re right, a little consideration.
Do you want a cup of coffee?
Thanks.
-Great.
Adam, come to the kitchen,
make a cup of coffee for Mom and Aunt Shlomit.
Pinchas, thanks, that’s very kind of you.
-No problem.
Adam, did you leave the door open?
-Oh, right.
Ben, let it be over already.
-Shlomit, you put on too much makeup,
it’s not respectful, it’s still a mourning period.
You need to decide, it’s either heavy makeup
or stubble from four in the afternoon.
You’ll still remove it with wax.
Ben, at least you’ll meet Mom there.
That’s not nice. It’s funny, but it’s not nice.
Oh, how sad.
What coffee does Aunt Shlomit drink?
-Forget the coffee for now.
What do you mean "forget the coffee,"
you said we’re making coffee, right?
I want coffee too, do you want coffee?
Can’t you see I’m in distress?
I just got here, I didn’t have time.
-Adam, don’t annoy me, okay?
I’m making you decaf.
-Forget the coffee.
Don’t you understand my life is over?
In what sense?
In the sense that from the moment your uncle became an aunt
he also became more of a mom than Mom.
Dad, I still haven’t had coffee,
I need a bit more.
He enjoys making my life miserable.
Just like Mom.
-Times two.
I get it.
-She’s compensating for the years she was a man
and he’s killing me.
I understand.
I get it, it’s been a tough week for you.
So you know what I'm gonna do for you?
-What?
Hot chocolate.
What time is it?
Maybe they really won’t come.
I can’t talk anymore, I need some peace.
All the time, "Why did Mom die?" She died,
she was old and she died,
cause of death: life. What do people expect to hear?
That it was a skydiving accident.
-Riki
Sorry.
I was so scared.
-Sorry, sorry.
You almost gave me a heart attack.
-Sorry.
Welcome.
-Hello, may you know no more sorrow, Riki.
Silvan-
My condolences.
-Rachel. And...
-I’m sorry.
-And you brought your big little one with you.
Meirav.
-Meirav, yes, Meirav,
Meirav, the chances I won’t forget anymore.
Have a good week.
-Pinchas, Pinchas.
I’m sorry for your loss.
-Silvan, Rachel, how lovely,
Come closer, what a dish!
K'
Y'
Ra
Roli' Abu
What’s in the pot? Rachel, you didn’t have to.
You should have.
Maybe I’ll go put the pot in the kitchen?
-Yeah, go ahead, go ahead.
Why "go ahead, go ahead"? We cleaned this week,
she’s got a pot in her hand.
Come in, come in.
-Come on,
Sit down, sit down.
-Sit down.
Excuse me, are you sitting on armchairs?
-Yeah, what should we sit on?
We do things differently here, we sit on the floor.
Pinchas.
-Excuse me.
These are Shai's parents and this is...
I’m Shlomit, nice to meet you, Rebecca's sister.
Nice to meet you, nice to meet you,
May you know no sorrow, Shlomit.
-Thank you.
Tell me, do you smoke?
-Why, do you have something?
Rachel, Rachel,
What’s in the pot you brought?
Something small I brought for you to eat, curry.
Thanks, I’ve never had that before.
What’s curry?
-Meatballs in sauce.
Meatballs?
Do you know what it’s called or
-How?
Meatballs in sauce.
That’s what I made.
May you know no more sorrow, Adam.
Thanks.
-Can I put the pot here?
What did you bring?
It’s meatballs in sauce.
Here.
Sounds delicious, I’ve been living on bourekas for a week.
Oh, a man like you needs meat.
-I love meat.
There’s meat, and a lot of it.
In the pot, I mean.
-Of course.
I have insides.
-Of course you do.
This is a new approach I’m trying, what do you think?
May you know no more sorrow? No.
We usually bring meat dishes during shiva.
Riki, should we tell them?
Shlomo, you’re killing me! Me too.
Tell me, Shlomit, how come...
We’ve never met?
-My husband and I live in Vienna.
And where's your husband?
-He was here,
He was at the funeral, just on Friday
he had to go back.
Business, you know.
-Yeah, sure, I know, yeah.
Are you here alone with them?
-Yeah.
Bless you.
May you know no more sorrow.
-May you know no more sorrow.
I guess we’re still in shock, but thank you.
I’m going to get you some chairs.
What did she die from?
Ski accident.
-Riding.
She died in her sleep.
Holy.
-Thank you.
I think she meant your mom.
Oh, she wasn’t holy.
I have no idea who these people are.
That’s how it is during shiva, people come by.
What are you girls doing?
My sweethearts, no running or shouting today, okay?
Grandma is very sad.
So go to the balcony and I’ll call you.
Quietly.
Honey.
-I’m exhausted.
Honey, we’ll be moving in twenty minutes max.
Hello.
-Hey.
Hi.
-How’s it going?
Your family is here.
-Hey.
What’s this, Mom, I didn’t know you were coming today.
We didn’t want to burden them at the start of shiva.
Oh, yeah, you’re right,
at the beginning of shiva there’s still some sadness.
Is Meirav here too?
-In the kitchen.
Hi, Shlomit.
-Hi, sweetheart.
Honey, show me where the bathroom is.
-Sure, come on.
What... how’s it going, Silvan?
-Good, everything’s fine.
Just sitting and chatting with Shlomit, so nice,
I just met her.
-How lovely.
What’s this, why didn’t you tell me you were coming?
What’s this, everyone’s coming.
-Everyone?
They’re bringing Alin, Orna, and Moshe.
Why?
-They need to...
Because they feel bad they didn’t make it to the funeral.
Tell me, why didn’t Shai say anything?
-Mom, come on,
it’s some grandma he didn’t get along with, right?
Still, it’s weird.
Tell me, who’s that woman Dad is talking to?
Aunt Shlomo.
-Explain.
That’s...
That’s Riki’s brother who recently decided to become her sister.
You’re telling me that...
-Yeah, totally.
Totally totally?
-I don’t know, maybe.
Mom, enough, quiet.
Is that Riki’s brother?
-Yeah.
Crazy, right?
Mom.
Mom, get a grip.
Don’t tell Dad, it’s not nice.
-No, it’s not nice.
Mom, it’s shiva.
-Yeah.
Herzl's dead.
Yeah, Riki
-Yeah, Itamar.
Itamar.
-Itamar.
Hey.
-Where are you?
Hi.
-Hey.
Hi, wow.
Who are those people that came before us?
-Distant relatives.
What?
Distant relatives, relatives from hell.
Hey, what's up?
-Hey.
Michal, do you remember my mom?
Hi, how are you?
What's up?
-All good.
Grandma Chava passed away, you know, Chaim.
Sit down, babe, come here for a sec.
May you know no more sorrow.
-Right, yeah.
So I don’t get why all this sadness is here.
Excuse me for a sec. Babe, come with me, please.
You know, Shlomit,
in our mourning period
we don’t even send regards.
What, he hasn’t found out yet?
-He doesn’t know anything.
Tell me, why didn’t you tell me they were coming?
I would’ve warned my parents.
-No, I didn’t know they were coming either.
So, when are they leaving?
-What do you mean leaving?
They’re going.
No, first there’s a prayer.
-What prayer?
A prayer, I don’t think my dad will go
before ten people show up.
What ten?
-For the minyan.
What minyan?
-Tell me, what’s wrong with you? What, are you a goy?
I’ve been here twice this week, babe.
-Babe, brush your teeth and be quiet.
Lips.
What lips?
-No..
Okay, we were here, can we go now?
No, absolutely not, you’re staying here like a good kid from Givatayim.
Jerusalem.
What’s up with you today?
-I don’t like death, okay?
I want to go home.
All this talk about death is killing me.
-No, I’m dying.
May you know no more sorrow.
-So nice you came.
Tbhm.
-Tbhmivan.
Tbhmivan.
This is Moshe.
-Right.
You remember, right?
This is Orna, she’s Shai’s sister,
and Mavi and Alon, Shabi’s brother, you remember.
-Yeah.
Tbhmivan.
They grew up well with you, no evil eye.
Ben Porat Yosef.
-Ben Porat Yosef.
Come on, let’s put this in the kitchen.
Pinchas, come here for a sec, just a moment.
Itamar.
May you know no more sorrow.
-Sure, sure.
Ah, Moshe, what’s up?
What? Dying, huh?
Yeah, soon at your place...
Sorry, I apologize, a bit confused, dazed
and mostly don’t want to be here.
You’re telling me.
Shlomit, I’d like you to meet my family.
Pinchas.
-What?
What are they doing here?
-Who knows?
The whole clan is here.
-They came to offer condolences.
What's the point? You can't even mourn.
Riki, they'll be here for... 20 minutes and then they'll leave.
I'm telling you, Pinchas,
His mom is watching us from above! She's cracking up.
I'm telling you, it's hilarious.
Say,
Riki's sister.
-Yeah, she's transgender.
You don't need to shout that,
his makeup is loud enough.
Can we go now?
-No.
And now?
-Itamar's giving a eulogy,
Respect your grandma's memory.
I don't want to, okay? I don't want to.
I was at the funeral, I was here for the shiva for a few days,
It's Saturday night now, I just want to sit
at home quietly and cry, for crying out loud.
I want to remember my grandma in peace
in front of my TV.
It's my right as an Israeli man to sit at home
on my couch and fart in peace.
When was the last time you farted in peace?
Just now.
-No way, I'm dying.
Look, look, how nice.
Now I need another one.
Are you waiting for someone?
-Yeah.
For which guy?
There are nine guys here, I need ten.
You don't think twice?
You're a real man.
Ugh, but we never go anywhere.
Because I'm telling you the kids are too grown up now
and they don't care about this nonsense.
I don't care about the kids, I was talking about me,
do you know how long it's been since I went to the safari?
Go to the living room, there's a safari there.
We're going back to the living room and you can entertain yourself,
be nice.
Next Saturday we're going to the safari.
Wow, I haven't been to the safari in weeks.
Leave me out of the safari, just let me get home.
We can pass by there on the way home.
I read there was a giraffe birth there,
it would be interesting to see a baby giraffe.
I've always been curious to see it at eye level.
Moshe, can you chill with the safari?
There's no safari, the safari is closed,
the animals are on strike.
-What a shame.
Focus on how we can get out of here the fastest.
What, by running? Won't that look like something happened?
Moshe, don't you get that we’re not leaving here
until my dad organizes a minyan?
-Okay, okay.
I wonder how much they pay for property tax here.
Guys, have you eaten anything?
Do you want to eat something?
The food you brought is really tasty, honestly.
Riki, do you want me to make you a plate?
-No, Rachel, I'd rather be alone
and eat quietly after everyone leaves.
Well, that could take hours.
-What hours? No way it’ll take hours!
We need to pray, right?
Mama, what did you do to me?
-Riki, it'll be fine.
The potato salad is delicious, something else.
Come on, Manny, when are we going home?
I'm tired of playing waitress,
the kids are probably driving Mom crazy too.
We can't leave until my dad
organizes a minyan and prays.
What's the point of that?
-Are you crazy?
What do you mean, what's the point?
If they don't say Kaddish,
the soul of the deceased won't reach heaven, right?
Sure, there's no chance she'll get there
with all the saints in the world.
Come on, that's not nice.
What, don't you have any good memories of her?
I don't know?
I remember we used to go to Grandma Chava's on Shabbat,
and she had this really nice carpet
that you couldn't step on
and couch covers you couldn't sit on
in front of a TV that you couldn't turn on.
That's how we were! Going to Grandma Chava's on Shabbat,
Shabbat at Grandma Savia's.
I used to spend Shabbat at Grandma Yafa's,
Shabbat at Grandma Buba's.
We spent Shabbat at Mazlika's and Shabbat at Shoshana's.
I loved Grandpa Menachem.
And then, one day, we stopped visiting the parents.
It's so sad,
suddenly one day they come to you for Friday night.
Just like we stopped going to Grandma Mazal.
I can't believe this is happening to me.
-What?
That I'm at Grandma Chava's shiva,
I really miss her.
Hey, until Kaddish is said
can we jump to the safari in the meantime?
It's 20 minutes from here.
What safari are you talking about?
-Orna, drop it.
Moshe.
-What?
Did you forget?
The safari is closed, the animals are on strike.
Sit.
Come here for a sec.
Sit down, my sweet,
I'm so glad your parents came
!your whole family, really a lovely bunch of people,
and I'm so grateful they came to us.
-But?
But I need your help.
What do I need to do to get them to leave?
I'm tired, sit down.
-No, no, you're right, you're right, Riki,
really, I understand you
and I also really want to help you,
but my dad just wants to pray and needs a minyan.
Minyan? How many is a minyan today?
A minyan.
-Yeah, but you know, I didn't study in yeshiva
!and my mom passed away this week, so how many is that, sweetie?
Ten, that's ten men.
How many do we have here?
-Nine.
Can't we round that up?
No.
Sali, we can't skip on...
-No, we can't skip that.
Someone needs to say Kaddish for their mom, who passed away,
and if you're bored, you can go sit
next to Riki's sister, Shlomit,
a really, really nice woman, very nice.
Sali.
-What?
There's something you don't know.
Not now, not now, I'm asking you,
not now.
Just so you know, your family is not normal.
What do you want? My mom's mom passed away.
Do you think I'm basing my stuff on the shiva?
I'm talking to you about weeks of observations.
Okay, sit down, babe, but good for you,
your family isn't exactly normal either.
Why is your dad insisting on praying now?
What do you want, honey? It's fine with him.
-But it's not fine with us,
So maybe he'll respect his traditions?
-So what do you want,
him to make schnitzel and mashed potatoes?
Because those are the only things that are sacred to you.
Right, schnitzel is sacred.
-Okay.
Your meziluf isn't sacred?
-Yeah, the meziluf is,
but there are other things.
What, honey, what's going to happen?
There's nothing to do, that's family for you,
a collection of people with minor
or major mental issues.
And meziluf, schnitzel, and love, that's it.
Family, that's what we've got.
Please, all the men in the room, raise your hands.
Come on, I want to count.
There are only nine, Mom.
So we're just missing one.
Go get a neighbor, Itamar.
-I tried, I knocked on all the doors,
no one answered me.
The Zigelmbims... I saw their light on.
When I knocked, they turned it off.
I'll deal with them at the next homeowners' meeting.
Okay, Shai, please go to the balcony, find
me a guy and bring him up.
Maybe I should go down and try to hunt for guys.
Maybe that's not a good idea.
I can talk to someone from my friends
on Facebook, maybe someone nearby.
Honey, you know
they're not really your friends, right?
Why not? I've actually met quite a few
of my Facebook friends
in person.
Shai, sweetheart, do me a favor,
there's a Bukharian synagogue downstairs,
you know where it is?
Bring me a Bukharian, a nice one.
-What?
No, no, no, no need,
not Bukharian, not Persian,
not Austro-Hungarian.
Shlomit, come here for a second.
Sali, can I talk to you now?
-Yeah, about what?
You miscounted, there are ten.
I miscounted? What, can't I see well?
-No.
You'll do it, for me.
He what?
Shlomo.
-Shlomo?
It happened in the last two years.
-Why didn't you tell me?
Because we couldn't disconnect you from him.
Here’s Shlomo, there's a minyan.
Shlomo?
-He has everything he needs.
Silvan, can we say Kaddish already, for heaven's sake?
-Yeah, sure.
Thank God.
We need to say Havdalah first.
I hope they left enough room in my mom's
grave
so she can turn over easily.
That's it.
Yeah.
We're going on vacation.
-Break.
Next week there will be no schnitzels, no meziluf.
Yeah, no Shleikler, no Shleimler.
Big joy.
-Weird.
Okay, put on a CD, play something.
"Who loves Shabbat
Mom! Dad
Who loves Shabbat
Grandma! Grandpa
I love Shabbat.
Me, you! You!
Almost the whole world.
So why not every Shabbat?
Why not every Shabbat?
Every Shabbat.
How nice, you're making sounds, babe.
-Thanks.
Tamari...
-Babe.
Itamar.
-Hey there.
Hey, come here.
-What?
Orna and Alin! Moshe and...
Manny.
-Everyone?
I forgot the whole family.
What, maybe we should stop somewhere
and grab some bourekas, drinks, something?
What prayer?
-I don't think my dad...
I don't like death, I don't like death.
Sweetie.
Enough, enough, I'm stopping...
Moshe...
Shai, go down to MDA,
to find me a guy, bring him up.
Why MDA?