Hey, when are we getting there, Dad?
In a week.
-What’s that? Why are you snapping at the kid?
She started it.
-Started what?
She just asked when we’re getting there.
Yeah, but why did she say "Hey, really"?
Because she got her mom's genes too.
-Oh, so talk to her nicely.
She might also have your dad's genes
for getting offended.
Okay, you’re right, honey, we really created a new breed.
-Yeah.
Are you guys joking with me?
-No, honey, of course not, God forbid.
No, honey, what did you want to know, sweetie?
Where are we going?
-We’re going...
Wait, where are we really today?
What, where did we eat last Friday?
I suddenly don’t remember.
Everything’s turned into one big mix
of Shabbat hugs and kisses.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Look at me, look at me and...
Where are we going?
If you had the option to choose,
where would you want to go?
Tell me, what are you doing?
-Just a question.
What question? It’s like asking the kid
who do you love more, Mom or Dad.
What are you talking about?
-There’s no choice here, honey,
my parents work really hard
on Friday night so you can eat on Shabbat.
I’m not the only one eating.
-Okay,
but you probably don’t understand how hard it is
to host everyone.
I understand very well, you’d be surprised,
but even in my family, it’s a hassle.
I’m really surprised.
-Sit down...
Honey, maybe you don’t know,
but for us, the preparations for Friday
start already on Tuesday.
Is everything okay?
-Yeah, why?
I don’t know, you look a bit stressed.
I was just thinking about what I need to cook for Friday,
what I need to buy.
Suddenly I find myself
once again with all the same things
again and again and again,
enough, I’m tired of it, I don’t want to.
It really is tiring.
-What’s tiring?
What, you don’t like it?
-I like it, what, no...
Did I say I don’t like it? What’s not good?
I like it, I like it a lot.
You just said you’re tired of it, and so am I...
I mean, if you’re tired of it...
Hey, do you understand?
-Of course I understand.
Okay, then.
No, I’m not making anything, that’s it.
-Great, for once,
for once don’t make anything, thank you, that’s all.
I’ll make a bowl of macaroni and that’s it.
Don’t bother, please, let’s just order from a restaurant for once.
What restaurant? Why do we need a restaurant?
What, all that macaroni takes 20 minutes,
including boiling the water and the sauce.
What’s that, macaroni isn’t food? It’s not good?
Okay, it’s food, it’s good, it’s food,
I’m backing you up on this, okay?
And that’s it.
Really, that's it.
-And that's it.
Tell me, is the macaroni sauce
with meat or without?
What, I already made Bolognese, come on.
So on Thursday, we need to defrost the ground meat.
And that's it, that's it.
Wait, Sali, wait, wait,
If I'm already defrosting
the ground meat on Thursday,
then I can use some of it
to make Manny's meatballs,
so you won't cry.
What’s the deal? It’s the same prep time, that’s it.
-Fine.
You know what?
The girls don’t even have to mix
the meatballs with the rice.
What are you talking about? Rice is unrelated.
I have to make rice
because that’s the only thing they eat.
I always make rice.
And Moshe can whine until tomorrow morning
that he doesn’t have a pakala, tough luck.
Orna.
-What now, Orna?
No, she’ll start with the "Why does Manny get meatballs |
and Moshe doesn’t get a pakala?"
I don’t have the energy for this headache,
I’ll make the pakala.
Fine, that’s it.
-That’s it, we need to buy beans.
Okay.
There’s one more thing, but it’s not about food,
it’s a medical issue.
Alin, she’s anemic, and the doctors recommend
that an anemic woman eat iron,
so a little peas will do the trick.
You can tell you’re a guy, you don’t understand anything.
-Fine.
He has a lot of work.
What about the eggplants?
-Eggplants, of course, eggplants.
I really, really love your eggplants.
Eggplants, that’s it.
-That’s it.
And again, I’m doing the same things.
-Right.
And you think it’s easier at my parents’?
-Of course.
You’re so wrong.
It might not start on Tuesday
because of the number of guests,
but the hysteria is no less.
Pinchas.
-Huh?
How many people are coming over for dinner?
As usual.
-What kind of answer is "as usual"?
Do you want me to answer you "as usual"
when you ask me where your underwear is?
Sorry, Riki, I just woke up.
Well, we know more or less who’s coming, right?
More or less is the least accurate there is.
I don’t want to just throw away food,
I’m making my dish with the apples
and I want to put in exactly, not less, not more.
Why the silence?
-I’m counting in my head.
Not sure I want you counting in your head
when I send you to the store to buy seven things
and you forget one,
save your head for the pillow.
Okay, what do you want me to do?
I want you to call Adam
and ask him if he’s coming alone
or with his date.
I don’t want to bother him over something silly.
Just add one more apple
!If she comes, then she’ll have it.
And if she doesn’t come? What, am I going to throw away food?
Isn’t that a shame, Pinchas? It costs money,
I don’t remember the last time we got
a call from Gabriela from the lottery.
Ariella.
-What, do you know her?
No.
Then call her.
That way he’ll see we’re thinking of him.
You know what, if she doesn't eat
then I'll eat, okay?
Why, are you a garbage can?
Don't you have enough calories and cholesterol
in the pantry?
Go call him.
-Okay.
Hello, hello.
Dad, can you talk to him later?
Oh, you're the...
Yeah.
Son.
-What’s up?
He's busy.
Did he answer you?
-Yeah, but he's busy.
What do you mean he's busy?
It's a simple question, yes or no,
No need for a seminar for that.
I know, Riki, I'll call him
in 15 minutes, okay?
And what am I supposed to do? Wait a quarter of an hour?
Why don't I have a life of my own? I'm bored?
Riki, he's busy, he's in the middle of something, come on.
Call him now while he’s still answering,
in a quarter of an hour he’ll be swamped.
Okay, okay, just don’t get mad.
For real.
What, Dad, is it urgent?
-Adam, just answer me yes or no.
Yes, Dad, I'm still busy, bye.
-Come on, Adam...
He didn't answer me, he's probably really busy,
let's respect his privacy.
Why doesn't he respect my time?
I think when we call him
he should answer us right away.
What if the kid suddenly has an accident
or some unexpected death?
In our family, there’s no unexpected death,
it’s expected all the time.
Death doesn’t bother us as long as we’re alive.
Fine, fine, belittle me,
yell at me, kill me,
I don’t understand what big deal you made
out of a simple little question,
is he coming alone or not.
What’s the big deal?
Fine, let me handle it myself.
I don’t understand why I have to
do everything alone in this house.
Riki.
-You wouldn’t last a minute without me.
I just hope I die first
so you can see you were right.
Fine, talk, talk to him, see he’s busy.
Hello.
-Adam, I don’t care if you’re busy or not,
I want you to answer me right away,
are you coming alone or with your latest diva?
So yeah, I’ll come with her, okay?
-Alright, mama's boy.
You know Mom loves you the most
in the world, right, Adam?
Yeah.
Alright, Mom, bye.
-Bye, sweetheart.
Come on, was that so hard?
When I talked to him, it was hard.
Sorry, my mom.
I think he’s worried about his mom.
That’s why he brings someone different every week.
Alright, let’s skip the prep stage
and focus on the shopping stage.
Of course, poor his dad.
Poor him? My dad’s the one who’s poor.
Because shopping for us usually
never ends.
Sali, I forgot some things,
I need you to go to the store.
Oh, not fun.
-It’s nothing, I made you a little list,
I need you to go quickly and come back fast.
How can I go and come back fast,
just the line at the checkout is over an hour.
No, no, you don’t have to wait an hour,
you can go to the express checkout for ten items.
Nine, ten, eleven.
What eleven?
-There are eleven items.
Come on, it’s nothing, so eleven.
What do you mean nothing? Why is it nothing?
I’ll stand there, and some know-it-all will come
and say: with all due respect, sir,
there are more than ten items,
just stand there, in the regular checkout.
I have to stand there later.
Spare me that, son, just take it.
Silvan.
-Rachel.
Alright, son, take one off, give up something.
Please, then take it off.
You can take off the black coffee, quietly.
No way, no way, I can’t do without coffee,
what do you want, me to fall asleep all weekend?
Fine, then if you’re ready, take off the eggs.
Okay, I can manage without eggs.
Alright, I’m off, son.
Wait, wait, Dad.
-What?
Are you going shopping?
-No, just for a few things.
Okay, but I really need you to buy me some acetone,
it looks like this.
Please, here, now it’s eleven items.
It’s just acetone.
Rachel.
-Okay, the ten-item checkout is gone.
Alright, come on, I’ll try to sneak into
the ten-item line, let’s go.
Cotton candy! Q-tips!
And Dad, I need the...
Got it?
-With the...
Wings, got it.
In the packaging of the...
-Of the Super Tavker, I got it already.
Dad!
Alright, Sali, maybe you should go through the checkout
of ten items twice,
it’ll save you time—
Anything else?
-Yeah, you can put back the eggs I took off.
Okay, I’ll put back the eggs.
Pinchas.
-What?
Come here, I’ve prepared a
precise shopping list,
I’m asking you to stick to it.
Please pay attention to the details, really well.
-Okay.
There’s something in the third column, you see?
-Yeah.
The number of grams for each item.
I don’t want you to buy the big packages,
we’re not a clan or a big family.
Okay, but Riki, it doesn’t matter how
many columns there are and how detailed the list is,
because every time I come back, I get yelled at.
Because you make decisions on your own
that I don’t agree with.
I don’t understand what the difference is
if I bring you a kilo of Persian rice
or a kilo of basmati rice,
what does it matter, for heaven's sake?
If you’re asking, I have nothing to add.
I’ll just add that it only reinforces what I said earlier.
Do you think I have time now to soak rice?
You’re not moving an inch from the list.
I’d rather not move an inch from home
and have you go to the store for me
than get yelled at later with eyes wide open.
Did I tell you?
Tell me, do you think I enjoy this,
yelling at you
and saying “I told you so” like you’re a little kid?
Riki, how about we go together?
It could strengthen our relationship.
Pinchas, it's not legal to do that in the supermarket.
But I have an idea,
if you go to the supermarket, I’ll owe you one.
Fine.
-Alright, my martyr,
darling.
I'm going to sleep now, and when you get back from the supermarket
we’ll strengthen our relationship here at home
and not among the frozen foods.
-Okay.
Sali, I need you to go back to the supermarket,
I forgot a few more things.
I forgot too,
I need you to get me wax for my legs
!tweezers !razors
!Bamba with halva, please.
Sali.
-What?
Put it in the cart.
Rice.
Put in. Sausage.
Forget it, let’s get to the cooking stage.
Here, my mom definitely works harder.
Maybe you should drop it?
My mom doesn’t work any less hard in the cooking stage
than your mom.
Dude, seriously, shh.
Sorry, what are you implying?
That my mom’s food is less invested?
Honey, I’m not implying, I’m saying
that our cooking is a whole story from scratch
and yours is a story from the freezer.
On one hand, I’m really happy
that you come and eat here during the week,
on the other hand, it makes me sad to see you so hungry.
It is what it is, Mom,
she doesn’t have it and she won’t get it, that’s the situation.
Itamar, maybe you should bring her to Mom,
so she can teach her to cook normal, homemade, fresh food.
I’m ready, are you ready?
No.
-Why?
Because I’m not leaving her alone with Mom.
Why, because they’ll eat each other?
Mom will eat her, Michal’s a vegetarian.
You need to eat meat, it has vitamins,
it’s called B12,
without it, a person becomes dumb.
You know, Mom, what vitamin I'm missing?
Be quiet, please.
Okay, and what about iron?
-Thanks for the food,
I’m off.
-Bye
Bye
Bye, Itamar.
-Bye
So, what, shall we start cooking?
-Yeah.
Go take the schnitzels out of the freezer,
the frozen vegetables,
the soup, the fish, and the rice.
-Right away.
And then take out the cans of peas and carrots,
the pickled cabbage and mushrooms.
-Okay.
Then take this,
this bag, mix it, make mashed potatoes.
-Yeah.
Half goes in the freezer.
You know, Riki,
I love when we cook together.
Tell me, Wednesday afternoon
and you’re already starting to prepare the pakala?
We have to start, right?
-Where’s the spinach?
Spinach too, right, spinach, and oil
and I don’t have any soup powder.
Sali.
-What?
I need you to go to the supermarket.
No, no, no, it's a busy hour.
Later, please.
No, it's nothing.
How many items?
-Three.
You can stand in the ten-item line.
At this hour, that line is busy too.
Come on.
-We need to suggest to them
To open a three-item line.
Okay, just go quietly,
so Mirav won't hear you're going shopping.
Otherwise, a thirty-item line won't be enough.
So go.
-Come on! Come on!
It's Wednesday and you're starting with the meatballs?
-Come on, how else will it be ready?
And you’re not short on breadcrumbs and parsley.
Because, Sali.
-What?
I need you to go to the supermarket.
What now?
-It's nothing.
What do you mean?
-Breadcrumbs and parsley.
And that's in the seven-item line.
-Yeah.
Look, if I go...
Mirav.
What is it, five in the morning! Are you already preparing the chicken?
-Of course.
Aren't you short on lemon?
Sali.
-No way.
It's nothing.
Tell me, maybe I should just stay at the supermarket
instead of going back and forth?
I'll set up a protest tent between the fish and the meat.
This is the last time.
But listen to me, if...
-Mirav.
Mirav?
What smells.
-Sali.
No way.
-I need you to go to the supermarket.
What now?
-I don't know,
you go ahead, I'll call you to let you know.
Oh, it's you.
-You'd better believe it.
What, are you awake now? Aren't you falling asleep?
I need to check that there’s enough water
in the dishes, otherwise it dries out.
Racheli, morning's coming, come sleep, please.
Now I remembered what’s missing.
What’s missing?
-Bay leaves.
It's nothing.
Racheli, four in the morning,
where am I supposed to get you leaves now?
There's that supermarket that's open 24/7.
Tomorrow, tomorrow morning I'll bring you leaves.
I'll bring you wood-
Four in the morning, only you and Yehudit Ravitz are awake.
Come sleep.
Sali.
-Enough, no, I'm not going,
I'm not going anywhere anymore.
-We're not going, we're not going.
I'm done, we're not going.
-Thank God.
Thank God.
Sali.
-What?
Quiet! Just a few more hours.
Tell me, did you make my eggplants?
I forgot the eggplants.
No, I'll make them now, I'll make them now.
Wait, I'm missing something.
Yeah, let me guess, it's nothing.
No, it's almost, it's nothing.
So I'm giving up, I don't want,
I don't want eggplants.
No, no.
-I don't want eggplants,
I hate, hate eggplants.
-No, no.
I hate it.
-No, no, I'm not giving up, Sali,
Can you go to the store and get me some garlic, please?
It's nothing, just stand in the garlic line.
I know, Meirav, yeah.
That's it, we're done cooking.
-Great.
Can we go to the bathroom?
-You could say yes.
Wait, what about the aprons?
-Oh, how did I forget the aprons?
Do you have the energy to cook the aprons now?
-Of course.
Great.
Take them out of the freezer.
Come on, and after cooking comes the next step,
the step where the guests arrive.
No, there are still a few hours until the estimated arrival.
Ah, so we call this step "Shitpuda."
That's it, Riki, are we done with all the cooking?
You could say the cooking has worn us out.
So until all the bandits arrive
we have some time to go to the sitting room,
to be together a bit.
-Great idea, Pinchas.
Awesome.
Can we bless the finished dishes?
-Yes.
Okay.
There's one more thing!
Levi.
A.
Yeah.
(Y)
Bar
for you
and
come
there.
I'm standing and
my son
I can only talk to you about it in the sitting room.
Really?
-Yeah.
Wow, I'm curious.
What do you say?
-Yeah.
Julia Rogers, come with me, please.
I'm coming, Richard Gere.
Please.
This is Meirav.
-You're not answering.
Vardi
Roy
come
No.
There, she gave up.
-Thank you very much.
Where were we?
Again Meirav.
-No, you're not answering, you're just not answering.
That's it.
She gave up again.
No.
No, we're not answering, not answering.
Okay.
What, is that Meirav?
No. Health clinic.
Health clinic at this hour?
-I don't know what that is?
Hello?
Yes.
Meirav, did you change your name
in my phone to health clinic?
What?
No, I'm not going to the store.
-Hello.
Yeah, sit down, yeah.
You're coming over tonight, yeah.
Come on.
This is for you.
-Hello.
Because, Moshe.
I didn't forget to buy the grape juice for the girls.
Meirav, what did you want from the store?
After the "Shitpuda" step comes the welcoming stage,
which is a stage we know.
-Actually, the hosting stage is the easier one
because everyone does and says exactly
the same things week after week.
Yeah, the welcoming stage is supposedly the easy part,
But you know,
that's where all the energies
positive or negative, converge.
It's like with plane crashes, most accidents happen
either during takeoff or landing.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom, Riki.
Listen, I have a joke.
What is it, the cream? Are you pregnant again?
No, I had a lafa with shawarma on the way.
Shabbat Shalom, babe.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Oh, you won't believe what a week I've had.
What's up, Dad, everything okay?
They found a fungus on my palm, it's terrible.
Hello.
What’s that? What are you getting dirty with all the time?
Shai. -Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Shabbat Shalom. You won't believe what I bought.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom, Riki.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom.
You’re pregnant? Don’t tell me you’re pregnant.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Didn’t we already say Shabbat Shalom?
-Are you sure?
Yeah, come on, I already cleaned you up.
Shabbat Shalom.
Yuck, you disgusting.
-Is it disgusting?
Have you tried my dad's mushrooms yet?
I learned a lot from your side.
-Really?
I learned a lot from your side too.
Now I’ll look at everything differently.
So, are we at the summary stage now?
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom, Adamka.
-Shabbat Shalom, Adami.
Last time I’m doing this.
Of course.
Did you see how Michal Shabi gained weight?
-Of course.
The scariest part is that we used to be like that too.
Whether you like it or not, you know, it runs in the genes.
So you’ll do what your mom does?
-Probably.
If my grandma was like that
and my great-grandma was like that,
then what’s stopping me from being like that?
So when do we get to the argument stage for a lighter sentence?
Yeah.
What’s that?
-What happened?
Great-grandma passed away.
-No.
Sali.
What?
What’s with the “that” twice?
But you’re not missing any mushrooms...
Wait, aren’t you missing breadcrumbs and parsley?
Breadcrumbs.
And not by the frozen stuff.
-Okay.
Okay.
This is the last time.
-Listen, if I...
If I...
If the supermarket visits, I already got it.
-Dad...
Listen, Al, I’ll just stay at the supermarket,
you know what...
This...