I don't get it, if you're not to blame...
-I'm not to blame, not at all.
So why did you give in to him?
-Because he threatened me and scared me, okay?
What did he say, that if you don't eat
a cop will come and take you away?
No, he told me that theoretically, if he wants,
he could even open a criminal case against me
for suspected involvement in terrorism.
And what did you tell him?
-What did I tell him? Come on, let's see you be a man,
open the case.
Great, you backed a cop into a corner,
what did you expect to get out of it?
Tears, a sea of tears
over two cakes
How much I cried...
and I got all emotional.
So his manliness went up and he let me off.
You couldn't cry from the start, huh? You had to be clever.
Look at me, look at me and...
Oh, whoa, yeah, "oh, n...
Sit down
come here
Were you born in Israel?
-Yeah.
You're holding my file, right?
-What's written here are just words.
Okay, let's wrap up this spy movie.
Do I really look like a spy to you?
Are you being clever, Ms. Rosen?
-No.
Do you realize that because of your cleverness
the relationship between Israel and Russia is at risk?
Do we need Putin to freak out on us?
Do you even understand what that means?
-Yeah, I get what you're saying,
I just don't really understand
how Putin is connected to me.
Let's start from the beginning.
Do you happen to know Chechens?
-Don't you say "Chachans"?
Do you know them?
-No.
Uzbeks?
Kazakhs?
-Definitely not.
Abkhazians?
-Maybe a few.
No, no, no, just kidding, do you think?
I don't know them. Me and Abkhazians, what...
Abkhazians, you say.
-No, no, no,
I'm not saying that and I don't know them,
I don't know Chechens, Chachans,
Uzbeks, or Abkhazians.
I'm Shiri Rosen, I'm not an atlas.
What do you want from me?
-I want you to tell me everything from start to finish,
including what exactly happened there.
Okay, on Saturday during the interrogation,
I'll tell you everything from the beginning.
Uh...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
What a handsome guy, Dad.
-Shabbat Shalom, Silvan.
You managed to squeeze into the suit.
You can laugh as much as you want
but this is a very prestigious firm.
Yeah, no, Dad, it shrank a bit since the wedding.
I'm so excited.
-Honestly, we're excited too.
I prepared, I prepared it myself.
Hello? Yeah.
Come here
Yeah, yeah,
yeah.
Thanks.
Okay, see you.
He canceled?
-No, I was warned he smokes.
That's the Russian Minister of Health!
Well, he got appointed a week and a half ago.
I'm going to set up a smoking area on the balcony.
-Alright.
I, I prepared it, really.
Listen, Mr. Minister.
Wait, when addressing the minister, we say
"Mr. Minister." How do they do it, you know?
Yeah.
.. yeah..
Wow, Mom.
-Hey, sweetheart.
I can't believe it, a senior minister,
a representative of one of the biggest powers
in the world at my house.
How's the dress?
The Red Square on May Day is educational in the background.
What, did I go overboard, is it too much?
-No, no, no, it's nice, it's very nice.
Help me clean the service.
The service of the Queen of England.
Well, it's not England, it's Russia.
It's not a queen, it's a minister.
Mom, it's the Minister of Health.
-Health is respectable enough.
I
am
for you
the hang' y ben-
Sweetheart, do you think my food is good enough?
The best.
-Good enough for...
Representing the State of Israel?
Yes.
.. yes..
To say "Your Honor."
-Your Excellency.
Your Excellency?
-Your Honor.
Okay, okay, okay, Your Excellency,
the Minister of Health and Hygiene.
Dad, tell me, what are you doing?
I want the meeting with the esteemed guest
to be a respectable and fruitful one.
Respectable, sure, but why fruitful?
He's not coming here for an official visit,
for him, it's family.
Yeah, exactly that,
exactly because it's a family visit
I want the conversation not to sink
into mundane topics, got it?
That's why I wrote a few words to share with him, that's all.
If I had time, I picked a few topics
that can lead to short to medium conversations.
Dad, listen...
I want the esteemed guest
to feel like he's talking to an interesting person
who represents sane Israel.
What’s that? What?
Do you need something?
-No, no, no, I...
I thought. The restroom is over there.
No, no, everything's fine.
-Thanks.
Alin is his wife and they are the only family
for whom, because his brother passed away,
he came here to see
where she lives and what's going on with her.
By chance, he was chosen to be the Minister of Health.
-And Hygiene.
So Dad, I'm asking, please don't ruin it for Alin
with unnecessary ceremonies.
The minister is coming, Meirav, and you're still not dressed.
I'm debating what to wear.
-What’s there to debate?
Wear that black one with
those down there, it's respectable enough.
Sorry, I don't need to look formal and respectable,
I need to look attractive and appealing.
What, are you a doll for the Russian minister?
-Why not?
Alin says he's single, right?
Excuse me.
Mom, don't ruin it for Alin.
Who knows, maybe this is her luck?
I've heard and seen weirder stories than this.
Where did you hear and see, on TV?
איפה שמעת וראית, בטלוויזיה?
I'm actually rooting for Meirav,
because she's trying hard and not giving up
and turning over every stone.
Even if the stone is from the Stone Age?
Doesn't it bother you
that he might be connected to the Russian mafia?
That's on the sidelines, I just want him to leave here
with a better image of the Israeli citizens
that make up the Israeli bloc between the powers.
-Nice.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
-What a suit.
I see everyone dressed up for the holiday.
Alin said to come dressed nicely, so we did.
So what, when you meet him, do you have to bow?
And click your heels.
K'
Buchoz"
Beny
I hope he comes before the madrasa gets embarrassed.
Shabbat Shalom.
Wow, Mom, where's that dress from?
It's the original dress from Little Red Riding Hood,
soon the Russian wolf will come and gobble her up.
What, did I overdo it?
-No, no, not at all, it's a stunning dress.
That suffers from redness.
What, is it too much?
-No, no, I'm just joking.
Where's Meirav?
-Getting ready for a date.
What date?
-For Meirav, every guest
is a date and a potential husband.
Isn't he supposed to be elderly?
-He's a bit older than me.
Here they are. Come on, let's welcome them nicely.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Hello.
This is our apartment and this is our family.
Wow, he's way younger than I thought.
Because it's not him, it's the security guy
from the Russian embassy.
Thanks.
The tests showed everyone passed except for Shabi Rozen.
She's registered with the police as having a criminal record
for aiding terrorists.
What about me?
-What terrorist?
He says they did preliminary tests
at the Russian embassy
and we're all fine,
except for you, who's a saboteur.
-What saboteur?
He says you have a criminal record
for suspected involvement in a terrorist act.
Terror?
-That must be a mistake.
It must be a mistake.
-The record is from today.
He says it's registered today.
Oh, come on, it's that stupid cop,
but he told me he erased it.
What, are you a terrorist?
I had a little car accident today
with a police car.
Accident?
Just a scratch, an accident.
Did you call the police?
-No need, there was a cop built-in in the car.
You know, it's great to crash
into a police car because it saves you the phone call.
Enough, Ben, he was at fault and I got mad at him,
I told him I’d file a complaint against him,
so he said he’d write me a serious offense and here we are.
It wasn't exactly like that,
you told him: let’s see you be more of a man.
You annoyed him, so he opened a case.
Then you cried, so he let you off.
-That's nonsense.
I know, I understand Hebrew.
It's okay, I'll call him to come.
Everything's good except for the little sweet terrorist.
What a stupid Israeli cop.
What did he say?
-He called me a terrorist but said it's fine.
Oh, okay.
Why didn't you tell me about the accident?
Come on, Mom, it’s not an accident, it’s a little fender bender.
And for a fender bender, he’s writing me up as a terrorist?
Because I annoyed him, I got out of the car,
and I started saying: Let’s see
you, man, I gave him the...
Forget it, come on, it’s over.
So not a word about the fender bender?
-Mom, come on, it’s not an accident,
it’s just a tiny scratch on the car.
I’ve hit the car so many times
that I don’t want to be the joke of everyone here,
especially this time when it’s not my fault at all.
And everyone’s just sitting here, smiling, laughing.
Why can women be good pilots?
Why?
-Because in the air, there’s no reverse.
Great, funny, funny.
Just this time she was totally fine,
it wasn’t her fault either.
Besides, aren’t you tired
of making jokes about women drivers
since the time she bent the bumper on the sign?
Where’s the best place to put women
so they won’t bother you while driving?
Where?
-In the glove compartment.
Well, that’s really not how you say it,
not at all, listen.
Where’s the best place to put women in the car
so they won’t bother you while driving?
Where?
-In the trunk.
Shai, please come to the bedroom.
-I’m coming, babe.
"Coming" means now.
-So now I’m coming, babe.
Do you know why women hate GPS?
Why?
-Because they don’t want anyone telling them
where to go.
You didn’t get it.
I got it, I got it.
-What did you get?
Shai, what was that just now?
-What? It wasn’t me, I didn’t tell the jokes.
It doesn’t matter, you laughed,
it’s like you’re laughing at me indirectly.
But I wasn’t laughing at you.
-I don’t care.
I don’t want you laughing at me, not above me, not in front of me,
not beside me or behind me, one, two, three.
Okay...
Can I at least chuckle...
something light like that.
-No.
Not even that?
If you want, you can laugh with your mouth closed, like this.
Like this.
Here he comes, here he comes.
Come on, let’s go.
Your Excellency, Minister...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom, Shabbat Shalom...
Minister, Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Please meet.
This is Rachel.
-Nice to meet you.
The pleasure is all mine.
This is Manny, my husband.
-Manny.
And this is the husband of Manny’s sister, Moshe.
-Moshe.
This is Orna, his wife.
Orna.
This is Meirav.
I’m Meirav, I’d love to get to know you better.
Relax, Meirav.
Water?
-Do you need water?
No, thanks.
-No, thanks.
Honey, you don’t need to translate every word,
everyone knows what "bait," "de," "charshan,"
"sapsiba," and "dasvidaniya" mean.
Sorry, everyone in Israel knows
how to say yes, no, and thank you in Russian.
What, now you’re translating what I said?
I’m sorry, I’m allergic to alcohol.
He’s allergic to alcohol.
-From my hand cream, damn it.
Meirav.
-Sorry.
Damn.
This is Silvan Hasson, the head of the family.
Your honor...
Now you’ll translate what I say word for word,
even if you don’t like it.
Right?
Please.
Your honor, the Minister of Health and Hygiene.
Honorable Minister of Health.
And Hygiene.
Health.
Right.
Mr. Honorable Minister, welcome to the painted house.
We’re happy to host you in our home.
Yes.
-I heard you have a special place for smokers.
What does he want?
-Yes, of course.
Over there on the balcony.
-Thanks, sorry.
Why the balcony?
He asked me where he could smoke?
I told him on the balcony. He said thanks.
I can’t believe it. You made a
period after "painted house,"
you made a period! That’s a comma.
That’s a ruling, why a comma?
Because I have a lot more to say, look.
You just crushed me.
-From me...
Your intonation was like a period.
Dad.
-Come on, enough, enough.
Did you see what European manners have vanished from the world?
Maybe try with dish soap?
-I’d try with a scrubber.
Great, exaggerate.
No, and you didn’t exaggerate with the flirting.
-How did I exaggerate?
From the first moment, he was sending me hidden messages.
You’re right.
Anyway, if you’re his doll and he’s going to kick the bucket,
then I think you need to hurry up.
Here, here...
And kudos to the minister.
It’s hot here.
-Right, hot.
Hello, Mr. Minister,
after "hello," there’s a comma because I have
something to say after the hello. Thanks.
Hello and...
I cleaned, I cleaned, no cream—
No creams now, what creams?
She came with creams.
Mr. Minister, in many ways, we, the Hasson family,
are the average Israeli family, comma.
In many ways, the Hasson family
is a regular Israeli family...
And I’d say...
-It was very nice to meet you.
Excuse me, where’s the bathroom?
-What’s he saying?
Bathroom, over there, the door at the end of the hallway.
Where is he going now?
-He said,
Nice to meet you.
-Yeah.
And where's the bathroom?
-What bathroom?
But I still have... I have more to say.
Alright, while he’s out,
let’s start organizing the food.
What, but that’s two hours earlier
than we usually eat.
I knew it, I didn’t eat since morning.
But I have something to say.
-He smokes a lot, doesn’t he?
I don’t know.
-I don’t know,
It seems to me like he’s
not measuring it in packs,
he smokes an acre, an acre and a half a day.
But I have something to say. I wrote...
Watch out, I’m reversing, Dad! The fish pot.
Not today. It’s not a good day for your reverses.
-Funny.
It wasn’t my fault this time.
Why don’t you just admit you’re a bad driver and that’s it?
She’s not a bad driver.
She just has parking issues, that’s all.
Listen, the police car reversed.
Come look, you have to see what happened.
Here a car was parked, here Anton was parked.
I came in from here, it’s a traffic light in the storage,
and he...
-Wait, no, no, no, don’t demonstrate with that, no,
you don’t want the salt shaker to reverse
and accidentally hit the Queen of England
and have a diplomatic incident
with your grandma, may she rest in peace.
From the diaspora, we gathered a stone, folks,
and by virtue of our historical right
and by virtue of the UN declaration on November 29th
we established this state for ourselves,
it’s the State of Israel.
It ruins their style.
Yeah, yeah, with the style.
He’s not answering, he’s not answering at all.
What’s up, Shai?
No, I’m afraid if I laugh at those jokes
about women or their driving
then she’ll walk in right then.
She’s right.
That’s not nice.
But those are just gender jokes,
it doesn’t mean anything.
It’s like jokes about Russians,
no one thinks they’re all...
or Persians.
-What do you have against Persians?
I don’t have anything, I don’t have anything.
She’s probably nervous because of the accident,
and you’re laughing because she’s a woman.
But it’s not related to the accident
and it’s not about driving skills,
it’s just a joke.
Look, see, no cop recognizes Anton after an accident
whether he belongs to a man or a woman?
How?
A woman put a floral pillowcase on the airbag.
Great, great, keep laughing at me.
-Come on, you’re not...
I just gave an example of a joke
that has nothing to do with you.
-Yeah?
Yeah, I downloaded it from the internet today
after you told me about the...
Oh, so you came prepared,
you prepared material to laugh at me on Friday.
Honey, you’re surprising me more by the minute.
With the cover,
Alright, Dad, maybe we should do a blessing?
But the minister is still in the bathroom, he’s not coming out.
Manny, go check on my uncle.
-Sure.
What?
-Got it, got it.
Alright, so you got it.
Honorable minister.
Honorable Minister of Health?
By the way, according to studies,
Is everything okay?
Women have way fewer accidents than men.
Is everything okay over there?
Me.
The minister isn’t answering, maybe he fell asleep?
Alin, maybe you should go call him in Russian?
He doesn’t understand Manny’s Russian.
Maybe tell him jokes about women driving
or about your wife’s motor skills,
That’ll wake him up.
-Enough, babe, enough.
I’m going to check.
Enough, babe.
-Why like this?
I didn’t get it.
-What didn’t you get, Moshe?
There’s no punchline here.
-Oh.
Uncle.
Chik
Uncle, we want to eat, we’re just waiting for you.
Uncle!
Okay, you all drive the best, alright?
I think he really fell asleep in the bathroom,
I don’t want to wake him up.
I’ll open it. I don’t mind waking him up.
Sir.
I’m opening.
I’m going to see what’s going on in there.
It was like a Bermuda Triangle in there.
Oh!! I don’t understand
-What?
He’s dead.
-Who, Moshe?
No, he fainted.
Mom?
-No, I’m not Mom.
The Russian minister died in the bathroom.
-What, no way.
Of course, understood.
He’s dead and Moshe fainted next to him.
-I feel like throwing up.
Wait, wait, wait, let me ask you,
Dead, dead?
-My uncle is dead?
How do you know he’s dead?
-He was dead.
What do we do now?
So now what, are they going to accuse us of murder?
We didn’t touch him.
God, now it’s the Russian mafia
and the oligarchs and... God...
Good thing he didn’t eat, otherwise they’d
blame me for my food.
The worst part is we don’t have an alibi.
If they catch someone, they’ll say
they were home as an alibi,
now they’ll ask us where you were at the time of the murder,
so we’d have to say we were at home
!This is the crime scene.
Okay, we need to call the police.
You need to calm down.
-But, babe, I touched him,
he was cold.
-You need to calm down, take some water.
I’m telling you, I know innocent people
who didn’t do anything,
they just got blamed, they sat in jail for weeks.
It’s fingerprints, it’s...
Silvan, we need to involve the police,
you have a dead Russian minister at home.
I touched him, I touched him.
-No...
I touched him.
I touched him, you understand,
I think I left fingerprints on him.
What am I going to do? What am I going to do?
Come on, I’ll help you, come.
Okay, there’s no choice, we need to call the police.
Isn’t it better to call his guards outside?
-Not at all.
In this case, I prefer the Israeli police.
Yeah, but maybe those guys know what to do.
Whatever they do won’t help like a glass of air for the dead.
Wait a sec, there's a problem.
-What happened now?
Moshe tried to wipe his fingerprints
off the minister's forehead with a cloth.
And from the rubbing, the minister fell on the handle.
Yeah, I think it's a serious crime.
What?
-It's a serious crime.
I'm done with them.
And then the idea to roll him up in a rug was scrapped.
And throw him in the sands of Rishon.
We went and told the security guards that you were called.
And then you showed up.
Okay, I get that you went through a tough trauma today.
Yeah.
-You think I don't know?
It was fine, Dad.
One more little thing,
I need to interrogate Shai Rosen.
Me?
-Winner. Bring him in.
And then you took me in for questioning because of
that stupid accident with the police car.
Now I totally get it.
I just hope I can
explain all this to the Russians.
Besides that, I'm really sorry about what
happened to you with the cop in the car.
You just caught them on a bad day.
No, no, honestly, I'm sorry too,
I annoyed him as well.
Next time you decide to hit a police car,
check first that it’s not Vlad's car.
He's a little prick.
A little prick.
-That's close.
Shabbat Shalom.
Please welcome the terrorist, Shai Rosen.
You're okay, my sweet.
We thought the KGB already took you
to their torture facility in Siberia.
Everything's fine, Dad, everything's fine,
I apologized, they apologized,
it was just a bad day, for me and for Vlad.
The worst day ever.
-Why, what happened to you?
I lost a life-long friend.
How's that a life-long friend? You barely knew each other.
Yeah, but there was a quick click.
Do you think Russia will recognize me as a widow
even though we weren't officially married?
Alright, come on, let’s start the Kiddush.
I had so much to say to him,
I didn't even get to say half of what I prepared.
Okay, Dad, now Kiddush,
save what you have to say for the funeral.
Period.
Shame on you.
Comma.
I prepared Kiddush in the minister's language!
"And on the sixth day.
The heavens and the earth stopped.
Sabri Maranan.
To life."
Really, take this!
I just want this day to be over,
not the best day I've had.
An accident, a Chechen terrorist,
a Chechen murderer.
See how important it is to drive carefully?
No, don’t start, don’t start with me
again about that accident.
You know I'm not to blame
and even the police came and apologized.
Okay, I want to apologize too.
I want to start by saying
I have no problem with women driving.
Okay.
-You drive just like men do.
And it's just a coincidence
that you have trouble parking in reverse.
Oh, come on.
-What did I do?
I think I hit an ambulance with the body of the Russian minister.
Let him go, you know, to his country with a feeling,
but! a better feeling, you know?
The citizens are upset, that we're part of...
The minister is coming, you’re not yet...
Are you a terrorist?
-Not a terrorist, Dad. Do I look like one?
A terrorist...
What was that just now?
Oh, I cleaned... cream house...
I’ll open them, I have no issues.
You’re going to open it?