Honey, why did you wear that shirt?
You're losing it.
What, I'm not putting in any effort for them.
-Fine, neither am I, who cares.
But like, you know, if they're filming
at least let it be respectable.
What’s with the "filming" thing, does that excite you?
Today, everywhere you go
you're caught on a thousand security cameras.
In malls, parking lots, clubs,
on Highway 6, in the fast lane.
In Ramat Gan, you're filmed, down to your bones.
Fine, what do I care?
Let them film, what can I do?
Really, there's nothing to do because it won't be long
before everything goes live,
to YouTube, and of course, Erez Tal will host it.
Of course.
-And the viewers at home will vote! More
than from parking lots, from malls... Shabi Rosen,
do you have a minute to leave the mall?
Funny.
-And outside, even bigger cameras will be waiting for you.
If you get through this, in a month
you'll be hosting a show on Channel Two.
Fine, but aren't you a little excited?
-No, what’s that, I’m just being natural.
What do I care if they’re filming, or not.
-Okay.
Honey, what are you doing? There’s a camera at this intersection.
What, did they just film us?
What’s up with your eyebrows?
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom, Shabbat Shalom.
What’s this? What did Rachel buy this time from the shopping channel?
No, it’s not Rachel, it’s not the shopping channel,
it’s Meirav this time.
-What’s this? Is that a karaoke machine?
Maybe
and M
Sharon
What does it matter?
-What? How’s Meirav?
Meirav, ever since she was told
she made it to the next round of "Born to Sing"
she’s been driving us crazy.
I must say, it’s a big surprise.
I didn’t even know she could sing.
She didn’t even know she could sing.
What’s this? What’s the black elephant?
-That’s it.
She wants to impress the filming crew,
like it’s just a regular thing
in our house, that we have a dishwasher,
we have a washing machine
and we also have a karaoke machine.
It gives a musical home vibe.
But what? But what, there’s barely a chorus.
For us, sol is herring.
Seriously, tell me, where’s Mom?
Right now, she’s getting a briefing from Meirav.
A briefing from Meirav. That’s interesting.
Because usually, you get a headache from Meirav.
Mom, you have to understand that misery
is part of every reality show competition.
No, that’s nonsense and I’m not up for it.
No, I don’t get it.
You want to direct a reality show?
The whole point of a reality show is that it’s real,
that it’s spontaneous, it’s reality.
-You cracked me up big time, Mom.
All this reality you see
is staged to the last detail.
People say the lines they’re given,
they make up life stories, deafness, blindness.
There’s even a rumor that the dwarf
from "Big Brother" isn’t even a dwarf.
It’s a camera trick.
-How do you know all this?
I’m telling you with certainty, Mom.
If you’re not a loser, you’re not exciting
and if you’re not exciting, you don’t get sympathy.
And if you don’t get sympathy,
there are no SMS votes, and if there are no SMS votes,
it means you don’t exist
even if you think you do.
You don’t want me to succeed?
-I want you to, of course, I want.
Good. Everything for you, it’s fine.
Thanks, Mom.
-Alright.
Oh, and if you could
speak a bit more with a ch and an ayin...
What?
-For the voices of the Mizrahim.
ותקראי בבקשה לאבא בדרך.
חית ועין?
-אימא...
טוב, בסדר, רק תעשי לי טובה.
כשאבא יבוא, תהיי איתו מאוד עדיבה.
שלא יחטוף התקף לב, חס וחלילה.
התקף לב זה מעולה,
אם זה בזמן צילומים, זה מלא אס-אם-אסים.
שי, אתה מבין את דף ההוראות הזה?
אני לא מסתדר עם ההיגיון הסיבוך.
מה, מה לא ברור, אבא?
-זה כמו סינית בשבילי.
זה בעברית.
זה בעברית אבל זה בביב 0'ב'.
-ביב.
כן.
-רגע, זה לא בעיה.
בוא, בבקשה, תראי לי.
אני לוחצת כאן, להתחלה.
-בוא?
התחל. לוחצת, לוחצת.
פלייליסט.
-אוקיי.
ועכשיו אתה בוחר שיר,
לוחץ וזה יתחיל להתבגן.
-וואלה, כל הכבוד!
בחיי.
-רגע, חזור, חזור, חזור.
חזור, פלייליסט. קח את זה רגע.
איזה... הכפתורים... תראי כמה שהם קטנים,
זה כמו לסחוט קנקן של מיץ תפוזים
מתפוזים סיביים קטנים.
שבת שלום.
-שבת שלום.
שבת שלום, אימא'לה.
שבת שלום. אחת, שתיים...
הנה זה עובד.
-זה הטלפון שלי.
מה, הרבה? כן, כן, הבחורה כבר כאן.
אני לא שמעתי שאסור לבוא עם פסים לטלוויזיה.
בן, די, אין לנו זמן. תבואו. בוא.
סאלי, מירב מחכה שתבוא לתדרוך דחוף.
מה יש לך, אימא, מה קרה לך עם החית הזאת?
-נתקע לך משהו בגרון?
אתם תגיעו למירב, אז תבינו מה אירע.
מה אירע?
-מה יש לה?
אבא יודע. אני לא צריך את התדרוכים שלה.
סאלי, היא תתעצבן.
-שתתעצבן. גם אני יודע להתעצבן.
בסדר?
סאלי?
-היא תתעצבן...
סאלי, אני מבקשת ממך. תיכנס למירב.
זה סיכוי בפלא למצוא לה חתן ראוי.
עוד פעם התרגיל הזה עם החתן הראוי?
החתן הראוי, החתן הראוי. בן, שי, בוא כבר.
ביום שהוא יבוא אני אציע לו שלא יבוא.
שידע כמה שאנחנו סבלנו בגללו עד שהוא בא.
החתן הראוי... או, הוא יצטער,
הוא יצטער על היום הזה שהוא בא,
החתן הראוי הזה. אדרבא,
שיבוא, שיבוא, שיראה אותן,
נראה אותו לפני שהוא הולך.
ולא חוזר. כמו כולם.
אבא, השלט.
-מה?
השלט.
-הנה השלט.
הצלחתם להתקין?
-כן. זה פשוט, זה...
כן
ו
זה בני
הנה. פליי.
חזור, חזור, חזור.
חזור, חזור.
אבא, תנסה להיות קשוב.
אני צריכה שהקהל בבית ירחם עליי.
אתה תכנס לי בול לדמות הקורבן.
-קורבן? אני?
כן
בני.
מה
רב.
אני כן
כי יש לך היסטוריה של עלבון ועליבות.
אה, וכך את תמצאי חתן?
שידע שיש לך משפחה אינפנטילית
ואבא קורבן?
-טוב, בסדר,
אתה תספר את הסיפור האישי שלי.
-כל הסיפור?
You’ll say I’m almost a widow of the IDF.
-How can you be almost a widow?
Say my almost ex-husband fell in battle.
I don’t get it. Did he fall or almost fall?
-He fell during the fight.
On a wasp's nest, and got stung by a bee,
and it turns out he was allergic,
so he swelled up and since then he’s been in rehab
at "Beit Levinstein."
Got it?
And the wasp?
Dad...
-Okay, okay, fine.
Fine. You’re almost a widow, he’s almost dead
and he’s almost at Beit Levinstein too.
Got it? And if they want to film,
Almost film at Beit Levinstein?
-Then we’ll say he passed away yesterday.
And if they want to film the funeral?
-Then we’ll say he’s in a coma
and he doesn’t want to be filmed.
-Because of the coma?
For privacy reasons.
"Rachel, look, they’ve returned to their borders..."
Enough, stop that.
There’s some faking going on here.
-I hope you got Dad’s singing talent
Meirav got from him.
-Excuse me, I’m not faking.
The one faking is this old machine.
It’s an ancient machine,
from the days when Shoshana Damari lived in a rickety shack.
Enough, come on, Mom, let’s go. You’re not a singer.
I remember when I was a kid
and you sang "Nomi Bumi" to me,
I closed my eyes not because I fell asleep. From the chills.
Okay, play me something else.
Here, this, this, I love this.
"Alvar, Alor, to you, Aliram."
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom, my sweethearts. Shabbat Shalom.
What’s going on here?
-What is this, karaoke?
Karaoke.
-It’s with an accent. Krau-ka.
Yeah, yeah, Meirav rented this machine
to impress the filming crew,
like to show them we’re a musical and musical family.
Did you know the word music isn’t spelled with a "z"
but with a "t" or a pencil?
Okay, play me the song...
-No need. Come on, we heard you from downstairs.
I studied music
and 99% of people are off-key.
It’s not easy to sing in perfect pitch.
Yeah, it’s fine that 99 percent
are off-key in one tone, sure,
but what happens when one person is off-key among 99 good ones?
Funny, right?
Sure.
_Okay, who wants to
-Dad.
Yeah, before I forget: Shani and Shai,
to the teachers' room for a briefing with Meirav.
Okay, sit down, let’s finish this.
Silvan.
-Wait, who put a song for me? I want to sing.
What’s the problem operating this?
-Here’s the instruction sheet, put it there.
No need, just give it here. Ah, okay.
What song do you want, Dad?
This.
-This.
Okay.
Start, enter, choose,
go back, go back, go back.
I can do that too.
-Come on, give it here.
Can you act like you’re paralyzed?
-Are you normal?
Why paralyzed? Paralysis is, it’s a small creator,
it doesn’t really evoke sympathy.
Maybe we can take off a hand or a leg.
-I thought about that,
but it’s a bit hard to prove he doesn’t have a leg.
-So maybe you should bring a saw.
Sit down. I have a better idea.
Send the filming crew to film his mom.
They see Riki in action,
you get a sea of tears in the meantime.
"Alone I will go, I have no prayer.
Alone, without a future, without hope, without a dream..."
Stop.
-What happened?
You're off-key.
What?
-You're singing half a tone lower, as usual.
Really?
-At least it's consistent.
I can change the key.
-Go ahead, be my guest.
Here you go.
"I will walk alone
I have no prayer..."
What? What now? What now?
-I'll change it again. Okay?
Here you go.
"I will walk alone, I have no prayer..."
Stop.
-There's a problem.
No, the problem is with you.
-With me? Don't talk nonsense. Okay?
I have no problem. I've got a great voice.
So she got the musical side from Mom?
You're right, Silvan. You've got a great voice.
It's just that you're not in tune yourself.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Is this the karaoke machine?
-Karaoke.
Kirioki.
-Don't you think she went overboard this time?
Why? Why? What's wrong? She leveled up.
Why not support her? What happened?
So one evening, help her out.
That's not an unreasonable request.
She wants me to say on TV that I'm dying.
What's better, her filming your mom?
Rachel, come here, please. I want to talk to you.
And Manny and Alin, for Meirav
to brief about "Born to be Miserable."
Let's get out of here quickly before someone
decides to make us miserable with another song.
I want to sing one.
-Quick, quick, quick, quick.
Wow, maybe we should do a duet?
-Wow, wow, wow. We were first.
What even...
-It's our turn, and we planned a duet.
Tell me, seriously, does this whole misery thing seem right to you?
It's terrible.
-She leveled up, right?
Yeah, she leveled up... it's not that.
Listen to him-aye
I, I heard her sing.
With all due respect, this...
-Sali, maybe, maybe we,
actually appreciate her too little?
Do you know anyone who appreciates her too much?
No, because if there was, he'd already be marrying her.
Meirav, you're a doll floating in the air.
You have no chance. You're not a singer.
Why are you discouraging her? There are surprises in reality shows.
True.
-What do you want us to do?
Like this. Alin, you need to speak with as much accent as possible
and try to use words with the letter "resh."
"Resh?"
-"Resh."
It shows a connection
between new immigrants and the local population.
Now I want you to say you worked in a mall as a security guard
and helped catch a terrorist, then got promoted
to be a cashier at the supermarket.
In short, you want all the stereotypes
of Russians.
Not all of them, but before you met Manny you...
-Shh!
No, no, no!
-Don't you dare say that.
So the Russian slot is taken?
-Duh.
And which slot do you want to put Manny in?
Do you think you can fit Manny into any slot?
"I don't hear, I don't see
and usually I'm wrong..."
Enough.
-Why? Come on...
I haven't gotten to the part where "this is how you wanted me,
take me like this, with all that I am.
-And what you lack."
Shai, I think they took this
a bit too seriously. It's just karaoke,
we don't need professional singers here.
-Alright.
Orna and Moshe, Meirav is calling you.
-What, what's going on?
We're representing the melting pot.
-Orna!
I'm curious, what will I be?
-Come on, before she gets mad.
Come on, what did you get?
-I married a cashier at the supermarket.
Do you have a membership card? Updated on the deals?
What about you?
-I got to talk about...
the almost husband who's almost dead.
-Enough, enough, calm down.
It's just for the evening.
-Why am I the only one dying?
Enough, let's stop. Let's find a
happy song to lift everyone's spirits.
Okay?
-I have an idea for a really happy song.
Wait.
-Please.
Repeat, repeat, repeat, repeat.
I'm Orna, Meirav's sister. I'm a nurse by profession
at a hospice for terminal cases
because someone needs to hold their hand
in their last moments, and Meirav, my sister,
volunteers with us twice a week.
Every evening she comes and sings to the residents at dinner,
sometimes without accompaniment. A cappella.
-What's a cappella?
It's without accompaniment. You learn the text really fast. Huh?
What am I? What am I?
-You're a resident who was at her hospice
they fell in love! And to their surprise, he survived and they got married.
So we're in a relationship?
-Yeah. You have kids, right?
What's my text to learn?
-That's it, you don't have a text
because during the surgery you had, they removed your
vocal cords and you're mute.
-Mute.
That's really a very happy song.
Three, four and...
"My father left me before I was born,
my mother went to God weeks ago
I have no friend, no one on this earth,
I'm sad and miserable in my soul"
Again.
"I have no friend, no one on this earth,
I'm sad and miserable in my soul..."
Generally, you all don't make noise, don't ask questions
If anyone needs to pee, now's the time. Not right now, right now.
After I finish talking now. Got it?
Now for the role distribution.
Each one gets something, so no jealousy.
You're limping, you're stuttering.
I'm
here.
You can't see colors.
-And!
You're waiting for a pancreas transplant.
You're adopted from Colombia.
You suffer from Alzheimer's.
-Exactly!
And you can't walk, only crawl.
-And!
Sweetheart.
"I'm sad and miserable in my soul. Hey!"
Is everyone briefed?
-Yeah.
Does everyone know their stories?
Yes, I
-Why am I dying?
What about you?
-Mute.
Being mute is smart.
Can he also be dying in addition to being mute?
No, lucky he recovered.
I'm his nurse, I took care of him.
Wait, did he marry his sister?
-No, a hospital sister.
A nurse who takes care of Meirav's almost husband
who is paralyzed from the neck up.
Sali...
-and the pole.
Alright, no last-minute changes.
Besides that, I want to practice
my song before they arrive.
And when they walk in, I'll be in the middle of the song.
-What if they're late?
You're mute.
Then you'll hear the song a few times.
Why isn't it working?
Give me a second.
-What did you do to make it not work?
It's stuck on this song.
-What song is it?
"She left me before I was even born..."
Stop.
-But I can't sing that.
It doesn't give other options.
-Turn it off and on.
Let me, please.
-I can't sing that.
It's too happy. I'm associated
with "Eucalyptus Grove."
Now it won't play at all.
-Great. Thank you so much.
I knew you'd manage! To ruin this for me. Move! Move!
Let me, let me.
-As if someone else would volunteer.
Everything good in my life gets ruined.
Enough, my beautiful, don't cry, it's a shame about the makeup.
Don't cry over smeared makeup.
-How will I live without music?
Mirav, why do you need all these masks?
All this misery and the supposedly musical house?
Go with your truth, that's miserable enough.
Tell me, Shani, wasn't there someone else
who was associated
with "Eucalyptus Grove"?
-Yeah, the one who couldn't sing well, the Ethiopian.
Wow, I remember her. What a poor thing.
What, so you think that...
Mirav is their new Eucalyptus Grove?
Wait, wait, wait. Has anyone of you
ever heard her sing?
Yeah. Why?
-Does she sing well?
No. Why?
-There. I fixed it.
Did you succeed?
-Yes!
"When Mom comes here
'young here
Dad built her a house on a hill"
That's them. Open the door for them, I'll keep singing.
"But on the banks of the Jordan
as if nothing happened
the same imagery
!the same scenery
Eucalyptus Grove
the bridge, the boat
and the salty smell..."
What, is it stuck again?
Is this how it is every Friday?
-Hello. You probably want to interview me.
Come on!
-The hair, the hair.
Sorry.
Come, sit here. Do you want to start
by recording a few of my lines?
I want to ask you...
-Ori, what I was thinking
is that I can say a few lines
that you can air throughout the season.
So here it is: I can't believe I made it to the quarter-finals
and just wait! Look where I came from.
Me? Mirav Hasson? I made it to the semi-finals?
My whole family is in shock. In shock.
Oh
oh
Sorry to interrupt but oh.
Oh!! Oh oh
They're interviewing Dad now
and the "oh" is even bigger.
Oh!
You have to see Dad.
He's crying over himself, it's genius.
Mirav, I want to show you something.
I really don’t know what happened to that wasp.
Because, as you know, wasps,
when they sting, they don’t die.
They switch out.
Can we film the blessing?
-Of course. With pleasure, a lot of pleasure.
"The eucalyptus grove,
the bridge, the boat..."
-She sings beautifully.
What?
-I didn’t know someone sang it before.
And so well. So they moved me up a level.
Just because it seems like I’m imitating
her and they’re actually making fun of me?
Something like that, but...
Yeah.
Their comic relief.
-They want to film the blessing.
"On the sixth day, the heavens and the earth finished..."
Sorry, sorry to interrupt.
Can you do it higher?
No, no, no. The voice higher.
But I dropped it down half a tone again.
-No, no.
"On the sixth day...
-No, no. Can you go higher?
-Higher, higher.
If you can add some vibrato to it.
What’s that?
-Vibration.
"And the heavens finished..."
Alright, come on, come on. "Born to sing," right.
Born to fly. Don’t film me.
That was the best sixth day
with your family for Shavuot.
"I don’t work for anyone, no, no."
"Confuse him until he can’t sleep..."
Kaa Kalibka.
"Here in my home, my home with both my hands..."
"Oh Don Quixote, don’t be so naive..."
-"You suddenly came back, here you are at home..."
Sali! Sali!
-Silvan! Silvan!
Come, come, there’s a new Mizrahi song
by Gispan. Come.
Maybe we should also
rent a karaoke machine for your family.
You think?
-Of course.
Why? But I didn’t get to the part of "Take me
"This is how you wanted me."
-This is how you wanted me.
Why? I didn’t get to the part of "Take me like this."
Why, but why? I didn’t get to the part of "Take me."
-Like this!
And what do you want to do with Manny’s slot? Sorry.
Like, to give the feeling that we’re a musical home.
In the tree, in the canyon, we’re a musical home.
Are we a musical home?
-That’s the idea.
Sorry.
I have no problem.
-So the musical side...
I have a great...
Let me say "I have a great voice."
That’s really funny.
I can’t sing that song!
-Can’t you act without a smile?
אני לא יכולה לשיר את השיר הזה!
-את לא יכולה לשחק בלי חיוך?