God, I'm exhausted.
-Tough night.
Sorry again for dropping in on you like this.
Chill, chill, bro. You've got other problems.
You can always come and talk. No problem at all.
Just look at the mess you left in the kitchen.
I don't get when you even had time to talk.
You totally wrecked the kitchen.
You went through the fridge,
cleared it out shelf by shelf.
I came in the morning, and the kitchen looked
like Yarkon Park after Mimouna celebrations.
We wanted to tidy up but didn’t want to make noise.
Okay.
-So...
There was a little cake there,
I hope it wasn't saved for anything.
Yeah, it was a bite between—
Great, that's the little one's birthday cake.
Hope it brings good luck.
-Thanks.
I'm really sorry.
-It's okay, bro.
The birthday party was a month ago.
A month?
-A month.
I hope you don't have an "after-party" in your stomach.
Mom, who cried last night?
Evitar Gdasi.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Where have you been? I was so worried.
Shabbat Shalom. Come on, girls.
Come to Grandpa. Shabbat Shalom, sit down.
Shabbat Shalom, cuties.
Oh, Tzvi, how's it going?
-Shabbat Shalom. You know...
Not really, but I can relate.
Tzvi got a bit tangled up with his future ex.
-Shai...
Just kidding, man, they're in another round of fighting so...
Come to the kitchen, let’s eat some schnitzels.
I get that really lifts the mood.
Good.
So, he cried all night for you?
I know that feeling.
I feel bad for him, I like Tzvi.
I’ll go check they're not making a mess.
Sit down, you shouldn't have agreed.
If he wants to leave, let him go to a hotel.
Ben.
-Okay, okay, the mistake's already made.
So what, is he simmering at your place?
-Yeah.
I don't mind, but I care that he’s putting
all kinds of bugs in Shai's head.
Be a man, don’t be a sucker,
stand your ground. What...
You don't have to worry, Shai won't eat just anything.
No, he actually will. No, I'm joking.
A little. That's not the point, really.
Fighting is totally fine,
it's part of a relationship. But if there's love, Pinchas,
leaving is not an option at all.
-Look, at first Riki and I also...
You know, we used to fight over every little thing.
But then I realized it was pointless.
In the end, she always makes me look guilty
and stupid and I have to apologize,
so instead, retroactively and in hindsight,
I wave a white flag and the sea is calm with no waves.
Pinchas makes sense.
You just don’t get him.
I didn’t get it, but it sounds reasonable.
Pinchas...
-Don’t you see I’m waving a white flag?
Here, eat.
-Is it hot?
Why with your hands, like a barbarian? Give him a plate.
It tastes better with your hands, Mom.
Yeah, one day you'll accidentally eat your own fingers.
Mom, please, this isn't the time for that.
-How long have you been together?
Seven weeks.
-Well, maybe you started by mistake.
Those seven weeks were rough. Now it’ll be good.
I really hope those were the bad seven weeks.
Because if those were the good ones,
I don't want to imagine what's coming.
Bad times with that troublemaker.
-What's a troublemaker?
I already told you,
when couples fight, each one thinks
their partner is the troublemaker.
I'm sure your dad doesn't think I'm a troublemaker.
Of course not! You're not a troublemaker.
That's...
-A troublemaker is a guy! A Mizrahi?
Compared to Yael, my wife, you're an angel.
-And how am I compared to Shai?
What do you mean? What a question, what...
You're both angels.
Yeah, but my Yael really was an angel.
It's like this since three in the morning,
he goes "uhhh" every fifteen minutes.
Oh, that's tough. How long will he be simmering at your place?
Until they make up. I really hope
it won't take too long.
Because if not, I'm kicking both of them out of the house.
Or I'm moving in with Tzvi's wife.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
What, are you alone?
-I'm torn apart.
Collecting chicken thighs all night. Is it any wonder he's tired during the day?
Adam?
-Yeah, it's me.
I thought I heard you.
-I'm just closing my eyes for five minutes. Okay?
Don't you want some eggs?
-No, he's more into
chicken thighs.
-Enough already.
Riki never makes chicken thighs.
They're too juicy for her taste.
Someone else might enjoy that.
-Pinchas, I can hear you.
You want to switch to Shai and Shani for a week,
so all the guys can complain together?
-Sorry, Riki, sorry.
No, don't say "sorry,"
say "thank you for what I have."
Because it can always be a lot worse.
Thanks, Riki, thanks.
You see, no matter what I do,
I always end up getting in trouble.
You guys are just pretending to be victims.
No, Shai, we're not pretending to be victims.
We really are victims.
You women are oppressing us
and then shout "equality."
I say: come on, I wish
there was already equality.
We don't even have rights in our own home.
Freedom fighter.
Pinchas Luther King.
Shai and...
,h chimibutzan
.
L'shon!
Quiet! This is the living room.
Ben, my brother, how do you feel after...
Seven chicken thighs?
-It's filling but not uplifting.
No, I told you it wouldn't help.
No worries, Adam just arrived,
he'll tell you how nice it is in the single life,
I'm sure it'll cheer you up.
You won't believe the girls he meets.
Yeah, but today he came alone. He's really tired.
I think he had two night shifts.
Come on, brother, come hear some stories. If he's lucky,
he might flirt with a celebrity.
What? They finished your chicken thighs.
-It's okay, may they enjoy them.
Yeah, I would say "enjoy,"
but after what they did to me
last night, that wasn't enjoyment,
it was a sickness.
And then the maid comes in the morning and cries about everything.
It'll pass. Tzvi and his wife will make up,
it'll end and he'll go back home.
Amen!
-It was the same when Shai lived here.
If he was in a fight with some girl
or if he was arguing with his parents.
And he stayed to sleep.
-How long would that usually take?
You know his dad is
the head cardiologist at Assaf Harofeh,
if you ever need it.
-Why would I need it?
Because you're an "I type person,"
you take things to heart and pound schnitzels.
Thanks for the encouragement, Riki.
-Anytime, sweetie.
Sit down, leave that alone,
don’t interfere with Shai and his friends.
You’re not at risk, trust me.
I’m saying this for your own good.
I don’t have the skills I developed anymore.
Ahh, no.
-What happened? Did something happen?
Nothing.
Come on, Riki’s schnitzel helper?
-Not really.
Wait, Dad, I thought Adam's stories
were still the same.
Leave him alone, he’s tired.
-Adam, Adam, why are you so tired?
Leave it, bro, let the kid be.
-Tell it, tell it, come on.
I didn’t sleep all night, okay?
-He didn’t sleep all night. You get it?
Leave him, leave him alone.
-Hey, Tzvi’s here, say hi.
Hey, Tzvi, sorry, I’m just wiped out.
-It’s okay.
No, wait, I promised him
a juicy story like that,
to cheer him up.
-Sure, there are plenty of stories.
Let him sleep.
-Alright, one story and I’m out.
I promised a friend I’d tell him what’s
going on in the single life in Tel Aviv. Come on.
You don’t know what he’s already been through.
-Leave them alone, enough.
So why, why didn’t you sleep last night?
-Because someone dumped me. Okay?
Someone I wanted. So I spent the whole night
sitting in some bar feeling sorry for myself. Okay?
Yo.
Dad's going to sleep on the balcony.
Those whines...
-I didn’t remember it was this intense.
Okay, I can’t take it anymore.
Yael, Yael, Yael. Yael!
Hey, Yael. No, it’s not Tzvi, it’s Shai’s Shabi.
Listen, I really know it’s like this,
it’s not customary to interfere between couples,
but Tzvi is just howling and whining like crazy.
I’m sure you can forgive him
for some nonsense he didn’t do.
No, he won’t do it again.
Huh? Shabi.
Shabi of Shai.
Shai Rosen, his friend.
Are you Yael?
And you’re not his wife?
Yael from work. Sorry, it’s a mistake.
Whoa...
I can’t stand this anymore.
Honey? Honey.
Hi. No, it’s not Tzvi. Yael?
Honey. Ah, he...
I’m really sorry. I got confused.
Sorry. What’s this?
Yes, I can pass it to him.
What?
That they moved his appointment with the proctologist up by two days.
Alright, I’ll let him know. Bye.
You’ll really have a reason to whine soon.
Mishmash?
It’s probably his mom.
Mom, you idiot. What are you doing here?
I really don’t care what you’re doing.
I’m going to sleep in the bedroom.
Call me for food.
-Oh! Babe.
Thanks.
-Not you.
Babe.
Yael? It’s Shai’s Shabi.
Yes, he’s here.
I don't get it. What were you fighting about?
-I don't know. We were talking,
and then suddenly she flipped out.
At first, words were thrown,
then vases were thrown,
and I told her: if you don't calm down,
I'm leaving the house for good.
-And...?
He left for a day and a half.
-Maybe I was wrong.
She was so young when we got married.
-No, no, no. Tzvi, Tzvi,
Don't whine. Tzvi, no!
What’s going on? What happened?
-What happened?
Wow, Tzvi, what a story! 20 years.
No, I'm dying. Can't you see he's crying?
What happened to him?
-He fought with his wife.
So he left the house! He slept at our place.
-Sorry to hear that.
What, what happened?
-Do you really want to know?
No, I'm just asking out of politeness.
-He's joking.
I'm not.
It's you guys.
Oh, Riki.
-Oh, Mom.
How's it going? Got schnitzel?
-Of course.
You're building here today.
-Thanks.
What happened?
-What?
I'm in the kitchen.
-I'm coming.
Maybe I'll go down to the car.
-Tell me, are you normal?
You're not going to the kitchen to eat.
You're asking him what happened,
with empathy.
Me, Tzvi, what happened? Tell me.
Itamar, do me a favor, go eat something.
Later, if you have the energy,
come back for dessert, to hear gossip.
-Thank you very much.
Tzvi, Tzvi, no! No!
You avoided the living room because of Tzvi?
-Yeah.
That Tzvi messed me up.
-Ahhh.
Ahhh.
-Oh dear.
Sorry, am I interrupting your quality time with my mom?
Itamar, stop messing around and take some schnitzel,
it'll make you stop talking nonsense.
-What do you want,
Michal's been grinding my brain all day
that I'm rude and tactless,
so I just checked—
-For a change, she was right.
What? Did you meet Tzvi?
-I heard you opened a shelter for whiners?
I'm coming too.
-What do you have to whine about?
You had a golden wife. You didn't know how to keep her,
she slipped through your fingers.
-What slipped?
How can you hold an eel?
-Eat, eat.
There's nothing to do with Tzvi.
-Actually, there is.
I called his wife.
-You had her number?
No, but I had his number.
And what did you tell her?
-I told her the truth,
that he regrets it, that he's crying,
that he's whining, that he asks for forgiveness
and that he's waiting for her to come get him.
Did he ask you to do that?
-Not exactly, but he hinted.
He forgot his phone next to me.
-Nice.
Good job, I never liked that Tzvi.
He and Shai always bullied me
when I was a little kid.
Itamar, please. Don't talk with your mouth full.
What’s with all of you today?
I didn't know you had that in you.
What, is that a compliment, Riki?
Because I don't know whether to be happy.
-Be happy, be happy.
Because that's the closest to a compliment I've ever heard
my mom say to anyone.
That's really something.
More than that, it would be a Nobel Prize
or lighting the torch.
Suck in your stomach.
Tzvi, do you want to watch something on TV?
There's a new show by Aharoni, you haven't seen anything like it.
I'm still full from the schnitzels.
-What did he do to his wife?
Why do you jump to conclusions?
-Because I don't understand what he's doing here.
Like talking to his wife, for example.
-I never want to talk to her again.
Come on
Come here.
Yael, what are you doing here? How did you know I was here?
What do you mean how did I know?
You asked Shabi to call me, right?
-No. Shabi.
Shabi called you?
-Yeah, she said you wanted to make up.
And that I should come.
-I don't want to handle our fights.
Here in front of everyone.
-You can go to the bedroom.
Ignore the mess.
-Thanks.
What are you doing here?
-What do you mean "what am I doing here"?
Sit down, babe...
-What?
What did you do? Did you call Yael?
-Yeah. Did she arrive? Is she here?
Yeah, they're in the bedroom.
-Oh, great, great.
You can't just do things like that without talking to me,
he's your friend, you just complicated things for them.
Shai, don't make a big deal out of it.
-Mom, this is between me and my wife.
They'll talk and make up.
She actually handled it just fine this time.
Riki, it's their business.
You don't have to interfere in everything.
You always interfere and I hold back
from saying anything to you,
but this time you crossed the line.
Pinchas, since when do you interfere?
Since when do you call me out in front of everyone?
-See what you did now?
Instead of one fight, there are now three fights.
Enough, come on, babe. I had good intentions.
Yeah, good intentions on the way to hell?
Okay, Pinchas, apologize and let's end this.
-Enough! Stop!
You shouldn't have interfered
in the argument between Shai and Shani.
About whether she should have interfered or not.
Why? Sometimes it's a mitzvah to interfere.
-Why do you think you know everything?
Do you even know what happened between Tzvi
and Yael that made it right to call them?
I'll say what I think.
She got married very young,
so either she's naive or she's after money.
What?
-Mom, Michal's here, that's not nice.
Is that all you have to say to her, "Michal's here"?
You might be really old,
but you're just a four-year-old kid.
What are you saying? Three fights plus one for free.
It's not her fault. It's Pinchas.
No, it's not Dad, it's Michal
who suddenly snapped at me.
Come on, you see this has nothing to do with me?
Tell me, are you normal? What are you doing here?
Do you want to act out here too
and throw vases?
-You're an idiot.
Ouch!
-Sorry.
Sorry, just a second.
What are you doing here?
I told you, Shabi called from your phone,
said you wanted to make up
and that I should come. But what does it matter?
Do you want to talk or not?
-But why here?
We're already here, right?
-But we can't talk here.
Do you want me to leave?
-People are listening.
So you'll have to talk quietly
and I'll manage without the vases.
No, I don't get you. You took his
phone and snooped through the numbers?
A phone is personal.
-Come on, I'm really interested in the phone numbers
on Tzvi's phone. I was looking for
Yael's number, his wife.
Okay, but how can you do something like that
without talking to me?
Come on, what? Now maybe I need to
ask you for permission to breathe?
Okay, I'm asking you to promise me
that you'll never do things like this.
You're getting involved with my friends on your own.
Shai, Tzvi is a friend of both of ours.
And if he feels comfortable hanging out all night,
and using my kitchen without a care,
then I don't count him or you at all.
Riki, this can't go on like this.
You're always interfering in their lives.
Are you raising a black flag?
-No,
but this is already an invasion of their privacy, for crying out loud.
You don't get it, this is the modern world,
it's okay to interfere.
This generation has no secrets
or privacy. That's just how it is.
Everything is open on the internet, on Facebook.
Everything is transparent and visible.
You know what they say? Those who live in glass houses
shouldn't walk around naked. If you hadn't called me out,
it wouldn't have escalated into a bigger fight.
-But how long can I stay quiet?
You keep silencing me and in the end...
-Here, take a schnitzel.
Do you realize that even your picture here
is from your wedding with Smadar?
Babe, that's a great picture of me
and I'm alone here, Smadar isn't here.
That's my mom who put it there.
-Does it bother you that I'm not here
or that your mom thinks
I'm with you because I'm after your money?
Come on, babe, I don't want to fight.
-You're acting like a little kid.
Said the little girl.
-They called! From the daycare,
they said you forgot a pacifier.
-Okay, come on, come on, come on.
Go back to the nursery you crawled out of.
-Is this a grown-up argument for you?
I thought we were lowering ourselves to your level.
-No, we're lowering to your level...
Go eat mashed baba.
-Idiot.
And how we laughed at your dumb sister-in-law.
-Dumb?
At least she's not as dumb as your Aunt Amalia.
Amalia's not dumb.
It's something you're born with.
You know, overall we're good together.
It's not as bad as it seems.
True.
-I'm crazy about you.
And I'm crazy about you. Okay, we need to fight a bit. Right?
Every sea needs a few waves.
It's good for the surfers.
It's a principle. Because even if we're a couple,
everyone decides on their own friends.
Tell me, don't you understand that when you
give him shelter, you're no longer a friend,
because then he knows he has somewhere to escape
and takes advantage of it
instead of going and confronting his wife.
What kind of friend are you?
One who opens the door when someone knocks.
And if he needs a shoulder, he gives...
He gives everything.
Forget it, the last image didn't work for me
but you get the idea.
-For you, it's fine if he doesn't go home,
right? Cool for you, let them hang out all night,
laugh, whine together,
gossip about me. Why not?
-Shai, enough, enough. Really, I love you,
I love you. Let's not fight, okay?
I think you shouldn't have interfered,
you think differently...
-I can't take it, I don't want to hear you anymore.
Don't you notice how you
keep hurting me in front of everyone?
If you don't want to be with me, Itamar,
then don't be with me.
Tell me, what happened, did you change tactics?
Did you switch to whining?
I'm not whining at all, I'm just
saying maybe your mom is right,
maybe it's better if you really go back to Smadar
because she's much more mature
!she gets along with mom way better
-Okay, babe...
Don't call me babe!
Am I interrupting?
We're in the middle of a fight.
Sorry, I have nowhere else to be.
-Did something happen?
Okay, leave her alone.
Let's go continue somewhere else.
-I'm done.
I'm not!
-I am!
What, you're not leaving me in the middle of a fight.
Itamar, come here!
Itamar, come here! Itamar!
So you're saying you usually stay quiet and don't respond?
Yeah, because I choose not to fight with you.
So why this time?
-Because this time you went too far.
Alright, fine, I won't interfere anymore.
-Thanks, Riki.
Turns out she called his wife
not to make peace between them,
but for her own personal interest
which is that he won't be at our house anymore.
Shai, there's no such thing as no interests.
If you pay attention, you'll see that everything Shani does
is out of self-interest.
-You're interfering again.
Pinchas, enough with that!
-I'm fed up.
Fine, you don't have to. Go find something else to do.
How rude!
-What nonsense!
Do you really think it's okay to involve
my mom in every argument we have?
Look at that. When it comes to your mom
suddenly you lose your tact.
And why do you need to involve...
Excuse me for a second.
Why do you need to involve Smadar in every argument?
Smadar the saint.
-She's my ex-wife.
Maybe she'll be your future wife too.
-Just so you know, you're starting to annoy me
Level nine on the Itamar scale.
Oh, yeah, maybe you should get down from the scale
you climbed, Itamar,
and look at me a bit and see how much you're hurting me.
Like, do you even love me?
Mom!
What?
-Look, she's interfering again.
No, we can't do this here. Come on.
-What a shame.
At least you're as happy as I am?
-At least our happiness
doesn't come at the expense of others.
How rude!
-What nonsense!
I'm dying.
-Unbelievable.
Who needs this babysitter?
-No one can tell me in my own house not to interfere.
See you later.
-Thanks for everything.
Bro, I'll talk to you tomorrow. Thanks, Pinchas.
Bye.
Ben, you see? They left on good terms.
Yeah, look at that, Riki.
They managed to get along and make up.
Great, because I'm starving.
Babe, I'm sorry if I said
a word here and there that I shouldn't have,
sorry, and I love you a lot.
-How much is a lot?
There are no words to describe how much.
Babe.
You see, Pinchas, sometimes you need to interfere.
It's not always right to stand on the sidelines.
-Okay, I get it.
Sorry, you're right, I'm an idiot.
-Just like your son, he turned out to be an idiot too.
I'm sorry.
Oh, all the men apologized. Let's sit down to eat.
How did you manage to fight again?
-I don't know, we left your mom's,
got in the car, and suddenly we started fighting.
That's exactly when we made up.
-No, I just can't believe it.
I'm not going home. Permanently.
-You want to come to our place.
Yeah.
-No, no, no.
The whole house is exhausted,
at least give us one night without your...
that.
-What, is it really bothering you? Huh?
Not really.
-But yes. Yes.
You want, I can take you
to a hotel nearby?
No, no, no, no. Just drop me off at home,
I'll try to sort this out with her.
-Great.
It's also cheaper.
-Of course.
Don't be a man, no, be a man,
don't be a sucker.
It's okay, bro, the birthday was next month.
Last month.
Which month?
I don’t get it, what were you even fighting about?
-No.
...Sorry.
Go eat some porridge,
Go eat a mashed banana!
Go eat something you can have without teeth!
Porridge?
There's nothing to be done, Dad! The color is too bright.
Why, Riki, specifically about this?
I’ll tell you exactly what I pushed.
She married him at a very young age, very young.