I don’t get what your problem is
that I asked Shai and the girls to sit aside for a bit.
You don’t get that you don’t start with me when he’s around?
I’m the problem for her.
Ugh!
It was only seven meters.
Come on, stop whining.
Seven meters is fine, but why outside the umbrella?
Why am I carrying an umbrella all day
if in the end I can’t sit in the shade?
I told you to put on sunscreen.
Meirav, do me a favor, I’m all burnt because of you,
so don’t start with me.
I don’t need it anymore.
Did you see how that guy with the paddles started with me in the end?
Seriously, it was because you took their ball
and didn’t want to give it back.
He did it to me
because he was too shy to talk to me.
He would’ve written down my number if he had a place to do it.
He just didn’t bring his phone to the beach.
-Okay, okay,
guys, enough, ceasefire.
Don’t say fire, I’m burning up.
Alright, friends, we need to focus on the mission,
we’re getting close to the target.
House rules at the Rosen family:
Compliment Riki a lot, finish everything on your plate,
say everything is delicious, and most importantly, no fighting.
I know, I know.
I wasn’t talking to you, I was talking to Shai.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Hello.
I’m starving, dying here.
Please go to the balcony,
don’t fill my house with sand.
What, why not the shower?
-Pinchas is in there,
he’s had enough of your visits to his shower.
-Yeah, right, right.
Barefoot, I hope you didn’t bring tar, okay?
-No, no.
Hi, Riki.
-Meital.
Meirav
come here
I didn’t know you’d come with them from the beach.
Why, I told you she’d come.
-No, you didn’t.
You said
-you repressed it.
Well, what does it matter?
We have guests, that’s what matters.
So how are you?
-I’m good, thanks.
Nothing new.
-It’s okay, it’ll be fine.
Go to the balcony, I’ll bring you drinks, okay?
Can we have some of the little schnitzels too?
You’re a schnitzel yourself, why are you so burnt?
Why did we buy you an umbrella
if you’re not using it?
Come on, come on.
-Alright, let’s go.
Hello.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom.
Hello.
Hey there.
-Itamar, hi.
What’s up? I was really worried, where have you been?
Nowhere, why?
Riki, you know we were out this week, we just popped by...
Sorry, wait, I have something in the kitchen right now.
Okay, don’t make a mess for me
because Mom is coming to pick you up soon
and don’t get dirty now.
No, I’m dying, you’re really turning into your mom.
Ouch, why insult?
-Don’t get dirty now?
What, you think I care?
I just can't deal with Smadar the sergeant
giving me a hard time.
No, I knew it, I knew you don't really care
how your kids look.
I can't believe you.
No, I don't get it, are you mad at me
because I care or because I don't?
Because I totally don't understand where you're going with this.
Wait, wait, wait,
Is it that time of the month
when you're...?
No, it's not, and I'm not mad
because you don't care about the kids,
I'm mad because I care about her.
My mom?
-Your ex-wife.
About Smadar?
-Yeah, about Smadar.
Don't you realize how much you're investing in her?
Dressing the kids for her,
feeding them veggies because she asked,
And don't think I didn't see
how you checked the little one's homework this week.
Tell me, what, are you normal?
Smadar asked me to keep an eye on them,
And besides, I didn't understand anything.
They don't teach math normally anymore.
You know there are no more fractions?
Yeah, really.
There aren't.
Don't change the subject, where was I?
So everything she asks you, you just do?
You have no backbone at all?
What?
Honey, honey, enough, be reasonable.
Smadar is the mother of my kids,
she can't just
disappear from my life one day.
So with all the pain, and believe me it hurts
me way more than it hurts you,
I have to do everything
my ex-wife asks me.
Your wife?
-Former. My ex-wife.
I have to do what she asks
because she's my ex-wife,
because you're my future wife, for now.
I love you.
Did you see how she looked at me? She hates me.
Honey, come on, please,
she doesn't hate you,
she just feels sorry for you.
Meirav, enough, be positive, okay?
Here, I brought you drinks,
Pinchas finished in the shower so you can go in.
First in the shower.
-Tell me, what's wrong with you? Are you a kid?
Shiko, let the girls go first.
-Come on, girls, let's go in,
on tiptoes, so you don't get sand on Grandma.
Good thing the bathtub is close,
so we don't fill your house with sand.
Come on.
Do you think she meant our house is small?
-No, no, no,
You didn't understand her at all.
She said that because of the...
evil eye, that's how it is for them.
Why didn't you tell me you were bringing her?
I would have made something special for Meirav.
I'm going to defrost some schnitzels.
-And you didn't bring me any.
You leave me alone like a dog.
Do you want me to buy the necklace...
Hey, what's up? What's going on?
-All good, everything's fine.
The kids are dressed up.
You have good taste in dressing up, Smadar.
Sand, sand, you're bringing in so much sand here.
Sand, shells, water, seaweed, tar, jellyfish.
Honey, it was an accident, honey.
-I'm not mad at her.
You're not.
-No, I'm not.
She sees me once a year,
she can mix up my name,
Of course, if she’s always
hearing her ex-husband’s wife’s name.
What did I do wrong now?
Honey, Smadar is Itamar's ex-wife.
Enough
what’s your ex-wife’s name, Oz?
_Mochal Meirav.
Well, why should I be blamed for his serial marriages?
I see her once in a while too...
And it’s always near their mom’s questionable food.
I hope she doesn’t serve the...
What are those little ones called?
-Shlayklech?
There are knaidlach inside, right?
Who the hell serves this horror?
Okay, okay, relax,
I’m going to get clothes for the girls,
Watch the girls and watch your mouth.
I said, for crying out loud, give me a break.
-Meirav, enough.
Well, well.
What are you doing?
-Nothing.
I’m looking for a comb or something,
I’ll comb you nicely.
Crap.
-What happened?
Nothing happened.
This will be our little secret.
What’s that smell?
-Smell...
Great.
We’ll be in the shower again soon, girls.
I said I’m sorry
!I meant it. Talk to me already.
Talk to your wife.
-You’re my wife.
Am I supposed to know that, Itamar?
Because we hang out together every night?
Because you enjoy being with me? Because of the sex?
What does that have to do with anything now?
I want to be your wife, honey,
not just the one you hang out with.
What, you want me to suffer with you?
Because you’re on the fast track, honey.
It’s not funny to me,
maybe being your third wife would be funny.
You won’t believe it, Itamar and Michal
are having a crazy fight over AS-IX.
Sex?
-What?
Nothing, honey, nothing, it’s for adults.
What’s going on? Did something happen? There’s a bad smell here.
Nothing, we just showered.
What did you shower with, a branch from the Super-Pharm?
You’re not being reasonable. It slipped out,
I can’t be responsible for all my slip-ups.
Yeah, I already know that.
Okay, enough, that’s it,
now you’ve annoyed me. Enough, stop,
We’re done, that’s it,
I’m really willing to go very far with you,
I’m willing to grovel,
I’m willing to tell you I love you,
But now you’ve gone too far.
Why are you yelling like that?
-She went too far.
We have a guest here.
Thanks, Riki, but I don’t see myself as a guest.
I meant Meirav.
I’m not ready for her to go to Shai’s parents.
!Say we’re yelling here.
You know how they love to talk,
they can’t keep their mouths shut.
Shabbat Shalom, I don’t have much time
because I have a date with a pair of twins.
No one wants to hear about your girls,
we have a guest here.
Worth it?
-Meirav.
Shabbat Shalom and see you later.
-Adam.
How’s it going?
-Hey there.
We just got back from the beach.
-Hey, Meirav.
What...
How are you?
-Great, thanks.
So, can you tell I got some sun?
What are you doing here?
The sun keeps moving on me.
Thanks, thanks.
I'm starving, this is really making me hungry.
Flipping over?
-No,
The smell of my skin is making me crave shawarma.
I'm dying of heat here.
Are they done in the shower?
-Shani's still in there.
I'm in trouble because at this rate, the sun's moving!
I'll be here until noon, no doubt.
Enjoy!
-Thanks.
Is this still taken?
-It's coming, it's coming.
Have you seen my aftershave?
-No.
It's not here.
I don't get why she buys
that air freshener,
it stinks. Do me a favor, sit down,
no matter what you did, don’t use it next time.
It’s not me, Pinchas.
You won’t believe the scene I had at the beach.
I just had a Diet Coke,
you know, it has
the worst burps,
maybe except for dark beer.
Hey, also dark soda.
Do you think dark drinks
make more burps?
So, who took my aftershave?
Adam?
-What?
Oh, come on, why would I use
your garbage juice? I just got here.
What are you playing?
Am I breaking the record?
-What?
He’s breaking his own record.
Oh, nice, show me for a sec.
-Why?
Good thing you came, I was about to be roasted.
Yeah, honestly, you really look ready.
How's your sister?
-You wouldn’t believe it.
So far, she’s managed to insult your mom,
call Michal Smadar,
ruin Raz's record in the game,
not counting the accumulated calls to Adam.
So we’re optimistic.
-And cautious.
It was a really good idea to bring her.
-Thanks.
Alright, go. Go take a shower.
Why?
Do you need help with something?
No, no, no, everything's great, all set here.
We're glad you came
with short notice or no notice at all.
You know, you don’t have to go out of your way for me.
What do you mean because of you and what do you mean go out of my way?
Excuse me, I’ll be right back.
I’ll keep an eye on the tsimmes.
Oh no,
Shloimel.
Hey, sweetie.
Of course, I hate that this happens.
How about you help Grandma Riki with the food?
-What?
Oh, did you get that?
We can make a salad.
Here, this is your knife.
Your whole family is so careful and considerate with her.
Why again?
She's actually a really nice girl inside.
Dad, do me a favor, don’t get involved, okay?
What’s so nice about her?
She kind of scares me.
-Scares you?
No, of course not, but...
I mean a little.
I'm afraid she'll go tell her mom everything.
What?
-What about her mom now?
What about her mom now, huh?
Don’t you remember what happened on Rosh Hashanah?
-Where were you on Rosh Hashanah?
Wait, wait, wait, who are you talking about?
-About Meirav, the one here.
We were talking about Smadar.
-Smadar.
Oh, Smadar,
it would have been so much easier
if she brought her sister.
See?
You see? It’s already passed.
And we don’t need to tell anyone about it ever, okay?
What’s with Meirav, what happened to her?
The girl? She got cut a little.
What do you mean she got cut? Did you give her a knife?
She’s too little.
-Okay, come on, how was I supposed to know?
Besides, don’t worry,
it’s fine, I talked to her about it.
What do you mean you talked to her?
She won’t tell, we said it’s our little secret.
Secret? Did you even explain to her what a secret is?
Didn’t I do well?
-No, Meirav, no. She’s a little girl.
Little kids, when something happens to them
they need to tell their parents.
And not keep secrets with strange adults.
-I didn’t think about that.
Oh, great.
I’ll go talk to Itamar about this.
No, no, no, I already messed up with his wife earlier,
let me handle this,
I’ll explain to the girl that I was wrong.
You’ll see, everything will be fine,
it’ll be our little secret.
Okay.
What was that?
-I don’t know.
I’m in the middle of something.
-No, Dad...
Shai, seriously, you broke my aftershave.
I didn’t mean to, it was already broken.
What are you, a kid?
I heard you behind the door breaking it.
But Dad, what are you...
Riki.
-Come on, close the door, Dad.
Sit.
By the way, I talked to Smadar this week.
-No, I’m dying.
Enough, Mom, you’re killing me,
we’re divorced, that’s enough already.
Of course.
She said you’re a good dad.
-Very nice.
Why are you following her? Let her be alone for a bit.
No, I don’t think so.
-You, don’t get involved.
Sorry.
So, are we eating today too?
-Excuse me for a moment.
If you had acted like that with Smadar,
maybe you wouldn’t have separated.
I found it.
-What?
The aftershave.
-Too bad.
Oh no.
- Shai broke it for me.
What?
- Yeah, broke it, broke it.
Did he know it was the last one?
Okay, fine, Riki,
no need to dance on his conscience.
I’ll buy you a new one, okay?
But it’s not possible,
the company that made those aftershaves
went bankrupt five weeks ago.
No big deal, just get a new one,
I love new scents too,
I put it on myself
and imagine I’m someone else.
Bonjour, it’s from Apple Breeze.
Pinchas is a bit more conservative.
- Okay, it’s just a scent
and to be honest, it wasn’t that great.
Meirav, are you crazy?
That’s been his scent since they met.
Now you’re stepping into a minefield.
Riki, what Meirav meant, basically,
is to just soften the blow, yeah,
so it’s not that bad it happened,
not that it stinks or anything! Like, right?
- Of course.
Didn’t you say you wanted
to tell a story to the kids on the balcony?
Yeah.
Kids, come to the balcony, I have a surprise.
But why is it like this? You didn’t get divorced?
Of course, babe, I divorced her,
but my mom hasn’t yet.
Why aren’t you doing something?
What do you want me to do?
Get divorced from my mom?
Not talk to my mom anymore?
- No, but...
So to reduce the friction
I do everything Smadar asks me to,
discipline, cleanliness, order. Just to avoid
her calling my mom
and then you get more trouble from her.
So all this because you’re struggling
with your mom’s nonsense?
- No, but...
So my mom just brings up
Smadar’s name again,
you see how she treats her,
and then you get annoyed.
- Yeah, but...
And I don’t want you to get hurt by all this nonsense
that has nothing to do with you, babe.
What, so all this is my fault?
- Not because of you, babe,
for you.
- For me?
Of course, babe.
So basically, it’s for you that you’re hysterical
that the kids won’t get dirty?
- Of course, babe,
it’s all for you, I love you.
Babe.
- Let it be quiet
Babe
This chocolate is not a secret,
and if you want, you can
tell your parents everything,
and there are no secrets between us, okay?
Okay.
- Okay.
More.
Let’s see what I have left.
Here.
- Thanks.
And I just want to remind you
that if you want candies and surprises from me
next time we meet,
then it’s better not to tell your parents what happened.
But you don’t have to,
you can choose to tell and not get chocolate
or not tell and get it.
Wait, wasn’t that you?
- No, it wasn’t me, I swear,
it was rolled in a towel.
Meirav.
K'
Meiravi
Beni
That's why it smelled like air freshener.
She's good.
-Oh my God.
Say, do you think we can...
-A little longer, just a bit more.
Well, at least nothing happened to me.
-Yeah.
The shleikelar?
Of course.
-Great.
I know exactly what to do
so she won't want to come here anymore.
Thanks.
Smadar loved my shleikelar so much.
No, I'm dying.
-Forget it, babe, half an hour and it's over.
Aya.
Did you cut yourself on the glass?
-Yeah, but not deep because it went through the flip-flop.
You need to disinfect it with alcohol.
-No, it's already sanitized.
That was my last bottle.
-Dad, it's not me,
It's from...
-Enough, Shai.
I'll check online where to get one of those.
What is it?
Why are they... no way.
-What happened?
Why are they so dirty?
Nonsense, it's chocolate,
it washes out, I know about this.
You know about laundry?
-What?
I know about chocolate.
I can't believe this...
Thank you so much really.
What do I say to Smadar now?
Smadar?
-No, no, no, no.
I liked calling her Smadar-malda.
-Smadar?
Now.
-Not yet.
Are we eating today too?
-Yeah, come on.
I really love all these stews.
I defrosted a shleikelar for you-
-Yeah, I know.
Do you already smell it?
-Yeah. I peeked in the kitchen
and saw them in the pot, but you forgot to add spices.
-Just a bit.
Now?
-Not yet.
Bode?
R, do you have
what is it, coach, Mo
Meirav.
-She's in the cut.
What in...
What do I say to Smadar now?
No, that's what you have to say
instead of asking your daughter if she's okay?
If I ask, what will she answer me?
...iPhone?
Okay. Sweetie, are you okay?
I told you.
-What did she say?
That her stomach hurts,
she wants to call mom on the iPhone.
What stomach?
Tell me, are you normal?
Did you cut her in the stomach too?
No, of course not, I just gave her a little chocolate.
With milk?
-I think so.
Not good.
Now?
-Not yet.
Here’s the shleikelar.
Be careful, it's hot.
What happened to the shleikelar?
-It's mujaddara.
Watch out, she's throwing up.
Now.
On this occasion, I want to say
that I don't think I'll be here next week,
we're going on vacation.
Do you think your parents noticed
that you said you’re going?
Because it was a total mess there.
Yeah, we’re counting on it.
What do you mean?
-No, nothing.
You really didn’t tell them I’m coming.
Of course, and we purposely went to the beach first.
Oh, it was a little trick, good job.
No...
Wait, so basically you’re using me.
What? No way, who’s using you?
You owe me
-What?
How much?
-More.
To...
Fine, okay, more.
-Alright.
You need to, you need to look at him completely.
There are crackers inside, right?
It’s here
-without here
No, she didn’t say here
-let’s go back to the beginning of the sentence.
No, I’m dying.
Here are the sliders. Be careful, they’re hot.
Sorry, sorry.
The sliders.
You’re killing me inside, Sabrine.