What happened? Why are you so deep in thought today?
No, just kidding, just kidding.
Honestly, I wanted to tell you something.
-It's a statement like an earthquake in the middle of the ocean.
Right after that, you know a tsunami is coming.
What's the deal?
-Remember I told you
this week I'm going for coffee
with Meirav and Michal?
-I remember.
So it wasn't really like having coffee at a café.
We went to some fortune teller at a café.
Reading coffee?
-Fortune teller at a café.
How much sugar?
Ben, what... since when do you believe in that nonsense?
Well, I don't believe in that nonsense,
but she's really considered quite popular,
and honestly, there was something strong there,
with her. Really, something genuine, weird.
-So what do you have to tell me?
What did she tell you? Sorry, what did she say?
First of all, she said I'm a
really cynical girl and that I don't believe,
usually, in these things.
-And you paid her for that?
Oh, babe, stop. She told me
three mysterious things would happen to me
this weekend, and only if those things
happen, then I'll come back and pay her.
Nice.
-Yeah, yeah. You know what she told me?
One, the gift will be harmed by black light.
What?
-What, Shai, it's a gift.
What, and...
-The second thing, you'll drown in many waters until you can't see.
And the third, you'll scream for help against the supernatural.
Good thing you didn't pay her. At least there's no money wasted.
Yeah, I paid 300 shekels for Meirav.
But she'll pay me back.
-Enough..
Tell me, do you think Meirav
is like the injury from the black light?
No, Meirav is more like a black hole.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shlomo!
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
It's you guys.
-Shabbat Shalom, with respect.
What, is it bad that you came?
-No, I'm just eagerly waiting for Uncle Shlomo.
I haven't seen him in three weeks.
-We see you every week.
So maybe we should start coming once
every few weeks, so you miss us a bit too.
Oh, you just got here and already complaining?
-Not complaining.
It's humor, Riki, who's complaining?
-So what, is Uncle Shlomo coming?
Will it be fun?
-What's your problem with Uncle Shlomo?
I have no problem with him.
I'm just hinting he has a dull life
and boring stories.
-He doesn't have a dull life. He has a stable life.
He's happily married, works at a bank,
has a steady job. What's wrong with that?
Nothing wrong, excellent, excellent.
I'm just saying maybe he should
be an anesthesiologist.
-What a flower.
Hey, Pinchas...
-Uh..
Seriously now, would you define Uncle Shlomo as a black hole?
Gray light, a more accurate description.
Oh, I just hope Shai didn't go to the kitchen to snack.
What, Mom, no eggs?
-No. I didn't have time.
I only made things that Uncle Shlomo really loves.
What does he love?
-Gizzards, tongue, izisala...
Izis... remind me.
-Chicken stuffed with sweet zucchini.
Who puts sweet zucchini inside chicken?
You haven't even tasted it and you're already
scrunching your nose. When our grandma,
blessed be her memory, made it,
we all stood in line.
In line. So we stood in line for everything, it was the
golden age.
It wasn't that great in history.
-No, because that's when they invented history.
Let's eat tongue. What, what...
איך...
שבי, מה, מה קורה?
-לא, זה, סתם.
הייתי השבוע אצל מתקשרת.
-אוי, שבי, באמת...
כן, האמת, פנחס שגם אבי חושבת
שזה חארטה בארטה אבל...
זאת ממש עבודת אלילים. הם מלחיצים
אותך, אחר כך משגעים לך את השכל,
ואת יוצאת משם עם הרבה יותר
דאגות בראש, פחות 300 שקל בכיס.
בו ומה, איך היא הפחידה אותך?
היא אמרה לי שיקרו לי בסוף השבוע הזה
שלושה דברים מסתוריים.
אני לא יודעת למה לצפות אפילו.
-תעשי מה שריקי תמיד אומרת,
תצפי לרע ביותר ואז תמיד תופתעי לטובה.
שבת שלום.
-שבת שלום.
אימא...
-הוי
יש שביצלים?
-אה, זה אתם, אה...
מה נשמע?
-בסדר.
מה עובר על אימא?
-מה, מתרגשת. אחיה צריך לבוא.
לא נכון. דוד שלמה בא?
-מה רע בזה?
הוא זה החלום הרטוב של אימא.
היא תמיד חלמה שהילדים שלה
יהיו כאלה בסדר. וכל פעם שהוא מגיע לכאן,
אנחנו יוצאים כאלה לא מוצלחים לידו.
-תגיד לי, איתמר,
מאיפה השטויות האלה? מה,
הכנת את המונולוג הזה בדרך?
מה פתאום, פנחס,
בדרך התעסקתי במשהו אחר לגמרי.
במה?
-אני מחפשת לי שם חדש.
לא נכון.
-כן נכון, היא מחפשת שם חדש
כי היא הלכה למתקשרת והמתקשרת אמרה
לה שהיא חייבת להחליף את השם שלה.
מה, גם את היית אצל מתקשרת?
-כן, היינו ביחד.
כן, היינו ביחד,
ולה היא אמרה משה בגימטרייה.
כן, מיכל בגימטרייה זה 100 בדיוק,
וזה לא מספר מספיק חזק.
היא אומרת שהרבה יותר עדיף לי 88.
100 זה לא חזק?
-מסתבר.
ואני ממש מבקשת, עד שאני אמצא לי
שם חדש, אם אפשר להימנע מלקרוא לי.
תודה. אז לך כבר קרה
מה שהיא אמרה שיקרה לך, שבי?
אולי, זה מעורפל מדי.
אי אפשר ממש לדעת. אין שם.
מי מחליף שם בגיל כזה?
-אבל, מאמי, היא אמרה שזה יחליף לי את המזל.
תגידי לי, מה את חושבת, שהמזל דביל?
הוא לא יודע שזאת את, שזאת מיכל?
לשם הפרטי יש משמעות ממש עמוקה.
זה לא סתם צירוף אותיות.
היא אמרה שלכן אומרים "בעזרת השם"
ולא נגיד "בעזרת השם משפחה".
את יודעת מה, אם כבר, מי שצריך
להחליף את השם שלו במשפחה הזאת
זאת את, שבי.
באמת
כי השם שלך הוא הרי במפורש אומר שבי!
מה לקחת אותה לשם, מה?
-לא, לא, סליחה. זאת היא לקחה אותי
ולי היא לא אמרה בכלל לשנות את השם.
חוץ מזה, שבי זה אדום חזק.
צ'ייבג'.
-אתם יודעים, אם אימא הייתה משנה
את השם שלה לחלילה, אז על הדלת היה כתוב:
כאן גרים בכיף
פנחס וחלילה רוזן.
אני הולך לבדוק מה קורה עם השביצלים.
למה לעשות מזה כזה עניין גדול?
-דווקא אני מבין אותו, מיכל.
פתאום הוא 'היה בשן' למישהי אחרת
ובסוף הוא עוד יתפוס את עצמו
בבגידה עם אשתו.
מי?
-משהו
מה זה?
-אימא הכינה את כל המאכלים שדוד שלמה אוהב
ושכחה שגם אנחנו מגיעים לארוחה.
-יש המון אוכל
ואם לא תאהבו את מה שהכנתי,
נוציא מהמקפיא. יש שם אוכל לשנה.
טוב, זוז, זוז מהלשון. תן לי.
הוא אחי התאום
ואני מרגישה מחוברת אליו. אוקיי?
אתם אף פעם לא תדעו מה זה קשר בין אחים.
אה, אימא...
-תאומים.
בסדר, אבל שניצל, אימא.
תקשיבו, אני מבינה
שהוא לא כל כך מעניין אתכם,
But I'm asking you, on Sunday he's going back
to school, so behave! Here and at home.
Somehow that phrase echoes from my childhood.
Yeah, yeah, she would also add
that threatening look of the...
Do it, do the threatening look, Mom. Go on, son.
I don't get it. How did I end up with such flower boys?
It must be Pinchas's genes,
that's his dominant destructive gene.
Here, that's the look.
Uncle Shlomo?
-Hi, Pinchas.
You haven't changed, you look as bad as always.
Say, this elevator is always broken, right?
I took the stairs out of fear of that height.
It's so hot here, I'm sweating like a Trojan horse.
So maybe take off the jacket. This isn't Europe.
A new suit I bought in Paris, 700 euros.
The seller wouldn't let me leave the store without it.
What do you think?
-Stunning.
Is that the bride of the eldest?
Sit down
'sit
and Michal.
-Do you come here often?
Nice husband.
-Thanks, also from Paris.
How tough those French are.
Good thing they have their own country,
otherwise they'd want us to return Netanya.
Shlomo.
-Raccoon
Shai and Itamar. As if you’re not growing up,
as if you’re Peter Pan
and Tinkerbell sprinkled magic dust on you.
Tinkerbell?
-Calm down, it’s with a "k." That’s already 100.
Shlomo, you’ve changed.
-Tell me...
I smell...
-What salad?
No way.
-Yes way!
Is that Uncle Shlomo over there?
-Did you see that?
No, no, something happened to him, he changed,
he became more colorful.
Colorful is a delicate word.
-I think he looks more like a chameleon.
He’s really not as boring as you said.
-I wonder how Mom is taking it.
Shai, turn on the light.
-Oh!
What happened?
-No, it’s nothing,
it’s just a scratch.
-The wait in the wound...
From the black light!
-From the black light.
No, I’m dying.
-That’s what she said.
What’s going on with you?
-I’m good.
I’m good, Riki. You won’t believe
what a change I’ve gone through in my life.
I see.
-What you see is just the tip of the iceberg.
Where do you want me to start?
-From the beginning. Where's Vera?
I left Vera.
-What, did you get divorced?
How do you say in Yiddish? Wow.
-Why?
For convenience. I wanted to move in with Alex.
Who's Alex? Do I know her?
-Alex is my life partner,
my boyfriend.
-Dad will turn in his grave.
Trust me, I advise him not to turn.
You never know what kinds of characters are out there at night...
Honey, I need to go there urgently.
-Come on, what, should I call to pay her? What do you think?
No, I’m saying it’s nonsense.
It’s just a coincidence. It’s not an injury.
It’s a small scratch.
-Maybe Uncle Shlomo is one of the curses.
What else was there?
-You’ll drown in many waters until you can’t see,
whoa...
-and scream for help against the supernatural.
Think! Whatever you want, the demons are already here.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Nice to meet you, Shai.
-Hey there.
Itamar.
-Pinchas.
Good, nice to meet you too.
Tom? What a beautiful name.
-Thanks.
His wife. I would introduce myself
but I'm in the middle of names.
Tom is Hebrewized?
-From what?
You tell me. I'm actually looking for a name.
Tom, that's such a lovely name, babe,
it's so full of innocence.
Are you looking for a name for a girl?
-No, for me.
How much does it add up to in gematria? Wait,
but Tom backwards is death.
Yeah, but I'm Tom with a "T."
-Oh, so backwards it's... Mot.
Cool. So, water is 40 plus... how much is Vav?
55.
-Really? So 40 plus 55...
No, no, together it's 55. Tom is 55.
Wasn't Uncle Shlomo supposed to arrive?
He's here, in the kitchen, with Mom, catching up.
Yeah, this could take a really long time.
Me, Riki, I had a terrible life.
If I hadn't done something!
with myself, I would have brought disaster upon me.
You can't imagine how
unsatisfied I was with Vera.
And now?
-Look at me!
Say, does anyone else know? Did you tell anyone else?
Mom knows?
-Mom knows. I think she always knew.
Look, moms, you don't need to tell them anything,
they pick up on their kids from half a meter away.
And there were signs beforehand, to...?
-Look, Riki,
she saw all the time how I switched girls
like batteries in a digital camera,
without focusing on any one.
So that's a hint?
-One of them.
I have to tweet that I arrived, so Alex won't worry.
I didn't want to bring him with me.
I said, one protest a day is enough.
Good call. Do you tweet a lot?
A ton.
-Where's the real Shlomo?
What did you do with him?
I heard about this psychic,
she's kind of a witch.
Honestly, I don't believe in that stuff,
I'm too much of a realist.
I didn't know you were so good at gematria.
What's good? I'm actually really good.
I understand it too,
but in reality, it doesn't help anyone.
-Yeah, so what other names are there for 88?
Uh... Isis
-Isis?
Babe, can I ask you something for a second?
-Just a sec.
Babe, what do you think about Isis?
-What even is Isis?
Actually, Isis was an Egyptian goddess.
It's a pretty cool name.
You guys have to try the Isis salad.
-Oudia, that's a new one.
Adamika, hey.
-Uncle Shlomo?
Riki wants to tell you something.
-Dear family,
it turns out my brother Shlomo is gay.
-No way.
And I ask all of you to respect the occasion.
What...
-That's not...
What a surprise.
-I would never have guessed.
Thank you, thank you, thank you. Not that I'm being modest,
but it's not that big of a deal.
What happened two years ago
at the conference, Alex alone, looking for a loan on
good terms to open a curtain store,
and since then we've been tied to the index.
-You have a curtain store?
"Shmamelon." Alex came up with the name, Shmamelon.
We even have a website:
"shmamelon dot com."
Honestly, I really need a curtain.
How do you spell "Shmamelon"? Is it with...
Just like it sounds, with everything you need.
Who are you?
-Oh, sorry, I'm Tom,
I'm dating Adam, nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you.
Unbelievable, this Uncle Shlomo, huh?
Tell me, are you really... aren't you scared?
Babe, I'm begging you, don't get into this.
What’s black light? What, a hole in the fire?
What, is it on purpose, all these
tricky insurances,
so you can understand everything from them?
What, what does supernatural even mean?
No, no, before the supernatural
comes "you'll drown in many waters until you can't see."
Was that a tsunami or are we in for a surprise tomorrow morning?
With the little ones at the pool and chlorine in my eye?
What?
-Come on, babe, come on, it’s 300 shekels.
Come on, let me call and pay her with my Visa.
-It’s a coincidence.
Tell me, is Adam multi-sexual?
-Multi?
You know, that girl he’s dating...
It’s the first time I’m seeing her.
She said her name is Tom,
and I’m telling you she wasn’t born Tom.
What are you trying to say?
I think she used to be Thomas. Thomas the Tank Engine.
Made a lot of smoke.
Do you think Adam knows she has a chimney?
I just checked her out quickly.
-Oh!
That’s how it is, a guest for a moment sees every flaw.
Oh, good you’re back. Shai, do you have another name at 88?
Maybe a flower name?
-Gladiolus.
What Gladiolus?
-88, bro.
Gladiolus?
-Yeah, you’re totally Gladiolus.
K'
Beni
Pinchas?
-Yeah.
Can you come here for a sec, please?
Sure.
-So good to see you all.
Tell me, Tom,
they say
if you look at him, Naor
you look familiar to me. Where were you in the army?
In Golani.
-Tough times, huh?
No kidding. What, you were in Golani too?
No, but I had a friend who would come back
with rashes from the Golani trips.
We all used to tease him
"Povidicit" from the public.
For sure.
-He would scream like a turkey.
And his wattle would turn red,
you’ve never seen anything like it.
Believe me, I’ve seen it all.
-I didn’t think otherwise.
Rangori
K'
Beni
Did you feel something weird about Adam?
-No.
Shlomo says he might be gay too.
Why? Is he in Shlomo’s office?
-What does Shlomo have to do with it?
But Shlomo knows about this stuff.
-Oh, what nonsense!
He’s out all day with girls
one prettier than the next,
is that gay? Really, Riki.
Shlomo says he knows it from himself! That it’s a sign,
he also says that Tom...
she is that.
-That?
that she used to be a man.
-Oh!
Rivka, what happened to our world?
-Take some cold water.
R Betuch'
once iz y -
taganden to him, Tomula, ashner]
What secure?
-Eyelid lift,
lip fillers,
circumcision?
Circumcision is a beautiful name. You know?
-612.
Itamar, come, come! Sorry, nothing happened.
What "nothing happened"? Dad,
you spilled water on me. Didn’t you see?
Come on, I’m dying, "many waters and you won’t see."
Wow! Wow, Shai, that’s the hint, many waters!
Seriously, one to one! Is this, is this many waters?
Itamar, do you know anything about Adam?
Maybe about his girlfriend?
What do you mean?
Uncle Shlomo says he thinks
that maybe Adam...
is gay.
You just made me laugh.
No, no, he also says that his girlfriend,
seems like she was a guy before.
Itamar knows about these things.
She’s not a guy!
Right?
-That’s what we’re trying to figure out.
Wait, are you sure it’s not just
in Uncle Shlomo’s crazy head?
Not at all.
Well, you know what, as long as Mom
doesn’t want us to be like Uncle Shlomo,
I’m fine with everything.
You’ll drown in deep waters. Drown.
Honey, these are hints, hints.
-Okay, okay.
Let’s say that’s true, alright?
-So?
Did she say what would happen if you don’t pay?
Not really.
-Okay.
What are you whispering about? Come eat already.
Coming, Mom, just a sec.
-Hey, if I’m already here,
could it be that this Tom was a guy before?
What? How did you get that? It’s not me, it’s Shlomo.
Turns out he’s an expert on this.
-What, is he a homologist?
What, does he have geometry? Does he use a joyoscope?
A flower, just a flower.
Hey... hey, cuties. Tell me, Adam,
do you like Eurovision?
Uncle Shlomo, what do you want?
-No, I don’t want anything.
I’m saying, who said you have to
live in couples? If it’s not working,
you don’t have to insist. Right, it worked on Noah’s Ark,
but since then everyone’s getting divorced.
Besides, what couples were there on the Ark?
The lion and the mammoth? The camel and the shibuta?
A hippopotamus, all alone.
Well, he was probably a single parent.
But who said we need a hippopotamus at home?
-Shlomo, I’ve lost a lot of weight.
Didn’t I say so?
-Come on, let’s go eat.
Shlomo.
-Please, Uncle Shlomo.
Here you go.
-Thank you very much. Thanks, thanks.
No, she’s not.
If it’s... it’s... then where is it?
You don’t want to know.
Tell me, tell me, but doesn’t it hurt when you sit down?
You get used to it.
-I don’t want to know.
Shai, what are they talking about?
-Why are you picking on me?
Ask...
-Why are you passing him to me?
Nothing, Adam.
-Come on, both of you!
Why now, when we’re about to eat?
-It’s important.
Girls, sit down, taste the tongue.
Yuck!
-Yuck!
Uncle Shlomo, do you have an idea for a name for me?
How fun it is to change your name.
-Right.
By the way, did you change yours?
-No. You?
Actually, I did. I’m not called Shlomo anymore.
-Really?
But let’s leave that. One surprise a day is enough.
What, Uncle Shlomo, why did you change?
-Why change the name?
How will you know what your name is?
-You know what, my dear,
I have an idea for you.
-Yeah?
What’s going on?
Is she a guy?
-What?
Or was she a guy before?
What are you talking about? Tell me, are you out of your minds?
Are you sure?
-What does "sure" even mean?
A hundred percent. What do you think,
that I'm that dumb?
Wait, wait, on this one you can't be wrong.
If you were with her in an intimate way,
then you know for sure.
I know for sure. Okay?
Really for sure.
What, do you think she... he...
Or...
I can get used to that name.
-Yeah. Honestly, it's a great idea.
It's genius.
-Honey, you changed the name.
Why?
-Because that's what I want.
-For Michal.
What, Michal?
-Not Michal. Michal, with a "chet."
Michal?
-That's 88.
!It has way better energy,
!This way I'll know they're calling me.
Michal!
-Yeah. See?
Okay, babe, cool. As long as you're not a guy,
I'm all for it.
Eating?
-Yeah, we're eating,
but before we eat
I want to ask a little question.
Go ahead.
-Tom,
have you ever been a guy?
What, are you kidding? Where'd you get that idea?
Just a simple intuition.
-Sorry for the blunt question, yeah.
Just my whole family wants to know. Are you a guy?
I can't believe it. Alright, I'm outta here.
Find yourself another ride to Tel Aviv.
-Cool. Are you a guy or not?
Tell me, does this look like a guy to you?
Wait a second. That doesn't tell me anything.
And does this look like a guy to you?
-Oh, my God.
I thought one surprise a day was enough.
Well, your mom yelling "Oh my God,"
is like "help" in Yiddish?
Correct me if I'm wrong.
-What do you even need a psychic for?
What are you missing in life?
-Honestly, I'm not missing anything.
What about the 300 shekels Meirav took?
-I consider that money
in shekels whose burial place is unknown.
Next time, take me with you to the psychic. Okay?
Maybe by some random chance
Meirav will return the money.
I wrote "faith." What does that mean?
What’s up with this, the wiper switch isn’t working.
It should be blue and this is black. What’s going on?
Turn it on... Ah!
What happened?
-I got cut by the switch.
What’s with this rain? I can’t see anything.
Help!
-What’s that?
No way! Uncle Shmuel is coming?
Shlomo.
-Shlomo.
Sorry.
-Shmuel is dead.
Flower.
Riki, don’t get mad...
And your mom yelling "Oh my God,"
is like "help" in Yiddish?
In Yiddish. Again...
Believe me, I've seen it all.
Wait, there was something with the...
-Totally, totally, totally.
Your mom yelled "Oh my God," which is like "help" in Yiddish.
He would come back with rashes from all the trips of the...
from the mishaps of the trip...
'Like
So when we would spray
him with "Fungicide" from the hose...
Fungicide. Right.