Oh no.
-What happened?
Ugh, I broke a nail.
Oh dear.
-What, are you making fun of me?
I'm not making fun, I just don't know
how you'll deal with the loss.
Very funny. I can't believe
I have to go to Lydia again.
I sat with her for two hours yesterday.
Why does this have to happen to me?
Why me?
-Like someone died.
No, it's worse. Okay?
-Tragic.
Now you'll have to deal
with the five stages of grief.
It's not grief.
-See? It starts with denial,
moves to anger, goes to bargaining,
continues with depression, and ends with acceptance.
It was tough, but you'll get through it with them.
Yeah, you heard about the five stages
of how to shut you up?
It starts with a slap, goes to a smack, flick, punch,
and finally a kick. It was tough,
but we'll get through this with you. Right, girls?
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Hello, hello.
Dad, you won't believe it. Dad, listen.
We just won a scratch card downstairs, at Yossi's.
How? It's Shabbat, closed.
-I found an unscratched scratch card on the sidewalk.
What are you talking about? The chances of that happening
are like... winning the lottery.
-Exactly. We won.
No way.
-Yes way!
For 2,500 shekels.
No way.
-Yes way.
I've been scratching with him for twenty years,
never won even once.
That's Shani's hand.
She scratched with the nail she broke...
Honey, bring me a scratch card
faster, faster.
What a hand. Gold.
Give me the card.
-Here you go.
What's this, honey?
They gave it to us at school and I forgot to show you.
It's the registration form for classes.
-How much will it actually cost
to send the girl to classes now?
2,500 shekels.
No way.
-Yes way.
Ben, D.
-He'll definitely call.
Ben, D, Meirav. Come on, better one.
Don't say that. He'll come back.
-But he said he wouldn't.
But he'll come back.
-Meirav, why can't you accept that?
At least he was nice enough to tell you to your face.
He won't come back.
-I'm telling you he will.
I'll call him.
-No, Meirav. He told you
under no circumstances to call him.
-Shabbat Shalom. You're not calling him!
Who did Grandma miss? Who?
I just finished making the mezilof.
I don't want to. Mom, I don't want mezilof.
-Neither do I.
What do you mean? What does "don't want mezilof" mean?
Girls, go play.
What happened?
-No, what a coincidence.
Shai brought mezilof from the supermarket.
-Mezilof?
Yeah, like this industrial mezilof.
Mezilof in a box?
-Yeah.
He actually brought it on Tuesday.
By Thursday, there was nothing left.
It's not as good as yours. Right?
That's obvious. There's no comparison at all,
but the kids actually liked it.
-Industrial mezilof?
Are you making fun of me?
-No, really, Mom.
He brought this from the supermarket's freezer.
It’s not fresh, but... frozen like that.
Quiet!
-What happened?
It’s fresh.
I told you he would call.
Hey. Which phone are you calling from?
I don’t recognize this number.
Oh..
Mistake.
Here, look at the card.
No, this isn’t real, it’s a nightmare.
Twenty that... I’m saying
I told you, there’s no way you’ll win.
He has a curse on his little booth.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
What’s with that face? Did you lose a scratch card?
What?
-He got the test results
and he doesn’t want to open them.
-Alin, enough.
On the phone?
-By email.
Come on, just open it already.
-I don’t want to!
What is this? What are "the results"?
-Of those tests,
that they told you about on Friday.
-Why did you even go for that test?
I didn’t want to. Alin forced me.
Here, now it’s official. The result is positive.
No way, that’s not true.
-Look for yourself.
It must be a mistake, it’s someone else’s, it’s not true!
I get it.
Poor guy. In denial.
The things people come up with these days.
No, I can’t believe it.
A frozen yogurt at the supermarket.
That’s the weirdest thing I’ve ever heard.
Yeah, it’s from "Mamazlof."
Shai is already waiting for the "Mamachalata" to come out.
So wait, they put it in the freezers?
How funny.
It’ll never work for them,
it won’t work. It’s not economical. No way!
No way.
I understand a thing or two.
It won’t catch on. Never.
It can never beat
home-cooked food. Never.
Of course not, Mom. Of course.
-Never.
Shhh...
-What’s up? What happened?
I thought the phone was vibrating.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
-What happened?
There was a mess with the computer.
-What did you do to it now?
Why me?
-So who?
She accidentally deleted the folders
of our photos on the computer.
What a sad story, Silvan.
Sit down, can you bring the letter for a sec?
Did you check the name of the sender?
Because he’s had a mess like this before.
Come on, that’s your daughter’s name.
Yeah.
Maybe last year’s date?
No.
Honey...
-Everything’s fine, Moshe.
We can recover it, I know we can.
I don’t know. Did you hear what Coral said?
What does Coral know?
There are people who are experts in these things.
Coral is an expert.
-Not just a school kid.
An expert, like a real expert.
-They’re the biggest experts out there, for real.
Moshe, we can recover it. I know we can.
I don’t know, babe, I don’t know.
Don’t tell me “I don’t know, babe.”
-Babe...
And don’t call me “babe.”
And don’t tell me it can’t be recovered.
Who are you to say that to me?
Why, do you understand computers?
If you were such a computer whiz,
you’d upload the pictures
from the camera to the computer every time.
But you don’t know how to do that, right?
I know how to do it, right?
I don’t get this stuff.
You know I don’t get...
It’s all your fault. Everything.
What am I supposed to do now, huh?
All our history is gone, everything is gone, everything.
And that technician... is she a computer expert?
What does she know? Did she even study anything?
Does she know anything about life?
Does she know anything about our whole lives that got erased?
This is the last time
she’s coming to the Knesset. The last time.
This is just outrageous. 2,500 shekels?
-Come on, isn’t that way more
than what we paid last year?
Thieves.
-They have no shame. And for what?
Really, for what?
They only have numbers in their heads.
-And the girl, she’s not learning anything there,
she’s not learning anything there.
-Nothing. You just give,
you don’t get anything back.
-And another 2,500 shekels?
They’re brainwashing the kids with math
like it’s the most important thing in the world.
Babe, it’s for extracurriculars.
-So that makes it even worse.
At least if they took the money,
they’d invest it in math, like they should.
The girl doesn’t even know her times tables by heart.
-Right.
You know that in enlightened countries
the state pays for those extracurriculars
to ensure the future of its citizens.
-Everything costs in this country.
You don’t get anything back.
-Exactly. As if we don’t have
anything to do with that money,
as if we don’t have other needs and expenses.
No, this isn’t real. You know
what we could buy with 2,500 shekels?
A floor vacuum.
-A 24-inch computer monitor.
Excuse me, a floor vacuum?
-Excuse me, a 24-inch computer monitor?
Call! Please, call.
Auntie, why are you sad?
Oh, my dear,
yeah, I’m a bit sad. You see,
sometimes adults feel pain in their hearts.
You know when you give
your all to someone,
put your heart and soul in their hands,
and what do they do with it?
They throw it away, like it means nothing,
to the time and experiences we shared together.
You know we barely went on a second date?
And he even tells me, “Don’t call me anymore.”
He tells me I won’t call him anymore.
That he won’t call me anymore.
Who needs him anyway?
To cut it off like that, so coldly?
Not even let me say a word?
There’s no way in the world
I’d agree to be with a guy like that.
And I even thought he’d be a husband.
He’s not worthy of me.
Why did you ask her?
What?
Rachel, I swear to you.
I don’t understand what you’re angry about.
They did a mess-up, Silvan. A mess-up.
Yeah, but... they managed to stick
a human ear on a mouse’s back.
They can’t do a mess-up?
-It’s all the big companies,
it’s just money, money, money.
And sell, sell as much as possible.
I wouldn’t be surprised if we soon
see ads for mess-ups on TV.
Well, that’s already in the freezers at the supermarket.
So why wouldn’t Mrs. Feigold
buy and serve a mess-up?
-So let her buy...
Mrs. Feigold, let her buy.
I still don’t understand what your problem is.
What's the problem? She doesn't know how to make it.
That's the issue. It's outrageous.
No respect for tradition. Nothing, nothing.
They make it in a factory, Silvan, in a factory.
This is poison. Who knows what they put in there?
I'm sure there's supervision on it.
I'm sure it's under rabbinical supervision.
Come on, don't get carried away. It's just junk...
And Shai, how can he not be embarrassed?
He, more than anyone, should know better.
Why, does he make it?
-No, he buys it.
He buys it.
You can't put all the love,
all the patience, all the values
into something that comes from a machine, Silvan,
a machine. You can't. It's machines, it's...
No need for humans, none. No need for humans.
A robot. A robot makes your junk, Silvan.
A robot. Not a human. A robot.
Enough, relax, relax.
Why? Why? Why am I losing my hair?
That's just how it is, babe.
-But why?
I'm asking myself why too.
-You won't believe how mad I am, Alin.
I can't believe you're mad
about things you can't change.
And it's not just me, Alin.
-Am I losing my hair too?
Stop making fun of me, okay? We're also talking
about genes I'm supposed to pass to my kid.
For heaven's sake, he's three weeks old,
now he's going to be bald too.
-He’s already bald.
Not now. When he grows up.
-Come on, really.
What's the point? What's the point?
I won't accept that.
-I don't think they’re asking you.
Excuse me.
-I won't accept that, Alin. Okay?
You're right. You're right.
I’m not willing to lose all our history
with one "delete."
No way, Moshe—
-There's nothing to be done, babe.
Is it about money?
-No.
If it's about money, I'll borrow from Shai.
But it's not about money, Beshmat.
-Call Coral again,
see what she says.
-But you've already talked to her, honey.
I talked. But sorry, it hurts me too.
You heard what she said.
You can't retrieve it from the hard disk,
you can't.
-But maybe there's something we can do,
maybe, maybe, call her again,
tell her I'm willing to pay any amount,
just to get our photos back.
We'll recommend her to so many people,
we'll send her clients. Moshe, we'll give her
a like on Facebook, whatever she wants.
But Beshmat, I'm explaining to you.
No, no, no. It's impossible.
It's impossible.
But I want you to talk to them.
Talk to who?
To the robots from "Mamzelof"? Who?
No, to the kids. I want you to tell them
that you're not okay with them buying it anymore.
Why? Why should I say that to them?
Because you don't know what's inside.
Junk... they put in date syrup.
Yeah, and maybe it's poison?
-I can't say that to them.
They want to eat it
even during the week. What's your problem?
Fine, then I'll make it for them
and they'll take it home.
Junk?
-Yeah.
For all I care, they can
freeze it and thaw it out.
They can also, for all I care,
say they bought it at the supermarket.
Just let me make it and you go
tell them not to buy it anymore.
Go. Now.
I... just don't feel good right now.
Silvan!
Please, God, help me.
-Help me.
I'm ready to do anything, please.
-Get a transplant.
Just give me a few more weeks,
I promise to do whatever it takes.
Sure.
-I'll start exercising.
Right.
-Come on.
I'll put on tefillin.
Eat right and healthy.
I'm even willing to give up sex.
That's enough. What happened to you?
It was fine, honey, it was fine.
Great, Orna. Just who I was looking for.
You're good with words.
Meirav, we're just...
-Shut up for a second.
I need you to call Ra'ban
and convince him to call me back.
What?
-Ra'ban. We went out this week and he decided to break up.
Another one bites the dust.
-Moshe, if you're not helping, at least be quiet.
I'm in the kitchen. Is there any majluf left?
-Check for yourself.
I don't want to get angry anymore.
That's the number. Call from your phone.
What do you want me to tell him?
-I don't really care.
But it has to be in your words.
Explain to him why he should come back to me.
Why?
-I don't know.
Because I'm here! Sexy and confident.
And I have a huge heart, and if he comes back,
he can enjoy all of that.
No, why do you want me to call?
I'm afraid he won't answer my call.
Tell him it's a shame if he doesn't come back
and that I promise, promise
that I won't ever talk about family and kids again. For now.
And that I won't wait for him under the house anymore.
I promise, promise.
There's no way in the world you're going to convince me
that you need a new computer screen right now.
You're not telling me we're buying a floor vacuum.
Oh, I absolutely am, and here I am saying it:
We'll have a floor vacuum
long before we get a new computer screen.
Oh, like that?
-Yeah.
So now, principle,
I'm going to buy a computer screen.
-I want to see.
Please, you'll see.
-Yeah.
Mom, did you sign the form for me?
-Oh, no, no, sweetie.
I already signed it.
I forgot about those classes.
-2,500 shekels.
Gone.
You see, it’s not about that vacuum, but when I scratched it
and suddenly saw I won,
I felt special.
Me too, I just want to win something...
Not the costume contest at work.
And I don't want them to take it away from me after five minutes.
And here, not even five minutes have passed.
-To me, it feels like forever.
It's not fair. Just when we win something
once in our lives,
we have to give it up.
What, don't we deserve to win?
And it's not that I wanted a screen, I wanted the freedom
to buy myself whatever I want.
Exactly. I'm the same way.
Even though I really wanted a vacuum.
-I know, honey.
We really need it, yeah.
-I know, honey. You're right.
I'm sorry.
Next time we win, no, no, no,
I'll buy you a computer screen right away.
It hurts so much.
-Seriously, what a bummer.
-Like a hole in my heart.
All our history, my little family's history.
And ours. Oh, Ra'ban...
It's okay to cry. Let it out! Everything out, everything.
That's it, it's all gone, everything.
The big birthday party,
the hotel in Eilat, the trip to Bodrum...
-the first date, the second date...
I thought there was only one date.
-I count the time
he caught me in the stairwell! - a date.
Caught you in the stairwell?
-Just once.
That's it. It's all gone. Everything's gone.
He’s gone.
-I don’t see how I’ll get over this.
I don’t feel like doing anything.
-Me neither.
I don’t even have an appetite.
-Yeah, it’s like food has no taste.
Cheers.
Cry, cry, cry.
There were no tissues. That’s what happened.
-Thanks.
Come on, Rachel, why like this, Rachel?
Rachel, why like this? Come on.
I've lost my charm, Sali.
That’s what they say, right? I’m no longer useful.
Come on, please, Rachel,
it’s just a little crying. Just... relax...
No, there’s no more of Grandma’s crying,
no more of Rachel’s crying,
no more Rachels
-Enough, enough.
That’s it, no more Rachel.
-Enough, my sweet. Enough.
No. I’m not useful. Why would they come to visit? Why?
Why? They waited all week for the crying.
It used to be like that.
Enough, my sweet, enough, enough. Here.
-Come on, enough already, enough, enough.
Go get me a tissue from the bedroom.
It’s making my nose red.
Okay, I’m not feeling well. Okay.
It makes me sad, you understand?
-Of course I understand.
I know you love me no matter what,
I’ll always be beautiful in your eyes. But, but...
It’s my hair and it’s like my masculinity.
There’s also that story in the Bible
about Samson and Delilah and his hair,
and what does that say about me? That I’m getting old?
Hey, what’s up? What happened? What’s with the gloom?
-His hair.
Forget it, you won’t understand.
Come on, babe, I signed for you and I’ll send you
a check on Monday to school. Okay?
Thanks.
-Did you eat?
I was hungry, so I ate Grandma’s crying
and it was way tastier.
Tell Dad not to buy that one anymore.
-Okay, babe. I’ll tell him.
Did you hear that? Did you hear?
And besides, I, I will always,
always need you. Okay?
Enough.
-Look at them.
What, is this a photo moment? Oops, sorry.
It’s okay.
-I’m such a fool.
I know that hurts too.
I promise you we’ll create our own
new history,
exactly the same as it was.
-Really?
Does that mean we’ll go to Bodrum again?
Yeah, even though the situation with Turkey isn’t what it used to be.
-Doesn’t matter.
Luckily, it’s trendy.
I can point out a bunch of bald guys
who aren’t ashamed of their baldness.
-Right, and it’s sexy.
Oh, relax, babe. That bald guy is mine.
Go find someone else. Go find another bald guy.
Alright, whatever will be, will be. I know...
-It’ll be fine.
Oh, excuse me, there’s another bald guy who needs me.
So what, we’re growing up?
Wait until you get to the white hair.
Alin...
What a thief. So what?
So he already saw we’re the kind that doesn’t just win the lottery.
We’re the kind that goes bald
and works hard for our money.
Yeah.
Next time I win something,
I’ll buy you a screen right away.
24-inch floor vacuum.
Sis, you hear? I got the bonus from work,
so now I can pay you back
the 2,500 shekels I owe you.
Thanks.
Don’t even think about it.
Who’s thinking?
So what? Saturday’s tough, huh?
Mom, is there any slice of zelif left?
I saved you a piece, my boy.
-Oh, champ.
So what’s new with the Hasson family?
-I hope Meirav gets better.
I don’t get it.
They only went on one date, right?
Yeah, yeah.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom.
That’s it, I’m done mourning that guy.
Mourning?
-Yeah, yeah, there are five stages of grief.
And Shai knows them all.
Denial, anger, bargaining, depression...
-and acceptance.
So you’ve accepted?
-Of course. Fresh start behind me.
I hope you learned something from it at least.
For sure. I won’t build castles in the air anymore.
When I was a kid, I always tried
to build castles with blocks,
and they always fell...
-Not now.
Sorry.
Next time, I don’t have to describe
how our kids will look on the first date,
the wedding dress,
the dress for the party, and the dress for the Shabbat Chatan.
What’s that?
-Hungry.
Hey, could my laptop be with you?
Yeah. Oops, your laptop is with me.
It happens. Come on up.
You took his computer?
-It happens.
Okay, I’m asking all of you to clear the living room.
What?
-What now?
What’s not clear?
He came to offer him perfume.
Come on! Seriously!
I don’t think Meirav has moved past denial.
And you haven’t moved past bargaining.
-Me? You.
And you’ve slipped into denial.
-Okay, fine.
We don’t need a screen,
we need a floor vacuum.
No way.
-Yes way.
Okay, so neither this nor that.
Got it?
-Got it.
So what are we doing with the money? Together?
I don’t know, I think we can find something
that both you and I can enjoy.
But I need 400 shekels from the money.
-For what?
To get my lucky nail done at Lydia’s.
I want to do a 24-inch nail.
Are you underestimating?
-Not underestimating. Just don’t know...
What a look you gave me, oh my God.
I got scared.
Shai is already waiting to see the... the mama machalta.
Did you check the address of the delivery?
Maybe it’s, maybe it’s...
I don’t know, babe.
Wait.
Robot!
-I’ll talk to them.
So sad.
Like... it hurts.
Sorry.