No, I hate those episodes in shows.
Where at the end they say, "It was just a dream, it’s not real."
It’s all in the actors' heads. How annoying is that?
Yeah, right.
Hey, aren’t they dressed too warmly?
-I don’t know.
Believe me, your mom has already thrown me off balance.
Why, what did she do to you this time?
No, it’s not something specific. It’s in general.
She always has something to say,
She always makes me feel
like I’m not a good enough mom.
Well, over the years you learn to filter her.
You’ll learn to ignore the faces, the raised eyebrows.
No, it’s not just about the faces
and the raised eyebrows, babe.
She always makes me feel
like I’m killing the kids.
She doesn’t really mean it.
-Yeah, she always has something to say.
It’s hot, the kids are dressed too much,
they’ll get a rash.
It’s cold, they’re not dressed, they’ll get pneumonia.
Don’t give the kid spices
until she’s three, you’re killing her.
And isn’t that true?
-Of course it’s not true,
but that doesn’t stop her from saying it.
She also doesn’t know what’s right,
but she only knows that what I’m doing is wrong.
Sit down, babe, you’re a great mom.
-Right? I think so too.
I’m a great mom, right?
-Of course.
Just don’t say that in front of her
because it’ll just encourage her more.
Look at me, look at me and...
Can you at least tell him
to shut that annoying thing off?
Shut that annoying thing off.
He didn’t shut it.
-Babe, let him eat in peace. Okay?
What peace? I can’t eat
with that annoying noise.
Who even hears that?
-Aren’t you supposed to teach him, as a parent?
Do me a favor, let his mom
teach him. Now I’m hungry, okay?
Do whatever you want.
Why like that?
-Not like that. I said do whatever you want.
Fine.
-Yeah.
Sorry to interrupt. Where’s Uncle Adam?
He’s in reserve duty. Maybe he’ll drop by later.
Didn’t you teach her not to talk with her mouth full?
-Of course I told her.
Sweetie, if you talk with your mouth full,
you’ll choke and die.
-Mom.
Do you want to kill the kid?
Sit down, sit down.
-Riki, I’m asking, enough with this.
Enough with what?
-I can’t take this anymore.
Riki, enough. I’m a great mom. Okay?
-What happened? What did I say?
That she’s killing the kid, maybe?
No, it’s important to me that you understand I’m a great mom.
I care about their health,
I care about their education,
everything is perfectly fine.
-I’m sure of it.
I’m really sorry. I probably misunderstood.
It’s okay, everything’s fine. I forgive you.
Alright, let’s watch something now.
-Here it comes.
You all heard the silly fight
between Michal and Itamar, right?
Why silly?
-Because it was silly.
You don’t interfere.
So, as a great mom,
what do you think is right?
Should the kid play by the table or not?
What seems more educationally correct?
Take your time, thaw another slacker.
Sit down, come here for a sec.
Eat, eat.
Do you see what you did?
Do you see what you did? Idiot.
What, babe, it's fine.
-No, it's not fine.
I know her longer than you have
and I know where this is going.
Where to?
-To the import, Shai, we're going home, now!
At best.
So what, what do you want? I'm not supposed to solve
your mom's riddle?
-I told you it would just encourage her.
Babe, you're exaggerating, right?
-That's what you think.
No, I think a person
should do what they feel,
I feel like Michal is right.
Riki, what you did to Shani just now is really not okay.
What's the problem? If she says she's
a great mom, then it's just a compliment.
It's not like I asked her
to make eggplant spread with liver flavor.
Shh...
-Have you seen Itamar?
He's in the bathroom.
-Come on, eat the shakshuka. It's still warm.
And Shani, that really wasn't a compliment.
I think you're a great mom.
Thanks.
-And let's eat because this shakshuka is still fresh.
Eat up, eat up.
-And about what you said, you don't have to thicken it for me.
Sit down.
-Actually, I'd love to thicken it for you, Riki.
Yeah?
-I think in this case,
Michal is right.
-Thanks, babe.
Michal...
Why are you doing that?
-Doing what?
The eyebrow raise.
-Filter, filter.
You're saying Michal, who isn't even
a mom to a Chihuahua, is right?
What's wrong? I've always wanted a Chihuahua.
So Michal is right?
-Yeah, yeah, Riki. She's right.
I think in this case, Itamar needs to understand
that part of parenting is also teaching his son.
-Oh!
So Itamar isn't connected.
-No, I didn't say that.
So I failed to connect with Itamar.
-Riki, I... I didn't...
I didn't say that.
Let it go.
-Ew...
What, did the burp make you laugh?
Do you also like a little fart? Yeah?
Rivka...
-Did you see the little brat?
-And I'm always the one who's wrong.
My connection isn't good and I should just stay quiet.
-Rivka!
Did you see how the North African side jumped out of her?
Okay, fine, I know.
Family. I'll talk to her.
-Thanks.
But she needs to come here.
Sit down, babe, let's try to minimize the damage.
-Yeah, yeah, sure.
Just remind me: to minimize means
I need to go apologize.
Babe,
-What babe, I'm already tired of this,
you don't understand she's painting me as a monster
and in the end, I'm the one who has to apologize
for being portrayed as a monster.
Babe, you're not a monster.
-Thanks, babe, thanks.
I just... I meant to...
never mind, okay, thanks.
A distinction in the herd, just so you know.
-Thanks. Thank you very much.
So come on, explain to me what's the fuss.
-You're in the Knesset on the balcony and she's right,
and you have a lot to learn from her, and she's right.
Yeah, because she's right.
Yeah.
-She's right.
Maybe I'll also get down on all fours
and kiss her feet.
That could be a really nice addition
but you don't have to, you don't have to.
Okay, move.
I did my best.
-And I prepared the ground.
Do you think it'll work?
-No chance.
Adam.
-Hey, Shabbat Shalom.
Where's Mom?
-On the balcony.
Oh, so Dad, is it really okay that I brought a guest?
What a question, of course.
-Come on.
I'm sorry the conversation got to this point.
Me too.
Still, you have an edge over me in motherhood.
You're doing a great job too.
Come on
Wow
My dad Pinchas, my brother Shai,
my sister-in-law Michal. Meet Matadel.
So beautiful.
-Shh.
Nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you.
Itamar, come here for a sec.
So, what do you guys have today?
Oh, okay. Where's Mom?
She's on the balcony right now! Sit down, we're faking a reunion.
Hey, I'm Itamar, his brother.
Nice to meet you.
-Matadel.
Matadel sounds familiar. Oh, they're coming.
Hello, Mom.
-Hi, my sweet.
Pinchas...
-I hope it's okay
that Matadel is staying for lunch. Right?
Of course, what a question! You're invited.
See?
-Thanks.
Matadel is from the base and I gave her a ride home.
I was thinking of stopping by for a snack from the shlaykler.
Funny name.
-Matadel?
Shlaykler.
So you guys aren't friends or anything?
Not that I'm judging...
Judging what?
-He can date whoever he wants.
Just that he should get married in a few weeks.
After he finds the right girl.
Should we go to the table?
-Uncle Adam.
Come on.
It's calming. They're not a couple.
What? Why are you doing this to me?
Riki?
-You come into my house and do this to me?
Any moment now you'll start rolling your eyes at me.
I'm really sorry, Riki, for having my own opinions.
Stupid opinions, that's what you have.
-Stupid opinions?
Stupid. Yes.
I treat you like my daughter.
You come into my house and act like this?
What, are you spitting in my face?
-Is this how you treat your daughter?
Pinchas, look what she's doing to me in front of the grandkids!
Now, Shai, we're going home. Enough!
What, honey, it's fine.
-No, it's not fine.
I know her longer than you
and I know where this is going.
Where? To import, Shai, we're going home
right now!" at best.
Come on, so what do you want?
How am I supposed to solve
your mom's riddle?
-I told you it would just encourage her.
Honey, you're exaggerating, right?
-That's what you think.
No, I think a person
should do what they feel.
And I feel Michal is right.
-This won't end well.
So what, like? I need to do
this reverse psychology,
like you know what's right to do
and you do the opposite?
So be it. Itamar is right.
Riki, what you did to Shani just now is really not okay.
What's the problem? If she says she's
a great mom, it's just a compliment.
It's not like I asked her
to make eggplant spread with liver flavor.
Shh...
-Did you see Itamar?
He's in the bathroom.
-Come eat from the shlaykler, they're still warm.
And Shabi, that really wasn't nice.
I think you're a great mom.
Thanks.
-Now let's eat because these knishes
are still fresh. Eat up, eat up.
And about what Tzod said, you don't have to defend me.
-Shabi!
Actually, I'd love to defend you on that, Riki.
_ Yeah.
Yeah.
I think in the argument between Michal and Itamar
the one who's right is Itamar.
What about Itamar?
-That's true, but it was easy.
Now comes the harder and more important part:
Why is Itamar right?
I don't know.
Because, because the child's mom
is the one who needs to raise him.
No, no, no, no, no. No, great mom.
If the kid stops playing at the table,
then he'll start acting out,
start bothering, and then he needs to be raised.
But like this, if he stays quiet,
he'll connect on his own.
What, why are you going "ummm"?
Is what I'm saying not true?
No, that's not true. What?
Playing at the table means a connected kid?
And when my daughter apologized
for bothering and spoke with her mouth full,
you're saying my daughter isn't raised well?
You won't raise your voice in my house.
Rivka.
-Shabi.
Are you listening?
-Did I raise my voice?
I didn't raise my voice.
I'm just trying to save my granddaughters' lives
like any good grandma would.
-Me? I'm killing again.
You get it? I'm killing again?
-Shabi.
Why all these dramas? Why?
I'm not feeling good, I'm telling you.
Yuck!
-Now it's better.
Did you see that cheeky one?
-Shabi.
No, I'm always wrong and my parenting
isn't good and I need to be quiet.
Shabi.
-Did you see how her Moroccan side came out?
Shabi!
-Yeah, yeah. I know.
I need to go talk to her.
-Thanks.
I don't want to.
-Shabi.
She's the one who needs to apologize.
Rivka, what's with you? Why do you always
look at the glass half empty?
What are you talking about?
-She's trying to please you.
Even if she doesn't think so,
she told you she's on Itamar's side
just because he's your son.
And you don't see all that?
But...
-No buts. She's trying.
Okay, fine, fine.
Alright, I agree. It's family.
J
Orna `
Ri
Ren
Van
.Yay `bo`
Great.
-At least she's trying.
The second...
-Rivka, one bride on one Sabbath,
and the first one is a bit too much.
-Okay, fine.
No problem?
No problem.
-Okay.
I want to go home.
-Wait a second.
Can I?
-Sure.
Shabi, I'm really sorry
that the conversation got to this point.
Me too.
Regarding motherhood, I think
you're doing a good job.
Thanks.
And you too, Riki,
I mean, you have a big advantage over me in motherhood,
and I'm just trying.
-Yeah.
Boi
Come on
Yeah.
Mom, hey.
-Hey.
It's so nice you could make it.
I hope it's okay you brought a guest.
Of course, no question about it.
Come on in.
Hi.
-Hi.
Matadel, meet my mom Rivka. My sister-in-law Shani.
Matadel is from the base! I gave her a ride home.
I was thinking about stopping by for a snack from the shlaykler.
Funny name.
-Matadel?
Shlaykler.
-Uncle Adam.
What a coincidence, his girlfriend is Ethiopian.
-First of all, she's not his girlfriend,
and you don't say Ethiopian.
She's Israeli of Ethiopian descent.
You don't have to say everything you see.
It's a matter of upbringing.
-Rivka, I'm asking you
not to educate my daughter.
I'm her mom, and I'll decide if it's needed.
But if my granddaughter is acting
like a primitive from the jungle,
Sorry, Matadel, then I do need to educate her.
You just called my daughter primitive.
Are you for real?
She's not to blame. It's because her mom is primitive.
Shai, come on, we're leaving.
-Yeah, go back to the jungle you came from.
Riki, you need therapy.
-You need a reboot.
Enough!
How am I supposed to solve your mom's riddle?
I told you it would just encourage her.
Babe, you're exaggerating, right?
-That's what you think.
No, I think a person
should do what they feel,
and I feel Michal is right.
-This won't end well.
So what, like? I have to do
this reverse psychology thing,
like you know what's right to do
and you do the opposite?
Fine, Itamar is right.
And this could lead to another disaster.
Can I interrupt for a second?
Will it help if I say no?
-Not at all.
Listen, sweetie, it's a lose-lose situation.
You're heading for a dead end and the situation is a mess.
But there's also a third way.
What third way?
It's either you're right or Michal is right?
Don't play at all. You're not ready to take a stand,
you don't get involved, you're like the UN. That's it.
Come on, Mom brought out more shlaykler.
Let's go before Dad finishes them off.
Hold on, I'm in the bathroom. Moshe! It's not sitting well.
Come on, babe, let's head back.
It's not like I asked her
to make eggplant spread with liver flavor.
Shhh..
-Have you seen Itamar?
He's in the bathroom.
Come eat the shlaykler, they're still warm.
And Shani, it really wasn't intentional.
I think you're a great mom.
Thanks.
-And let's eat because these shlaykler are still fresh.
Eat up, eat up.
-And about what you said, you don't have to thicken it for me.
Okay.
What is it?
-What is what?
You're not answering me?
-About what?
K'
Oh, it's some kind of game.
-What game, Riki?
Rivka, relax.
Wow, it's so quiet. We can eat in peace.
Yuck.
-That was the pressure, babe.
It was sitting here.
-How's the shlaykler today?
You're asking me?
-Yeah.
Like always.
-Tasty or not tasty?
You can't mistake it, it's Riki Rosen's shlaykler.
She's doing it on purpose, she's not answering me.
Right?
-Riki, is there something you want me to say?
Enough!
-Rivka.
No, no.
That's enough for me.
-Calm down. Rivka!
Respect, sis.
-That was my idea, babe.
Okay...
-Wait, it's not over yet.
Did you see what she did to me?
-Rivka, you see the half-eaten cake.
Stop annoying me
with those metaphors of yours, Pinchas.
She's trying.
-Trying to drive me crazy.
Rivka, let’s go back to the table.
-Pinchas, there will be consequences,
I'm telling you, there will be consequences.
She knows she's being heard. Huh?
Come on
Come here
These knishes, I’m telling you,
they’re like seeds,
you eat and eat and eat, and there's still room for more.
If you're a great mom, what does that say about me?
What?
-If you're the great mom
with the excellent parenting methods,
then where does that leave me?
Riki, you're a great mom.
-The knishes will cool down...
And you raised wonderful sons.
-You can heat them in the microwave.
But parenting methods have changed, Riki...
-And for the worse. What does that mean,
that my methods are outdated? What?
-Not exactly.
So back then it wasn't win-win for parenting?
So what does that mean?
-Mom.
Hey there.
-Adam, Adam, my sweet.
So nice you came.
I hope it’s okay I brought a guest.
-Of course, what a question.
What’s the question anyway?
-Come on.
You see, this is the result of my parenting.
Look at this sweet and polite kid.
Oh! What’s this?
-She’s just a hitchhiker.
I’ll wait in the car.
-Mom...
Riki!
-What, now I’m also racist?
Mom!
-Shai, I’m asking you,
you and your wife, just be quiet for a bit,
we’ve heard enough of your opinions today.
What happened, Riki? Do you have a problem with Adam's girlfriend?
No! I have a problem with you.
Since you entered this house
I told Pinchas you’re a real pain!
Excuse me? Okay, Shai, let’s go home. Now!
Enough! Come on, girls, let’s go,
leave the food, let’s go.
And that’s not true.
-Of course it’s not true,
but that doesn’t stop her from saying it.
She also doesn’t know what’s right,
but she knows
that only what I do is wrong.
Sit down, babe, you’re a great mom.
-Right?
I think so too. I’m a great mom. Right?
Of course.
Just don’t say that in front of her,
because that will only encourage her more.
What, so you want me to
make her feel like she’s right, or what?
No, find something in the middle, neutral.
Neutral. With your mom, nothing will help anymore.
-That’s true.
I just want to remind you
that my mom took a self-defense course
a few weeks ago and graduated with honors.
I just want to remind you
that I’m younger than her.
Great, but my mom
has been pounding schnitzels for forty years,
so she has the muscles of a Georgian weightlifter.
I don’t care. I’ll tear her apart.
Babe, what’s important in this battle is not to engage.
So what, tell me, was this whole episode not real?
You just figured that out?
It was all in the actors' heads.
No way!
-Yes way.
Enough!
Riki, what’s going on?
Did you see the African forecast...
Did you see how all her European vibes came out?
-Excuse me.
European vibes.
-You meant to say African vibes.
But something's spicy in my mouth.
-Drink some water.
This isn’t going to end well.
Oh, so I’m like...
-Excuse me.
No, I have another sentence here.
My mom took a self-defense course
a few weeks ago and finished with flying colors...
Ear and mouth...
Itamar!
-Itamar, come here!
Of course, in time...
-So beautiful...
Excuse me, excuse me.
About the silly fight between Smadar...
-Smadar.