I'm getting a ton of compliments on it.
Sometimes I pull it off.
Thanks.
What’s that, a new outfit?
-No, not at all.
I actually wore it on my last birthday.
Really? It looks brand new.
-Seriously?
Still, there's something charming about you.
Hop hop hooray, I’m a year older.
Yeah, right, just a little bit.
But still, the outfit, something...
Well, I don’t always pull it off.
Mom, happy birthday!
-Thanks.
Happy birthday!
-Thanks, sweeties.
How old are you?
-Age is just for ID.
Tell me, do I look like your mom?
Mom is...
What’s that, your parents' new ringtone?
-Yeah.
Hello, Mom, Shabbat shalom.
On my way to the family dinner.
Friday dinner and a birthday cake for Shani.
She had it two days ago, yeah.
Doesn’t matter.
Less, let’s drop it for now.
-What less?
Just drop it, Mom, drop it.
More or less. Never mind.
Mom, say hi to Dad! Hi to everyone there, okay?
Mom, there’s a cop behind us! I’m not using a hands-free.
Hang up the phone...
You with the bald head, please pull over.
-Look, look, he’s stopping us.
This is what I need on my birthday, right?
Good evening, routine check,
car registration and driver’s license, please.
Here you go.
Bi
and Shai's
brother.
Sit tight, where are the car documents?
-Hold on, why are you rushing?
Here you go.
Great, now he saw us talking on the phone.
And because of your mom, we’re getting a 750 shekel ticket.
He didn’t see the phone,
He said it’s a routine check.
-Okay, okay.
Alright, quiet, quiet, he’s coming.
According to the documents, the only driver
allowed to drive this car
is B. Rosen! I assume that’s not you.
No, that’s me, officer,
it’s just my work car
and I can also register
my husband to drive it.
Really, and did you register?
-No.
So you just drove the car
without a proper license.
No, wait, wait, wait, I didn’t know,
she was supposed to take care of that.
-Yeah, yeah, officer,
Look, I just, I prepared
all the documents at work
just forgot to ask for the signature,
I just have my birthday today.
See, here’s my birthday cake?
That’s my birthday cake.
And I got confused with all the...
I promise I’ll sort it out on Sunday.
Where’s the cake from?
-I bought it from the supermarket.
Yeah.
Okay, switch places with each other
and until she sorts out the work approval
you’re not driving the car, got it?
-Sure.
This time I'll let it slide
but only because it's your birthday.
Thanks, really, thank you.
And you, put in a little more effort for your wife.
-Yeah, yeah.
You don't buy a birthday cake at the supermarket.
-What?
Here, this is your wife's parents' bakery
they have an open eye,
I'll be with you, just go later.
She just complicates things for them every day.
What happened this time? Who's on the phone?
I called Shai to wish him Shabbat Shalom
and to make sure they’re not coming here by mistake,
but he forgot to hang up
so I heard a cop pulled them over because of her.
She promised him she'd sort out the licenses
but she didn’t, so he drove without...
He trusted her.
He still doesn’t get that you can’t trust her.
Just do me a favor and don’t tell them anything,
so they don’t think I’m eavesdropping on their call.
I don’t need to eavesdrop on my son’s phone
to know he’s quietly suffering.
Quiet.
-You think he means we should buy another cake now?
They’re talking.
I’m pretty sure they are.
At least it’s cheaper than a report.
Oops, I forgot to hang up the phone.
-What?
Great, now your mom
heard the whole conversation with the cop.
Shai, what happened to you? What, you think
my mom’s bored out of her mind?
She has nothing to do but listen to our nonsense?
That’s exactly what suits her.
Now she’ll bring it up
and make a big deal out of it for a year.
Your mom never misses a chance
to get at me, please.
You’re really paranoid.
I know my mom
and you have no idea how wrong you are.
I’d be happy if our son
had a wife a little more...
A little more...
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
Happy birthday.
-Thanks.
Happy birthday, my beautiful.
Shabbat Shalom.
Look, wow, that looks great on you.
-Nice, right? It’s from silk.
Yeah, I know, Mom told me.
-Learn.
Thanks.
-No problem.
Happy birthday, but why were you so late?
Because a cop stopped us.
Turns out I was driving without the right license
because it’s Shai’s car and I’m not allowed to drive.
So did you get a ticket?
-No, no, he let us go,
he saw the birthday cake,
he felt sorry for us.
But he made us buy
a fancier birthday cake.
350 shekels for a cake.
Dairy?
-No, it’s parve, it’s supposed to be tasty.
Give it here, I’ll help put it in the kitchen.
Shai, how are your parents?
-Fine, really fine.
Fine, fine, now they have something to talk about
and mostly someone to talk about.
Because he’s disorganized
he needed a tidy wife,
but she’s worse than him by a few numbers.
I really don’t understand why we keep
the service if we don’t use it.
The service has emotional value
that passes down through the family.
Oh, Riki, come on, from generation to generation.
Your mom got it from her mother-in-law
who had nowhere to throw it away.
And when she moved to assisted living five weeks ago
she threw this at you.
It's porcelain that's worth something.
It's even more valuable if it's not used.
Didn't you see that BBC series about antiques?
It's worth a lot.
-A lot. Seriously, Ben,
it's just gathering dust and dirt.
I’d sell it to an old-timer,
better yet, you should sell the dust to a dust dealer
to sell it to the Turks.
You're just being a grump because you don't like to clean.
Hey, Riki, if I were a service,
would you take care of me and pamper my
ears like them?
If you were my ear,
you'd stop talking nonsense.
Ouch.
-What happened?
Your finger got stuck.
Wait, wait, Riki, just like it went in,
it’ll come out, don’t worry.
Pinchas, it’s not coming out.
-Show me, show me for a sec.
You need to apply soap, it’ll come out easily.
Go get soap from the bathroom.
-Okay, what kind of soap?
What kind of soap? Brain-washing soap,
what does it matter?
Just bring something.
-Alright, alright, I’m on it.
Maybe conditioner?
-Go, just go already.
Alright, come on, it’s late, to the table.
Wait, wait, I made the salad today.
Too bad you told them how much the cake cost
because now no one cares about the food,
everyone wants to know how she is.
-She’s really tasty.
What?
-Did you open it?
Come on, couldn’t you wait? That’s my birthday cake.
Pay attention to the second one, what happened?
I want some too, Mom.
-After the meal.
But it’s not parve, Rachel.
Hey, did you see what they did to you?
Alright. Come on, Sali, kiddush.
"On the sixth day
the heavens and the earth and all their hosts were finished.
And God finished on the seventh day..."
I’m sorry.
That’s the scariest kiddush I’ve ever been to.
It’s my parents, maybe something happened.
Okay, call them after kiddush.
"...for in it He rested from all His work
which God created to do."
Ben, answer already.
"Sabri Maranan."
Hello?
-Cheers.
Shai, it’s Dad.
-Yeah, I know, Dad,
the shark told me.
What happened, is everything okay?
Almost okay. Mom got stuck in the service.
-What?
Her finger got stuck in the service.
How does a finger get stuck in the service?
In the ear of the service cup, hey.
No, how did that happen?
-It was an accident, don’t ask too many questions.
She’s hysterical, Shai, come as fast as you can.
But we’re in the middle of kiddush
and it’s exactly Shani’s birthday.
Amen.
Alright, wait, Dad, I’m coming.
I made the salad.
-Amazing.
Did you cut it and season it?
Come here for a sec.
-What, is everything okay?
What?
Come on, what happened?
My mom got her finger stuck in the serving dish,
Don't ask me how.
-No way.
Yeah, so she wants
me to come help her get it out now.
What, are you serious? What are you gonna do now?
I’ll pop over to my mom’s,
help her get it out, and I’ll be back in half an hour.
Alright, come on, what should I do?
Go, do it quickly and come back,
I want you here for the candle lighting.
Okay, babe, everything will be fine.
What happened?
-Just a little mess with my mom,
I need to go help
try to get a finger out of a serving dish.
Alright, come on, go fast and come back quick.
Come on
-Come on, with pleasure
A lot of weird things happen to that woman, right?
Did her finger turn blue or is it just me?
I’m dying.
This is neither the time nor the place to die.
Don’t touch, please don’t touch.
Come on, Mom, it’s just a little twist of the finger
and it’ll be out.
Sometimes it gets stuck, the finger,
and then they have to take it off, right?
Come on, Mom, enough, you’re just stressing yourself out now.
And then sometimes it gets complicated
and they have to disconnect the whole hand, right?
How am I gonna manage without a hand?
-Trumpledor managed just fine.
Mom, relax,
we’ll make sure nothing happens to you.
I can teach you how to disconnect your mind and thoughts.
Have you ever been to a course like that that calms you down?
Have you tried Vaseline?
-Why don’t you just break the cup?
Seriously, are you normal?
That’s part of the serving dish.
-No one touches the serving dish.
Absolutely not.
-Okay...
It’s a serving dish that’s been in the family.
-Alright.
You’re right because if you break the cup,
you could get hurt from the shards
which is way more dangerous.
Okay, enough, enough, enough, I’m tired of these dramas,
I’m calling an ambulance,
they probably know how to handle this.
No, I don’t want an ambulance, why isn’t Shai here?
Why Shai, Mom? I’m here.
-I’m here too.
Why isn’t Shai here?
I’m sorry, babe,
I would’ve driven myself but I’m not allowed to drive.
If that cop stops us again,
even the cake from the best bakery in town
won’t save us from embarrassment.
Okay, it’s also my fault,
I didn’t organize the documents.
It’s fine, it’s okay, just make sure to come back quickly.
Just drive carefully so they don’t stop us again.
Come on, just do it already,
I can’t stand this.
Come on, what’s going on, Shai?
We’re almost there, Dad.
-Okay.
What’s the rush?
He’s coming.
Maybe we should put ice on it
to reduce the swelling,
like we used to do for dogs.
Since when do dogs get stuck in serving dishes?
Stop making fun of me.
Mom, lighten up, what’s the matter?
The kids aren’t here.
Yeah, it's great, humor, it’s also calming.
They taught us that in this course too.
It’s messing with my head.
-Yeah.
Did they teach you how to connect it there?
-I don’t remember.
Look, I didn’t find ice
but I brought some frozen schnitzels.
What did you do? Did you take it out of the freezer?
Do you know how hard I worked on this?
It’s going to spoil, it’s food, put it back in the freezer.
Riki, you need to be more relaxed.
I think I hear the ambulance downstairs.
Pinchas, don’t let them take me away,
I want to die in my bed, at home.
Honestly, when I think about it
I’ve never heard of anyone dying
from a finger stuck in the service.
And waiting for many more weeks of suffering together.
They’re here, Mom, think about the suffering, it’s more calming.
They definitely didn’t teach us that in the course.
Please.
You guys got here really fast, nice job.
I don’t need an ambulance.
Are you the guy?
-I’m the paramedic.
Oh.
What happened?
-Her what’s-it-called got stuck in the service.
Show me your finger.
I’ve been in the field for weeks and I have to admit
I’ve never seen anything like this.
How did this happen to you?
-If you lived here,
you’d see a lot more things you haven’t seen yet.
Once Adam dated an Ethiopian girl.
-What’s that got to do with anything?
You didn’t date her, Mom scared her away.
Okay, fine, there’s really no problem here,
we just need to break the cup and that’s it.
No way, not in the middle of the service!
I understand, ma’am,
but besides breaking it, there’s no other way.
And he doesn’t want to waste time,
there are more urgent events than saving lives.
I’m dying.
Wait, wait, so what do you suggest, bro?
Listen, you need to calm her down,
when her blood pressure is high, her finger swells up
and it never comes out. Just calm her down.
It’s okay, I’ll stay here at home
and I’ll calm myself down with the service.
The paramedic did his part, the paramedic can go.
Listen, when she’s calm
you need to scare her with something!
Then the blood comes out of the finger and the finger out of the service, got it?
Yeah.
So, who’s Itamar that called
to order the ambulance?
Me, me.
This is the ambulance charge, come pay soon.
What to pay?
Isn’t it covered by the basket?
You’re kidding me, there’s barely any Tylenol and a band-aid in the basket.
If I don’t transport, it costs.
Riki, I suggest you move to the living room
and there you can examine in peace.
Great, now you want to kill me, Pinchas.
What? No way, Riki, no way!
But he said you need to relax
so come on, examine in the living room.
And besides, Riki, don’t worry,
no one is going to kill you. Come on.
Wait, wait,
so maybe we should transport her after all,
are you sure not?
Because she has a lot of issues.
-For sure.
Hello.
Is the ambulance for here?
-Yeah, relax, Shai.
But is everything okay?
-Yeah, yeah, we just need to calm her down and everything will be fine.
Mom, are you okay? Do you want us to take you somewhere?
Turns out she doesn't need to go anywhere.
-We already know what to do.
Alright, the paramedic explained it to Ben more or less.
Guys, see you later and good luck.
Thank you so much.
-Thanks, thanks, bro. Bye.
Did you see that barbarian with the yogurt?
Breaking it, no respect at all.
Why not break it, really?
-Are you crazy?
What, are you normal?
-It's the service. We don't talk about breaking anymore,
It annoys Riki, she needs to chill.
Pinchas, it's been cooking a bit longer, notice that?
Shai, Itamar, come to the kitchen for a sec.
Riki, maybe you should watch TV,
maybe that will calm you down?
Riki, maybe I’ll read you the newspaper,
Come on, have you lost it? You live in Israel, right?
Since when does a newspaper or TV
calm anyone in this country?
Riki, only if Adam marries
someone from the alliance will that calm her down.
That's true.
Listen, let’s do what the paramedic said.
Sit together in the ambulance.
-What did he say?
Itamar.
After she's calm, we need to
surprise her, scare her a bit.
And then from the scare, the blood will come out of her finger,
we’ll pull it out and the finger will come off.
No, this whole scare idea
really doesn’t sound logical to me.
What, do you think the blood sits in the finger,
we come, scare them
and it moves to the second finger?
That's what the paramedic said.
Alright, Ben, let’s scare her,
but not too much, so she doesn't have a heart attack.
Then they’ll have to take her away.
So, in short, does anyone have an idea on how to scare her?
I have one...
)(9
And move,
,ְֲ ni
Is there a story that makes it
impossible to break this cup?
The set will be ruined.
So break the plate
of the cup too, then no one will know.
And then it’ll be five? Who's heard of a set of five?
Who's heard of an odd set?
So maybe break another cup and another plate
and then four, a set of four exists, right?
Can we stop talking about the set?
It's stressing Riki out and she needs to relax.
I'm talking without pressure. On the contrary,
I actually think I'm calming her down.
How can I relax
when my son almost got stopped because of you?
I had a feeling this topic would come up.
Well, my parents are waiting for me at home
with a cake that costs 350 shekels.
Congratulations, babe.
-Thanks, that was two days ago.
How lucky you are-
-What do you mean lucky?
Her birthday is on the ninth of Av.
She looks calm and is going off.
Mom, don’t ask what happened.
-What happened?
The freezer broke and all the schnitzels thawed,
everything needs to be thrown away.
No way.
What are you doing?
Stop, this isn't working.
-What about the schnitzels?
Chill already with the schnitzels,
we just said that to scare Mom.
Hello.
Are you guys completely out of your minds?
The service almost broke.
Yeah, Mom, we're still here.
Listen, sweetie, we just finished eating,
we're waiting to bring out the coffee and cake.
The kids and Moshe are going crazy.
When do you think you'll arrive?
-I have no idea, I don't know, come on,
Riki got her finger stuck
in some cup, you know what?
An ambulance was here, it's gone.
Alright, come do this as quickly as you can.
Because we can't handle the kids and Moshe anymore,
They're really glued to the cake.
Is that her?
Tell her I'm not waiting for her with the cake either.
Get here.
I don't know if you know
but the salad...
-you made it.
So here's the thing,
I've been trying to get pregnant for half a year,
and we finally found out I have a problem with...
Ben, you came mixing up my poles.
Anyway, we used a sperm donor
and Shani and I are going to have triplets.
I'm dying.
Just yesterday we found out they made a mistake
and the donor is Ethiopian.
-What?
What?
Despite the color differences,
we decided to continue with the pregnancy.
-What?
Itamar, pull already, Ben, pull.
Give it to me, give it to me...
What are you doing?
Just kidding, Mom, we wanted to scare you
into thinking your blood was coming out of your finger.
You guys are not normal.
You think you're going to scare me
with an Afro-Israeli triplet?
That'll be material to tease you about for the rest of my life.
And you, what are you doing?
Why?
Honey, come to the bedroom for a second.
I love the sound it makes,
it reminds me of the sound I used to make
when I’d hit you on the butt when you were little.
Why?
What's wrong with you?
-I want to tell you something.
Listen to me carefully, with all due respect
to your mom and her finger,
my parents are waiting for us at home
and the kids are driving them crazy.
You guys are messing around with all kinds of
silly scare tactics that aren't working.
Okay, we're just trying
to draw the blood from her finger,
that's what the paramedic said.
So listen well, my blood is rising to my head too
!and soon it's going to look for a way out.
The paramedic didn't tell you that, did he?
Okay, honey, honey, I get you,
but I can't leave her like this,
we need to scare her and we're not succeeding.
Do you at least have a good scare idea?
Yeah, I have a great idea.
Alright, I...
It hurts so much.
I'll stay a little longer.
Riki, you won't believe what happened.
Now, why in the middle?
I'm on the balcony.
What is this? Another scare attempt?
This is for Shani.
It's not the same sound.
Yeah, we're still here.
-What's up, babe?
Manny and Alin are leaving because of the baby.
What about the little ones?
-Visiting with Dad.
What about Shai's mom?
-She's putting on a show here.
Did you buy a ticket?
-Okay, enough, I'm done,
I'm going home.
I'm hungry.
First time there's really nothing.
-What do you mean, nothing?
There is, I just can't do it like this.
Come on, I'll defrost some shlikler for you-
Come on, Michal.
Come.
-But food.
Now, now, come.
But...
-I don't care, I don't care,
It was supposed to be quick
and turned into a big mess.
Fine, can I go after?
-We're moving now, do you hear me?
Can we add some salt to this?
-After I'm gone.
Okay, Mom, I see you're here with everyone,
so we're moving out.
The finger is already cold, can you feel it?
Sit down.
-No, no.
Okay, we're moving.
It hurts so much.
Riki, enough with that, okay?
-Enough with what?
Riki, enough, it's my birthday
and my parents and my siblings
and my kids are all waiting to celebrate with me
and here, not a single person
said happy birthday to me except Michal.
If you think I forgot
your birthday, you're wrong,
I planned to celebrate it
properly at our place on Saturday.
Yeah, Riki? How old am I, Riki?
Confused person
remembers the birthday date but forgets the age.
That's such an incorrect statement.
Besides, I also have a gift for you.
Really?
-Pinchas, shut up.
-Yeah, why are you surprised?
What do you mean, a gift? Like wrapped and everything?
No, not like that.
-Oh, then what kind?
Since I don't have daughters of my own,
I decided to pass this precious service to you
as an inheritance while I'm still alive.
Wow.
You're giving me the service, Riki?
-Yeah, sit down,
it’s passed down in our family from generation to generation,
Pinchas, shut up, it goes from my generation to hers.
So Riki, does that mean...
that this service is now mine?
Yes.
How lovely.
Thank you.
The service.
The finger.
Say thank you that they left the cake from the store.
Not even a bite from the second cake.
Okay, Meirav and Moshe apologized, right?
-Yeah.
I'm a bit sad the girls didn't see
that they lit candles for their mom's birthday.
Come on, babe,
they'll have many more weeks with her.
-Yeah.
What do you think, should we celebrate at your mom's tomorrow?
I think we’ve had enough of your
birthday celebrations today.
Never mind, just leave the cake,
we’ll light the candles tomorrow morning at breakfast.
It’s not important.
What happened?
From the beginning.
It’s my parents, something might have happened.
Where to?
-Where are you going?
He’s going back to the dressing room.
-No!
Alright, enough, I can’t take it anymore, folks,
I’m calling an ambulance.
They probably know how to handle this.
I can’t, she’s killing me.
Enough, Polly.
How can anyone stand this?
This is for Shai.
I’ll give them. Pinchas, be quiet.