What are you laughing at?
Look at how the girls look,
what’s up? They look like new immigrants.
I can’t believe I let you
dress them in those pigtails.
No way, it looks really nice.
Right, girls? It’s pretty, isn’t it?
It hurts.
-It’s tight on me.
Okay, don’t touch or scratch,
it’s tight and the hairstyle will get ruined.
You’re ruining the kids.
What do you want? That’s Grandma Chava, you know her.
What’s wrong with you? Grandma Chava,
she’s just a sweet old lady.
A tough, violent, and bitter woman.
Trust me, you don’t want to mess with her.
In a second, you’ll tell me
she’s connected to crime families in the country.
I wouldn’t be surprised.
-That’s fine.
How long is she staying with your parents?
Until the renovations in her assisted living place are done.
Really.
-Sunday, I think.
Why are you looking at me? Look at the road.
You know I could look really good as an aunt.
What an idiot.
-No, I’m serious. Should I pull over and do it for you?
Honey, if you don’t want
me to turn into a tough, violent, and bitter woman,
then you better chill out.
-What did I say?
Look at me, look at me and...
Three, four and...
-Shabbat Shalom.
Don’t run.
Walk nicely.
Mom? Dad?
What’s this? It’s freezing in here.
Grandma doesn’t like it when it’s hot.
-Okay, but it’s cold in here like a grave.
She’s not even here.
She likes to pop up unexpectedly,
she says it keeps them alert.
Come on, she’s 80,
how surprising can it be?
She’s not here?
Oh my God, Pinchas, you scared me, what happened to you?
Where did you come from?
-From the room. She’s not here?
No.
Alright, quick, Shabbat Shalom.
Okay, I’m going to see what’s happening in the kitchen.
Pinchas, Pinchas, can you
turn down the AC? I’m freezing.
Can’t do it. Chava says
it has to stay at 16 degrees in the place,
one degree higher is not civilized.
-What nonsense.
I know, sit down,
I know and you know that you shouldn’t touch a suspicious object,
not even get close.
No, you’re not normal.
I’ve been locked in my room for four days.
-Why?
Why? To reduce friction between me and her.
No, you’re not sane, huh?
And what happens if you need to go to the bathroom?
I have a bucket.
Okay, you didn’t see me, I wasn’t here.
-And, and...
Mom.
I thought it was Grandma.
-No, it’s me.
Where is she?
-In the living room, spreading negative energy.
Didn’t you see her when you came in?
-No, she’s not there.
So she’s probably in the bathroom,
releasing negative energy.
What’s this? What’s this? You really put in effort today, huh?
I made a soufflé fish cake in the oven.
Dinner's at exactly eight, a minute later
the soufflé falls and the fish dries out.
Got it? Eight o'clock.
What, no schnitzels?
-Of course there are.
Shayka, I've been working since yesterday,
I can barely stand.
Then sit down, take a break.
I can't afford to, Shayka,
I need everything to be perfect.
Otherwise, Her Highness will have something to say.
Okay, I don't want to talk about it,
It's Friday today.
Are the girls dressed nicely?
-Like new immigrants.
Are the curls tight?
The girls are curly.
-Great.
Not that it’ll help against Grandma Chava, but still.
I feel bad for their soft hearts, they're young.
Mom, it’s pulling me.
-I know, my dear, I know,
Just a little more and I’ll let you go, okay? I promise.
Go play with your sister.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
What’s going on, where is everyone?
-Around.
And Grandma Chava?
-No idea.
Good, because I really need to pee.
-You just went.
We stopped on the way, that crazy guy did
it in the middle of the street, I thought I was gonna die.
Honey, it’s not healthy to hold it in.
-Okay, okay.
What, he’s stressed about Grandma Chava too?
-What, he made me wear a bra.
How's Shay?
-Shay, not normal.
No, forget it, this whole family is not normal,
Everyone's stressed about Grandma Chava,
Who would think, Gila Almagor.
-Yeah, right,
Seriously, what’s the stress? An exhausted 80-year-old woman, what’s the big deal?
Enough, Gila Almagor is 80?
-What?
Cinderella, that’s what I am, Cinderella.
I held the house for her,
she worked me to the bone.
And she always had something to say about everything.
Criticism, criticism, criticism.
Shay, ease up on the schnitzels a bit.
I only had two.
-You had five.
One thing I promised myself,
I won’t be a mom like her
and I succeeded, I’m not like her.
Right, I succeeded?
-What?
Of course I succeeded, I’m not a mom like her,
she’s a monster.
Me, what an awful woman.
Come on, I’ll give you an example.
I sat with Dad and her in the living room quietly
because she doesn’t like noise.
We sat in silence like mice so she wouldn’t
have any reason to complain about anything
and then I cleared my throat.
Did she notice?
-I didn’t say anything.
You made a sound.
-She cleared her throat, Chava, that’s all.
You cleared your throat.
-Maybe.
Why did you clear your throat?
I don’t know, just.
-Just?
People clear their throats sometimes, Chava.
-People don’t clear their throats for no reason.
You need therapy.
-No, I don’t need therapy.
She doesn’t need therapy, Chava.
-I understand.
So you probably cleared your throat because of the dust in the apartment.
What are you talking about? There’s no dust here.
-There’s no dust here, Chava.
The shelves are full of dust.
It wouldn’t hurt you to take a cloth and wipe once in a while.
My house is clean, Mom, there’s no dust here.
There’s clean and there’s clean.
And it's not crying.
Besides, it's hot in here.
The AC is set to 16 degrees, honey. It can't get any colder.
So your AC isn't good.
You know you're a creation of a creative creator,
that color isn't good for your hair.
You're doing this on purpose.
-Mom, enough.
This is my house, and if I feel like it, I
can clear my throat as much as I want, okay?
You have a problem.
-No, I don't have a problem,
you have a problem.
I'm heading to the kitchen.
-Run, run,
you always find a reason not to face the world.
Right, Pen...
Pinchas?
And she's been here since Wednesday, Shai,
I can't take it anymore.
But it's almost over, Mom, just a little longer.
Almost over? She's as healthy as a horse,
she'll bury us all here.
No, I meant she's going back
to assisted living on Sunday. Not dead.
So, what are your kids wearing?
What?
Horrible.
-Thanks.
And the pigtails? Shai.
Horrible.
-Thanks.
So where's Grandma, actually?
Dad.
What's wrong, missing Grandma?
No, I don't want her to surprise me,
I want to be ready.
Why are you yelling?
-Mom.
You startled me.
-Yeah, but why are you yelling?
You know Grandma Chava doesn't like it when people yell.
What turned out in the end? That it's also because of my connection.
-Okay, okay.
But where is she?
-I don't know,
if she's not here, she's probably in the bathroom.
She's not, I just checked there.
-Are you sure?
Yeah, Dad, it would be very upsetting
to find out I peed on Grandma Chava.
Again?
Excuse me?
-I was three.
You were a week old.
-It slipped my mind, and I don't want to talk about it.
So where is she?
-She's probably in the kitchen, driving Mom crazy.
She's not! Mom's driving herself crazy.
Oh, good, I'm going to grab a schnitzel
because I'm starving.
Wait, so where is she really?
-Maybe she's on the balcony, thawing out.
Honey, go check.
-When?
Now.
I just sat down.
Wait, wait, hold on, hold on,
Honey, have you seen Grandma Chava by any chance?
How nice, thanks.
What did she say?
-I have no idea.
Well, she's not there.
-What do you mean "she's not there"? So where is she?
Pinchas, was she here?
-Of course she was here. Did she disappear?
She disappeared.
-Dad, relax.
I prayed to a strong creator
but I didn't believe it would really happen.
It's fine.
-No, I'm dying.
Okay, we need to go look for her.
She's probably around here somewhere, we need to go down and search.
-Of course.
Wait, wait, we have to tell Riki,
everything is timed with her
and dinner might get ruined.
R Nia.
Chavcha to the
building.
Shani, come on, let’s go down.
-Come on.
Wait, just a second.
Pinchas, you said we need to tell...
-I’m going to get a flashlight.
Wait, but why me?
No, I’m dying. No, I’m really dying.
In Petah Tikva, may their memory be blessed. Son...
Curtain?
-Curtain.
She didn’t want to buy me a dress,
so I took down the curtain and made myself a dress.
Isn’t that Sara, the heroine of the BIL?
-I’m Sara, the heroine of the BIL,
I survived life with Grandma Chava,
I’m a hero.
She chased me around the house later because of the dress,
with a ladle in her hand.
-Ladle.
After that, she said that’s why
I have beautiful legs to this day.
Hey, Riki.
-Hey.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
I wanted to say...
-Today we’re starting to eat at exactly eight.
Okay.
-Not a minute later.
Sounds good.
I’m saying this mainly to you
because you have a tendency to ramble.
Me? Okay, I just want to say something,
how do I put this?
Like this,
wait, from the beginning, what I’m trying to say...
-Just talk, go ahead.
You see? Your wife should go into politics.
Seriously, she can’t say
one sentence without going around in circles.
Okay, so what I...
-You’re also a bit of a teacher today, you know?
That dress doesn’t look good on you.
-Grandma Chava is a lady, okay?
She’s a lady. Is that clear?
That was clear enough. Right, honey?
Is that clear? She’s a lady.
Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom?
Hello?
-Adamka, you made it.
Dad, what’s going on? Where is everyone?
What, are you alone?
-Yeah. I heard Grandma Chava is here,
there’s a limit to what I’m willing to put a girl through.
Grandma Chava is the limit.
Come on, where is she?
-A lady.
What lady?
-Lady, lady, let’s go down and look for her.
Wait, wait, I want to say hi to Mom.
-Are you normal?
First, let’s find Grandma Chava,
then you can say hi to Mom.
If we don’t find Grandma Chava
in 20 minutes,
the soufflé will dry out, the fish will fall.
Do you want to tell her that?
Does she know she’s a lady?
-I don’t know and I don’t want to know, let’s go.
I saw she’s going to ruin my meal.
She saw I’ve been working hard since yesterday
and it hurt her, you understand?
It hurt her.
Did you check the attic, maybe she’s there?
-She’s not home, honey.
Everyone went down to look. Should we go down too?
-Let’s go down.
We eat at exactly eight, with or without Grandma.
Grandma.
-Honey, why are you shouting "Grandma"?
There are probably a lot of grandmas living here, you’re stressing them out.
Okay, what do you want me to do?
-I don’t know. What, don’t you have a whistle or something?
Grandma Chava.
You know, the truth is, Grandma Chava and I,
we never really bothered each other.
Lately, I’ve felt
like she’s not talking to me at all.
Better this way, believe me.
The last time I saw her...
How are you, Grandma?
-It was good until I saw you.
What are you wearing? You look like a farmer.
Is that a bad thing?
-No, it's not a good thing.
You're my grandson, what will people say?
That Chava's grandson is a bum?
Wandering around in rags on the street.
This is what Shani bought him.
Shani, is that the woman?
-Yeah.
Oh, come on.
-What?
Did your wife buy you that?
Fathers
Sons
I think so.
So tell her to stop, her taste in clothes
isn't exactly her strong suit.
Okay.
What’s this?
-I told you, she's a tough woman.
But why me?
-But she's my mom,
that's her way of showing she's okay
and saving me in the process.
Okay, but why are you putting this on me?
-She's my mom,
she has instincts, reflexes, a survival instinct.
Say thank you that I'm buying clothes,
because if it weren't for me, you'd still be wearing
your underwear from when you were 16.
Why are you making such a big deal out of this?
Go, go tell your mom, let her buy you clothes.
Seriously, great, now it's on me.
Grandma.
-Grandma Chava.
Grandma Chava.
-Adam,
Adam.
-What?
She's been with us since Wednesday, give me a moment of peace.
Tough, huh?
-Tough, tough.
You know, Dad, I have to say
I'm actually getting along with Grandma Chava.
Really?
-Yeah. I think she likes me.
Liked.
What do you mean?
Adam, listen, she had no choice,
she surprised us.
We were sitting quietly in the living room as usual and then...
So that means we're doing the order here.
We're not doing order anymore.
-Excuse me?
We're not doing order anymore because...
-Because we're not Jews anymore.
Pinchas.
-We are Jews,
Chava, but Adam, Adam is no longer Jewish.
Excuse me?
-He met a girl from the sector and he...
Converted, Mom.
-He's in the process now.
He asked us to respect
his customs! And celebrate the holiday with them.
But you can come with us to her village,
Mukharrar...
for Eid al-Fitr, if you want.
Over my dead body.
Are you guys normal?
-For real, it was instinct.
Muslim? Muslim?
You’re not normal, you’ve killed me. That’s it, I’m done.
-Adam.
She’s going to kill me.
She’ll chase me with a ladle! She’ll kill me.
There are really nice girls in the sector.
-Oh, come on, do me a favor.
You just threw your son into the territories.
Worse, into Grandma Chava's hands.
You don’t do things like that.
Adam, you’re right.
-I know.
But believe me,
four days with her and I’ve lost my humanity.
Adam, Adam, listen.
-Leave me alone.
-I’m calling B'Tselem.
-Adam.
My head is about to explode, I need
to drink something. Is there a café around?
What café? It's Friday today,
This area is full of religious people, there's nothing around here.
What, there's no place to sit for a bit?
Don't you need to empty out?
-Always.
But if I need to, then I’ll just...
No, you can't. People are coming back from synagogue.
They shouldn't be exposed to that.
Wait, there's the...
Sergey’s café right by the gas station.
Is that a café?
-Kind of.
Do they have coffee there?
-Black.
No, I'm dying.
Alright, let's go.
Hey, Sergey, make me a coffee.
Is there anything to put in the coffee?
Alexei. Sergey is the owner.
There's vodka.
-That works.
What’s up, you guys?
-Just for coffee.
Sergey, add more sugar.
Alexei.
-Alexei. Sorry.
Tell me, Pinchas,
how long are you going to use the excuse of Grandma Chava
as Shai's limited and clueless wife?
-Calm down, I just found out I converted to Islam.
There you are. No, I'm dying,
this is a convenience store with plastic chairs.
Sit down.
-Sergey's coffee.
Where's Itamar?
-Guess.
Shame on you.
-What happened to you?
This is really annoying.
Shai, can I go with you for the rest of the patrol?
-Of course.
I'm with Pinchas.
-And me?
My husband ran away because of that one over there.
How much longer
until the soufflé comes down and the fish dries out?
Five minutes.
I'm hungry.
-Me too.
Just five more minutes, girls.
I know, it’ll be over soon. Okay, sweetheart?
So what...
How's it going?
-Fine.
Life. What's up?
So-so. So-so plus.
Nice.
Yeah.
How's work?
You know, the same thing.
-Yeah?
Nothing new, no...
No.
How about you?
-No.
No... not really.
What, Mom?
-Don't answer her.
Until I get a chance to talk to you like this.
She should call Dad. Look, she’s given up.
In short, she keeps nagging him,
and he’s like not even listening
to what she’s saying and she’s going on and on
and he doesn’t care what she has to say, you know?
She just won’t stop drilling
and he’s like totally not into her.
Disaster.
-So what’s new?
Nothing. How about you?
Just let’s stay healthy.
-Yeah, that’s the most important.
Riki?
Not answering? Let her call Itamar.
-What a scene.
About a month ago, Riki calls me...
Well, I turned her down,
After five minutes, you hear? Are you listening?
Our neighbor knocks on the door, Riki's on the line.
And what does she call me about?
She wants back... you hear?
She wants back those boxes
of the shlayklech.
There's no point in me trying to make small talk, right?
-No, there's not.
Maybe
come on
Let’s go back to Sergei’s café and that’s it.
Well, I’m really happy to have
Friday night dinner
with the people I love most in the world,
my grandkids,
who love their grandma and I love them
and they don’t always come to her with complaints.
The mashed potatoes are cold.
-The schnitzel is salty.
Oh, you too? Great.
Raz. Raz, stop playing.
Grandma, you look really pale, you know
that color doesn’t suit your hair.
Six, Sasha.
-Alex.
Wow, I’m dying.
So you guys came back here too?
Say, and Vada.
Victor.
-Alexei.
Can you give me more of that coffee?
Where’s Itamar?
-He’s over there, he said it’s because he drank.
There he is again.
-Come on, really.
Sorry to interrupt, guys.
-Don’t send us home.
No, no, no. Listen up. It was
about half an hour ago, 20 minutes.
Good evening to you.
-Good evening.
I guess there’s no menu here.
Not really.
-Too bad.
This place has potential.
-It’s not mine.
Are you an employee here?
-Working.
Is there something the lady wants?
-Thank you.
I assume there’s tea here.
-Of course.
Grandma Chaya.
-Grandma Chaya.
Excuse me, can I hide in your kitchen for a sec?
-Sure, sure, come on in.
You’re a righteous among the nations, you know that.
Righteous among the nations.
I think her husband stopped chasing me.
But then, after you left...
They left, they’re worried about you.
Maybe you shouldn’t run away like that.
-You’re sweet, worried.
If I were you, I’d be worried about the health ministry.
Do you see what she did in the kitchen?
-I only work Fridays.
So how do you protect your rights?
What rights?
-Employee rights.
Just wait until you’re my age,
you’ll understand what social security is.
Listen, I’ll give you a phone number
of someone who works there, Sergei.
-Alexei.
That guy’s name is Sergei.
It started with social security
then went to why I’m not married,
what clothes I buy and why
I’m not doing something with my life.
So excuse me, I’m resigning.
Your grandma’s in the kitchen!
I knew that balloon looked familiar.
I’m not going back there.
-Okay.
It’s really just for the next few nights,
I hope I’m not bothering you.
-No, it’s totally fine, it’s really fine.
It’s still not working.
Grandma, that’s the coldest the AC gets here.
When was the last time you filled up on gas?
-What, that's Sh...
Sunday the antenna "enter the monastery."
-I won't be here on Sunday.
Is this the music you play for your hearts?
Why don't you play them "The Sound of Music"?
They, Mozart's Requiem,
it's really full of life.
I see you've caught Riki's bug.
Okay, but it's as cold as a prison, in a grave.
What? What?
-Sorry.
Where is everyone?
-Around.
Grandma Chaya is alive. Sorry.
Yeah, an 80-year-old girl,
no pulse, no blood pressure and...
What happened?
An 80-year-old girl.
It started to crash with the girl,
no pulse, no blood pressure.
I peed on Grandma Chaya.
Excuse me?
-I was three years old.
Pee.
-What, pee isn't good?
Cute three-year-old, pee.