Come on, babe, you're not that pathetic.
-I'm gonna die.
You sound just like Mom.
I feel that sting right here,
you know it's coming.
Okay, fine, come on, you can fight it.
No, it's pointless.
-I don't get it.
Why is it that whenever you guys are sick, you're all dying?
And I'm not talking about your ethnicity,
I'm talking about the whole gender thing.
Babe, maybe it's that new flu
that's going around this week.
And I'm the first victim here in the country?
-What a Shakespeare.
Molière
-What?
Molière wrote "The Imaginary Invalid."
No, I meant your Shakespearean drama.
But you just opened a whole new topic here.
The Imaginary Invalid?
-No. No topic, no...
You don't believe me. Put your hand on your forehead,
you're getting a third-degree burn.
Oh, what nonsense. It's nothing,
it's not serious at all, you don't have a fever.
I might infect your family.
They'll all blame me.
First of all, I'm taking responsibility for this. Okay?
And secondly, in my family, we don't get so worked up
about illnesses like in your family.
And if they haven't lost you by now,
trust me, they won't lose you today either.
And don't forget we're a vaccinated family.
-How vaccinated?
Strong. The Hasson family, vaccinated.
Strong.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Oh, Shabbat Shalom. Shabbat Shalom, Shabbat Shalom.
What's up, Dad?
-All good.
Sitting with Pharaoh! Trying to fix the computer.
Pharaoh, Pharaoh, Pharaoh.
What, talking to Efrat today?
-Shabbat Shalom.
What's wrong with you, are you sick? Really?
Yeah, Dad, Shai's like me. When he has a cold
he's in total system failure,
he's dying like crazy. He came here for
his last supper.
-You're just exaggerating.
Exaggerating, exaggerating, but I'm asking you
to stay away from me, please.
I wanted you to help me with the computer but I'd rather
you keep my space sterile.
I didn't know you were this hysterical.
-You told me the Hassons are vaccinated,
they have immunity...
-Just this week they talked on TV
about an outbreak, Adobe.
They talked about families of viruses.
For you, every virus is the size of a cockroach.
Sit down, I'm going home.
No, you don't need to go home. Why home?
Go to the kitchen, why are you standing here, go to the kitchen.
Great idea.
Dad, what's wrong, come?
-What?
Where's Mom?
-She's on a wrap-up call with Meirav.
Why a wrap-up?
-Meirav is going abroad,
so she's having wrap-up calls with all the family members.
She started with your mom.
Mom, I'm going with Orna to Hollywood,
I don't know if I'll come back with her
after a week because there's a bigger chance
I'll find a Hollywood husband
and stay there forever, like, forever.
Meirav, have you lost it?
What, you think it's easy to find a husband in Hollywood?
Well, that's not up for discussion, I'm just letting you know.
Besides, it's Hollywood, Mom,
everyone lives in a movie there.
Yeah, in a bad movie, directed by Uri Paster.
What about Efrat?
-Efrat's not an actress.
Her husband’s not an actor, and they actually met here.
Just so you know, you and Dad
never supported what I do,
you always blocked my luck. Everything that happened to me in life
happened because of you.
That's why I'm leaving and starting fresh.
Page bio.
-Okay.
Oh, and one more thing. I made a deal with a good friend of mine
that if I don’t come back,
I’ll rent her my room.
What’s that?
-600 dollars a month,
fifty-fifty, it’ll help me cover my stay there
and you guys won’t be bored here either.
-What’s that?
She’ll probably get used to you,
just like I did.
But I’m not used to you yet.
Well, if you have any objections,
it doesn’t matter
because you should have said that
before the deal was closed.
Sorry, now it’s too late.
Ah, it turned out tasty today, right?
I don’t know, I can’t taste anything.
All my taste buds are blocked. It’s hard for me to feel.
That’s why the cooks in hospitals don’t invest,
because no one can taste anything.
I’m done.
-I’m done too.
Alright, girls, you can go play now.
Sit, honey, do me a favor, if you love me,
let me go home to rest.
-No, honey, because I love you,
I won’t let you drive like this when you’re sick.
-You said I’m not sick.
You said I am.
-Ugh.
Come on, come warm up a bit.
Just be careful not to overheat.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom, Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom. How are you?
-We’re okay,
the baby was sick and just yesterday he got better.
Oh, right, if you don’t want him to get sick again,
keep him away from Shai because Shai’s in the kitchen and he’s sick.
Sick?
-Yeah.
Alin, sweetie, wouldn’t it be better to go home?
-Come on, don’t exaggerate,
we’ll keep me away from Shai, and that’s it.
-Okay, it’s your responsibility.
When does Shai need to leave the kitchen?
-You know that generally,
Shai doesn’t leave kitchens easily.
-Stay with him?
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom, Mom.
Shabbat Shalom, Rachel.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Meirav’s in her room. She wants you to come in.
What does she want?
-No, she’s got some bug in her head
that she’s not coming back from abroad,
so she’s having wrap-up talks with everyone.
And she can’t do them from Los Angeles?
Because I see the computer’s outside.
What, are you talking to Efrat today?
Right, and I want you to help me
put it together, I can’t manage.
Later. Go, wash something here first.
-I’m really worried
about the germs Shai’s spreading in the air,
but on the other hand,
hunger is stronger.
Let me know when I can wash the kids.
-I’m coming to deal with the germs.
Come on, what did she tell you?
That because of us she is what she is?
-Yeah, yeah, also. Of course.
She said that if she stays there
longer than the week she planned,
yeah?
-She wants to rent her room
to her friend.
-What?
She’s like a protected tenant,
and she wants to rent her room.
In subletting.
-I have no problem with her staying forever.
Abroad, okay? Just that, she can't,
she can't take ownership of...
What did you say? What did you say? That she wants to rent
her room to someone else?
And you're okay with a stranger
living in our house?
-Don't worry, I'll handle it.
It was fine.
Between us, Sali, it can't get worse
than the current tenant.
What's true is true.
-True.
Manny, you're in a hugging frenzy.
-Yeah, talk to me when you hit 39.4.
Three days in a row.
-Hey, how are you feeling, sweetheart?
I'm fine, oh my, the man on his deathbed.
Shai, are you okay? How are you feeling?
Thank you very much.
-Honey, do you want me to put something on your plate?
I won't eat until Shai finishes.
I don't want to catch his dysentery.
And then spread it to the kids.
That's just what we need.
What happened? So your kids will catch it,
why are you panicking?
How much can we be sick?
Really, they're always sick,
and not alone. Either all together or one after another
or in pairs.
-Okay, honey, come on, let's go to the balcony.
There's good air for the germs out there.
To the balcony?
-Yeah, yeah.
It's okay, it's not that bad.
Look, usually there's no problem
if someone here is sick at our house,
but today, you understand,
there are happenings. You're not mad, right?
-No, why...
Okay, honey...
-What.
Want me to heat up some bourekas with the majluf?
-Of course.
Fine, but in the meantime, serve it to Meirav,
she wants to say a few things before the flight.
Okay, I'm going to check in with her.
Are you done eating?
-I'm not done, they're moving me to the balcony.
I'll set up his food on the balcony.
Like Jason?
-Yeah, sweetie.
Who's Jason?
-That's our dog,
he eats on the balcony.
-Dog...
At least you don't have to eat Bonzo.
Can we go to the kitchen now?
Dad, I didn't mean to drag him like that.
-Drag?
To drag him, you need a crane.
-Oh, stop it.
Shabbat shalom.
-Shabbat shalom.
Oh, I see you took out the
computer today. You must be talking to Efrat.
Yeah.
-No, no, no, but I want it to be a surprise.
No mention that Meirav and I are coming.
I want to call her from there, from the hotel.
Wow, congratulations, I didn't tell you.
-What a coincidence.
Wow, what's this? He knows you're not an actress, right?
Of course, that's the first thing I told him.
It just happened by chance.
But that's not... it, right?
-No, no, what are you talking about?
I checked, everything, I asked. Serious production.
What, cool. So what, what are you playing? What's the role?
Oh, it's without... talking.
I'm playing the Israeli wife
of some guy involved
in some local corruption scandal.
Something like... three days of shooting.
But a week in Sinai.
-Yeah.
Why is Shai eating on the balcony?
-Shai is sick,
and he shouldn't infect any of us.
Wow, so I really need to keep
double the distance, because I really don't want
to miss this trip.
-Hey, Shabbat shalom.
My sweet girl. I always knew
you could be a Hollywood actress.
Okay, Mom, it’s not really a game.
Just a chance to meet Efrat.
Perfect, just perfect.
-Too bad I can’t go.
Speaking of which, Meirav is doing summary calls now.
Summary calls? What else is she doing?
She’s sticking a goat in the house.
If Meirav doesn’t come back from abroad,
she’s renting her room to her friend,
I mean, she’s sticking a tenant here
in the house.
What? But that’s not really her room,
you guys are the ones deciding.
Like what, did she tell you she’s a protected tenant?
Yeah, yeah. What do we need
strangers in the house for?
Just when I can finally
walk around freely in my own house.
In your underwear?
-Dad, come on.
Moshe, quick, say Moshe! So I can think about Moshe! Another one.
What? What, are you embarrassed to walk around in your underwear
near the goat? What does she understand, goat. What... what...
Moshe, I get it.
-Come on, sis, what did I do to you?
Are you kidding me?
-Come on, I’m so happy for you.
Amen, catch a millionaire,
send him some money back home.
Why amen?
-What, can’t I joke with you?
That’s exactly the point, you guys always
joke about me, don’t support me
and don’t believe in me.
-We’re not joking about you-
We’re just teasing you.
-That’s exactly what I wanted to talk to you about.
I get it, I want you to be a real brother,
someone who stands by me, supports me.
You were never there, not when it was bad
and not when it was worse.
What suddenly makes you want to
bring a stranger into the house? What suddenly?
They’ll think! That we’re still dependent.
-Shh.
Wait, you want her not to go,
to stay here?
Oh man, how that threat always comes up in the end.
Oops, that’s in the conference.
I thought it was over, that’s it,
I felt some kind of total release, some revolution,
like Tahrir Square,
!suddenly bam, scary.
Sali, enough. All we need
is to hope she finds her place there,
and we’re here, the new tenant will manage.
I can’t deal with this computer.
Silvan, there’s some problem with the computer.
The computer has no problem, you have a problem.
-Two slaps on the board
of his mom-mom and it works
like a horse. Is the bulletin ready?
How was it in the principal's office?
-Tough.
She gave me all negative feedback.
Dad, Dad.
-Dad!
What, honey, what happened?
I finished eating and I want to go home, to rest.
It’s cold here, it’s hot here,
I’m not comfortable with this isolation. I want to go home.
So what, you just came to eat and leave?
You said you wouldn’t isolate me from your family
and look where I am?
Okay, what do you want me to tell your mom,
that I left you home alone like a dog?
Sorry. I’m not...
-Sit.
I thought you understood computers better than me.
What, I don’t?
-I talked to who.
Dad, it’s this stupid computer,
you need to replace it,
it’s not that expensive.
-Girls, girls,
you’re bothering Grandpa from concentrating.
-Yeah, girls, maybe you could go
play somewhere else? Go out to the balcony.
-Ah ba ba ba...
Shai’s on the balcony, you can’t go out there.
-Okay, I’ll take him from the balcony,
so the girls can come in. Honey, come on,
the girls want to come into the balcony.
Great, so can I go hide somewhere?
-Yeah, come on.
To the bedroom?
-No, Meirav's in there.
So?
I'll take you to the bathroom.
-How am I supposed to relax in the bath?
It’s just a few minutes.
-So bring me a pillow or something?
Just put a roll of toilet paper
under your head, it’s comfy. Come on, babe.
-What?
-Here.
Okay, fine. Can you come here for a sec?
-Yeah.
Orna, I’m really hungry.
-Come on, let’s eat,
you can continue that later.
-Here, here. Here’s the problem.
You forgot to turn on the screen.
-Oh.
Did you see?
-Dad, can you buy a laptop today
for 300 bucks?
With a camera inside.
-Right.
Where am I supposed to get 300 bucks, come on?
That’s good enough, just drop it. It’s fine.
Yeah, Meirav, I’m ready.
-Okay, don’t stress.
I’m not stressing, come on, talk.
-I’m not saying anything.
Ah, Meirav, it’s not cool right now
for you to act all hurt.
I’m not going to beg you,
come on, Meirav, talk, Meirav, talk,
just talk already!
So here’s the deal. Sit down, you probably already know
that I’m leaving.
The ticket for me is one-way,
and I’m at a crossroads in my life.
I’m leaving all my failures
and the...
and the few successes behind,
and I want to start fresh.
Great, you have my blessing.
But before I go, I wanted to tell you
a few words of criticism about your performance as a sister.
Why just a few words? Come on, bottom line.
Grade. What?
-That’s exactly what I wanted to tell you,
that you never had patience for me.
At least I’m consistent.
Sorry to interrupt, but I think
you guys should first check
who this girl is. Maybe she’s a kleptomaniac?
They’ll take stuff from your house,
you won’t have a problem saying.
Anyway, make a proper contract with her.
-What a mess.
For weeks, weeks I’ve been dreaming
of a man under his vine, a man under his fig tree
and under his olive tree.
Come on, why are you making such a big deal?
We’ll try. If it doesn’t work out, we’ll tell you to leave.
But she’ll also be a protected tenant.
Wait, is she also going to eat our food?
-It’ll stay, we won’t let her?
Maybe it’s better if you write to me, I’ll put it in the freezer.
There’s no room in the freezer. The freezer is full of leftovers.
There are leftovers in the freezer?
-When was the last time you checked the freezer?
Okay, who haven’t I talked to yet? Alin. Come here.
Miri gave me the main points.
Okay. Orna! Has Moshe Katz arrived yet?
-In the kitchen.
Orna!
Psst, psst.
-Bismillah, you scared me. What’s up?
You left me here.
-Left you? I didn’t leave.
I thought you weren’t coming back.
Can we move?
No. Not yet, not yet, babe.
Come on, let’s go to the bedroom,
Meirav just cleared it out. Come on.
-Okay.
Slowly, slowly.
Wow, I’m so excited I can’t eat.
I can’t take a bite.
Just so you know, Meirav, everything you achieve
in Hollywood will be thanks to me,
Because I was the one who was supposed to go, not you.
-Thanks, Moshe.
You've always been on guard.
-Thanks.
Alright, I’m done here, I’m heading to the living room.
But the summary...
You'll have me for a week of summaries.
So what,
you’re leaving.
I mean not coming back,
not that you know, God forbid.
Why? For whom?
And I also mean coming back,
not that you know, God forbid...
So what exactly is your role there?
-I’m the hero's wife.
So you’re the heroine.
-No need to exaggerate.
He’s the hero, I’ll be in the background,
it’s a small role.
There’s a big rule that says: there are no small roles,
only lousy actors.
-Dad...
I would be so happy to go there.
They don’t need some Russian spy there, like...
How should I know?
Have fun, my sister.
-And make sure Meirav doesn’t do anything stupid.
Find a groom!
Amen.
-Amen.
Sit down, my whole body is shaking,
my back is killing me from the bathtub.
What? You were lying in the bathtub?
-You told me to.
Well, I was joking with you.
-Sit down, I want to go home, now.
The illness could still get complicated.
There are cases that ended in death.
No, no, no. Death isn’t a fool.
It comes to those who least expect it.
What? What does that mean? That my mom
and your grandma will never die?
You know you’re irresponsible
and a first-class egoist?
What happened? I thought we finished the conversation.
-I haven’t finished.
Aren’t you ashamed to bring your sick husband here?
You want him to infect me
with his germs so I can’t go abroad
and because of that, I won’t get married?
Now you’ve figured out my evil plan.
Oh-my-God!
Why would a kid living with his parents
rent his room to someone else?
Don’t agree to that.
-It’s not that simple.
To make sure she’s not a protected tenant,
you have to make a contract
for every child over 18. Otherwise
one day you’ll find yourselves on the street.
I wouldn’t be surprised if she says she
didn’t agree with Meirav on which room
to choose for the son as the bedroom.
Then she’ll bring a lawyer,
and we’ll have to sleep in the fridge.
-Sali, you’re exaggerating again,
you’re already sleeping in the fridge.
-Maybe I’ll go with Orna
and then the girls can stay here with Meirav.
No, no.
-No, no. Let her go and enjoy.
Yeah. Anyway, let her take her time too.
Maybe Meirav will even come back with me after a week?
Why? Why always think the worst? Why?
Dad, imagine you’re running to the bathroom with a stomach ache.
Suddenly the new tenant, let’s call her Aleph for example,
is stuck in the bathroom with her own stomach ache,
and you’re under pressure.
Wait, is the tenant Aleph from the tourism office?
Aleph from the president's office or Aleph from the top of the police?
Aleph.
-Stop.
No, there’s no limit to Shabi’s chutzpah,
and you’re still approving it.
Since she was a little girl,
you always let her do whatever she wanted.
Dad, come.
-Yeah, sure.
What, to connect?
-Yeah, just need to send her a text,
so she can connect too.
-What time is it there now?
It’s ten hours behind. How much is that?
Wait.
-Seven in the morning.
So, is she awake already?
-She has kids. She's awake.
Ah, there you go. That's how it is.
Dad...
-M'r... Meirav.
Just a second.
-What?
Meirav, my dear,
You know I love you very, very much, right?
I want you to know that I'm
really, really sorry you're leaving us
for good.
-Not sure it's for good.
Never, Meirav, it's allowed,
you should never lose hope.
Please
huh?
Okay.
-Amen.
So that's it, why would you leave with a bitter taste in your mouth?
Why bitter?
-This tenant,
that you brought into the house, it's really uncomfortable for us.
You understand? Suddenly, she's like this...
I thought the 300 dollars
could really help you guys
with all the expenses.
-300?
No, no, what... what does...
what do you mean 300 dollars?
What? What are you talking about?
I didn't quite understand.
Mom didn't tell you?
-No.
She'll pay 600 dollars
and we'll split it fifty-fifty.
Oh, really? 300 dollars? That she's...
That's really not feasible.
Wait, is that every month?
-Yeah.
What, what are you saying?
Suddenly, I'm thinking this is really,
having a subletter live with me is even...
it's even great for me.
You get it?
Is the computer working at all?
-Yeah, I fixed it. You can connect.
She's connecting.
-Come on, hurry up, connect.
I miss you.
-Maybe we should call Shai?
No!
-No!
I don't feel like a mambo.
Okay, I'll make us some tea soon.
Efrat, Shabbat Shalom.
-Hi
Shabbat Shalom, how's everyone?
-Shabbat Shalom. Everyone's doing great.
Everyone here misses you, my sweet.
Okay, Mom, no need to shout.
Dad, you need a new camera for the computer.
-No problem, no problem. Okay.
What's up, babe?
-Sit down, babe,
when are you coming to visit? I miss you so much,
I miss all of you.
-Don't worry, we'll meet soon.
Shh.
-What shh?
No, nothing. Nothing. What's going on with you?
Honestly, not much. Because of the movie
they made about that guy from Facebook
now they're making all kinds of movies
like that about the tech world,
and there's this disgusting yellow channel
making a movie about Mike,
a not-so-flattering film. They're starting to shoot it this week,
and we're afraid it will hurt his business. I don't want that.
-What?
They're filming a yellow movie about my husband, Mike.
Who knows who will play me.
They'll never find! Someone as pretty as me, Efrat.
-What a shame, babe.
No, they didn't even write her a big role.
Otherwise, only Penelope Cruz would fit.
But I read the script, it's not a role with lines,
like I'm his puppet. What nonsense.
Sure, you know,
they'll bring some Israeli who looks like,
more or less like me, the poor thing won't know.
She's in a racist movie
about a Jew robbing Americans.
Oh, oh, oh.
-No, no. Don't take it too hard.
Mike has the best lawyers
there are, everything's fine.
Gisele! Rachel and Yael are still sleeping.
Maybe I should wake them up.
No, no. Don't wake them.
Not Yael and not Rachel.
You ruined my Shabbat.
Bye, sweetie.
-Kisses.
You're not doing that to her.
It doesn't have to be the same movie at all.
Hollywood is big, it's not Migdal HaEmek.
I decided to walk.
-No, no, honey, come on.
I'll take you home, come on.
-Really?
It's okay, you can stay.
I won't make it to the flight anyway.
Shabbat Shalom. Strong, blessed.
From now on, everyone blame Efrat
for me being single.
Shabbat Shalom.
-No.
I have immunity.
Enough, the $300 for the computer is gone.
-Silvan...
Stay away from me! Stay away from me!
Honey, turn off the AC. I'm cold.
Come on, honey, it's on heat. What's wrong with you?
Why do you act like this when you're sick?
Yes, Mom.
Shiko, you're sick.
Oh, you sound terrible. Are they taking good care of you?
Yes, Mom, yes.
What meds are you taking? What did the doctor prescribe?
Wait, I hope she didn't drag you
to her parents in this condition.
Want to come over? I'll make you chicken soup,
Google Moogle, something to eat.
You have to get out of there. Are you in bed?
-I'm fine, Mom.
Shai, don't be a know-it-all.
She's going to ruin my kid. Pinchas!
The kid sounds terrible.
Mom, check-
God, God. Now I understand
why you're acting like this.
I was much better off
when we went to your parents. I need to rest.
It's okay, it'll be fine.
Like your mom says,
you'll run away in your grave.
Love you, Silvan-
Put your hand on your forehead,
you're getting a third-degree burn.
Honey, this...
My back is also stiff from the bathtub.
-What, did you shower in the tub?
You were sleeping.
Sit down...
-Honey...
Alif is the tenant from... m... the tourism office,
Alif from the employment office or Alif from the police department?
He said "employment office"?
-Alif is the tenant
from... m... the employment office?
Alif from the police department or Alif...
The tenant is Alif from... m... the employment office?
Enough, this isn't going to work.
The tenant, that's Alif from... m...
-Tourism.
From the tourism office. There are many tourism offices
on Ben Yehuda.
Two, one, action.