What?
-What... what did you do?
Good thing I went to the hairdresser,
otherwise you wouldn't even look at me.
They're giving you a compliment.
Instead of saying thanks, you're complaining.
I'm not complaining. I'm just stating a fact,
that it's really nice you noticed I went to the hairdresser.
-It really is nice.
Thanks.
What’s this? Did you dye it? Cut it?
-No, what are you talking about? Dye it, cut it?
Just tidied it up a bit.
New hairdresser, wanted to switch it up, got bored.
Rich people's problems.
Do you know how long it’s been since I went to a hairdresser?
How long, a month? Two months?
-What, I wish. At least six months.
We can't afford
for me to go to the hairdresser every month, you know.
If I went to the hairdresser every month,
my hairdresser would have opened a bank account.
Then going to the bank would be much nicer.
Some wouldn’t even switch banks for that.
So, how much did it cost, the hairdresser?
-Dad, are you mad?
No, honey. He’s just jealous he doesn’t have hair.
But he has hair in his nose.
-Shh. What...
Oh, look.
-What is it?
I found this little bag here.
-Open it. Let’s see what’s inside.
Wow...
-Ben Porat Yosef, blessed be His name.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Hurry up. Girls, girls,
go draw on the porch. Here are your colors.
Shabbat, Shani.
-What?
Not a word to my parents.
Why? What, do you really think
those jewels are real?
What, you think I know anything about this?
But I’m just raising a question, you know.
If they’re not fake, would you share them?
There’s nothing to raise and no sharing.
We’re returning this to the police.
On Sunday.
-No. I’m calling now for them to send a squad car.
But let’s think about it.
-I thought about it, I’m calling the police.
Sit down, sweetie, why the police?
Police means courts, restraining orders,
social workers...
Those are stories no one comes out of well.
Riki, Riki, what happened?
I volunteered for the civil guard once,
if that helps.
-Maybe show them what we found downstairs, Shai.
Thanks, Shabbat.
We found this little bag
and inside it...
-A treasure?
More or less.
Oh...
Zamir.
Did you notify the police?
Why the police?
-See, you get it?
Why the police? Tell me, don’t you have any sense?
If we found it, it’s ours.
No, that’s not true.
It belongs to someone and they’re probably looking for it.
I’m sure they’ll be happy! They’ll probably reward you somehow.
What reward...
-What “you”...
Well, it doesn’t matter now and it’s not up for discussion.
Riki, think that maybe there’s a person who planned
to sell those family jewels
for money for medicine. Do you understand?
How will I sleep at night?
You’ll sleep just fine at night.
If it was important to him, he should have
taken better care of it.
He should have considered that if someone
found it, they wouldn’t return it.
Riki...
Sit down...
Shai...
-Pinchas...
Sorry, it was at a fast pace.
Sit down, sweetie, how do you not see that Shai is right?
I don’t get it. God sends you a gift,
and it just happens to arrive on Shabbat,
and another thing, if God wanted
it to go to the police,
couldn’t He have just
left it by the police station?
Riki, remind me,
isn’t God the one who said "don’t steal"?
Wait. Who stole? Who was stolen from?
And what’s with the commandments all of a sudden?
Why bring up God for everything?
You know you shouldn’t take His name in vain?
Oh, the schnitzels...
-the schnitzels!
The schnitzels...
What’s going on?
What, everything’s fine with the schnitzels.
I just wanted to call you.
-Mom, that’s not nice.
You don’t do things like that.
-Don’t let her call the police.
Mom, she’s his wife.
-And...
And... the girls saw we found it too.
So what kind of education is that?
-Education is good only in theory.
In practice, everything’s corrupt in our country.
From the head of the wolf, it’s rotten all the way down,
the fish are spoiled and the stench reaches the heavens.
I’ll tell you what will happen. She’ll call
the police, they’ll come take it
and then they’ll keep it for themselves.
Uh-huh, and there’s no moral issue here?
Morality never stopped anyone from anything,
it just didn’t let anyone enjoy it.
Fine. Pinchas, I’m calling the police.
-Wait, wait, sit down.
If you call the police and it turns out
it’s just a little girl’s toy jewelry?
Wait a second, we need to check.
I have a magnifying glass here.
Yes. Let me check. One second.
What, what, what? Do you know about this, Pinchas?
Not really, but I saw someone do it once.
Fine, I’m calling the police.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom.
What’s this? Did you guys rob a bank?
Of course, Shai found it.
-What, is all this crap real?
Tell me, are you guys crazy?
You just throw this on the table?
The door’s open, anyone can walk in.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Honey, lock the door.
-Why lock it?
Shai found this bag with Itamar in the suburbs.
Wow, some poor guy lost this.
Honey, if someone lost something like this,
then he’s not poor.
Itamar, it doesn’t matter. We need to return it.
Right.
-What do you mean return it? Return what?
Sorry, we need to share it among everyone
and peace on Israel.
Itamar, we’re returning it.
-Fine, Itamar, I really don’t think like you
and I’m going to call the police now.
-Tell me, are you normal?
Do you think the Israeli police
have time to deal with this bag?
There’s a derby going on now.
-There are actually some really nice things here.
Michal, please return it.
-Sit down,
sit down.
-What?
Where are you taking this?
-It doesn’t matter. The main thing is, far from others.
But...
-Sit down, sit down.
I’m calling the police.
Shabbat Shalom.
Did you see the bag?
-Where did you find it?
Down here, by the parking lot.
-Were there any other bags there?
I didn’t look.
-How didn’t you look? Maybe there are more?
I’m not... I’m running to check downstairs.
Don’t let her call the police.
Come on...
-Honey, come with you?
Sit down...
-What?
You know I don't... I don't like
getting involved in other people's business.
Riki, I'm really sorry
but I didn't come to talk about the jewelry,
I came to call the police.
-No, no, no. It's fine.
It's not about that at all. You're totally right. Of course.
The connection between the girls is the most important.
I'm not that much of a witch.
No, I... I didn't say you're a witch.
Oh, thank you. At least that's something.
Riki, I'm sorry. What... what did you want to say?
Forget it, it's not...
-Okay, I'm sorry. What...
I'm listening. What?
-No, I'm just thinking
that you might think it's nonsense, everything I wanted to tell you.
No, no. No. Come on, what? Come here.
I just passed by and saw
they opened that new plastic surgery clinic here,
so I thought with your situation,
you're just in time to start looking into it.
What did you want to talk about?
-Forget it, it suddenly seems to me not...
No, wait a second, Riki - I wanted you to...
Do you think I need plastic surgery or something?
What do you mean "think"?
I think if you want to catch it in time,
you start at your age.
-At my age?
When things in the body start to age
you need to refresh them.
That's great.
-So you think I...
should only think ahead.
I'm afraid I understand too much.
Riki, I don't need any surgeries!
Are you sure?
-Yes.
Come on
and let's see
I have a good friend from the kibbutz,
and she has a really good friend,
a widow. She looks amazing!
She doesn't look a day over thirty.
And she did all the treatments.
And now she's living it up,
flirting with whoever she wants,
mostly with younger guys.
But those treatments cost a fortune.
What did she do, at a very young age?
She started a savings plan, a little money for a rainy day.
But why do I need to think a rainy day will come?
When the eyelids droop, all you see is black.
There's nothing.
-Did you look well?
Of course, babe. Tell me, tell me,
who are you planning to sell this to?
-I don't know. What...
Maybe you should post "Jewelry for Sale" online?
Yeah. Sure, babe. And then everyone who lost it will come
and also those who really lost it,
and all the jewelry will be gone.
Yeah, but I'm also afraid the police will find out we're selling
and then they'll catch us
and think we stole it.
What are you worried about, Shai?
She'll come to bail you out.
With the money from the jewelry
she can bail you out
and on the way, get Shai's cops
into early retirement.
I can't believe you guys are sitting
in my living room talking like thieves.
Who are we going to sell to, the police will catch us,
bail outs from detention...
In the end, only you will get arrested, Pini, because you're the homeowner.
Enough, babe, don't stress him out.
-What, but I don't understand you.
Shai said she's calling the police. Right?
-No, she's with Mom, so no way.
Shai, come here for a second.
-I'm coming.
Stay strong.
Babe, what's going on?
Your mom talked to me.
-I know. She talked to me too.
I really want to understand
how she dares to say something like that to me.
Babe, that's my mom,
she's been through a thing or two. She's confident about it.
And that somehow gives her
the right to interfere in my life?
Maybe you just... didn't understand her properly.
She just wants what's best for you! For me.
Oh, what's best for me? How does that relate to your benefit?
Because in the end, I should enjoy it too.
Right?
-Yeah, kind of.
True. Okay, so here,
Come on, tell me what I should do?
Okay, I think the best thing to do
is just to go with the flow.
-Oh. Go with the flow?
Yeah.
-Go with the flow.
What do you mean "go with the flow"?
What do you want me to go with?
What do you want me to do?
Should I bring it up? Should I stretch it?
Should I enlarge? What's wrong with that?
-What to enlarge?
Wait, babe, babe, what are we talking about?
About what? About all this stuff,
about eyelid lifts, breast enlargements,
facelifts...
-What? You don't need any of that.
Who put those nonsense ideas in your head?
-Your mom.
So my mom doesn't know what she's talking about.
Yeah, but she's been through some things in life.
After all, she's your mom.
Babe, eyelid lifts? What’s that? You're perfect.
Okay. Now I'm perfect?
You're just annoying! You're not objective either.
Yeah? You know what?
You want me to take a nude photo of you
and send it to some friends?
-Oh, do me a favor.
Objective.
-Do me a favor, Shai. Really. D.
Where's Shai?
-With Shai in the bedroom.
Well, I think it'll be fine.
-What's fine?
Say, where's Adam? What's going on with him?
He called saying he's running a bit late,
he's coming with someone new.
Listen, I don't think we should talk to Adam
about the whole jewelry thing.
You never know what kind of jewelry he'll bring.
And every time he surprises us more.
-What are you talking about?
About Adam, he's coming with someone new.
Well, I'm going to the kitchen.
Michal, I need you for a second in the room.
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Hello.
-Hey. Itamar.
Nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you. Mili. Hello.
Shai.
Hi.
-Do we know each other?
I don't think so.
-No?
No.
-Adam.
Yeah. This is Pinchas, my dad.
Nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you, Shabbat Shalom.
Nice to meet you, Mili.
Sit down. Michal.
-Let's go to the room.
So, Mili? Mili. What do you do?
Adam!
I can hear your voice,
aren't you coming to say hello to your mom
and introduce me to your new girlfriend...
Mili Tavalet?
Wow, Roko.
Did you see her? She's stunning.
Next week she won't be here anymore. Listen for a second.
-What?
I want to ask you something
and I really want you to be honest with me.
Just tell me the truth, even if it's
a bit uncomfortable for you. Okay?
Sure. What... what's the deal?
Look at me for a second, Michal, and tell me, really tell me.
Do you think I need
some kind of cosmetic touch-up?
Definitely.
-What?
Like, just a little bit,
you know, nothing dramatic,
but yeah, you need like... you know,
for maintenance. Like, a specific treatment.
Specific treatment?
-Specific, Riki.
That's Mili Tabavlat.
-Do I know her?
Gershon's widow.
-Which Gershon?
Tabavlat.
-The one who passed away?
Yeah.
-I didn't know his daughter.
How would I know who she is?
How's his daughter? That's his widow.
She was that young?
-Well, no.
Did you see what they did to her?
-No way!
You didn't tell me you're Riki Rosen's son.
Wait, so what's your connection to Mom?
-We have a mutual friend, Fanny.
Fanny from the country club?
What, you all know her?
-Only from stories.
What a coincidence. Why didn't you tell me
you're friends with Fanny from the country club?
You didn't ask, dear.
-Listen, it's really refreshing.
After all the girls Adam hangs out with,
it's nice to see someone who's more...
Are you serious?
-No, no, no. It's fine, it's fine.
It's fine.
-I'm just pointing out the fact
that you look over 35 and that's...
And when guys date younger girls,
what's up with that, is that okay?
That's not accurate, because when young girls date older guys,
they say it's because of their money.
Sorry, it depends on the age gap.
-What age gap?
Honey, come here for a sec.
I have to, sweetie?
-Yeah, sweetie.
Okay, sweetie.
-Get up, sweetie!
Umm... okay, so first of all
I want to say you look amazing.
I need your surgeon's phone number.
You probably remember it by heart. How does it go?
I won't let my little boy
date Mili Tabavlat.
She could be his mom.
-Yeah, but what can you do?
We need to separate them
before the glue dries.
I know this Mili, she's super clingy.
Okay, I'm going to tell him
you won't let this happen.
No. If you do that, he'll do the opposite
and you'll get the opposite result.
-So what do we do?
We need to do "divide and conquer."
I'll take Mili to the kitchen,
you stay with Adam.
I just talked to Michal
and she said I need to.
Need what?
-Those cosmetic treatments,
she knows about these things.
Did I tell you you're not objective?
Honey, you really don't need anything!
So why did she say that?
-Because she's messed up in the head.
Your mom said the same.
-Because my mom's messed up in the head too.
That's true.
Just so you know, more and more guys
are getting surgeries lately.
Honestly, I don't need
any of that.
I'm perfect.
-Maybe a hair transplant?
Sorry, that's an optical choice.
Mili.
Yeah.
-Can you come to the kitchen with me for a sec?
Sure, I'd love to help.
Crazy, right?
What, do they know each other?
Tell me, how old is she?
-Older.
Forty?
-I don't know.
My man, she's over fifty.
What fifty?
-What, haven't you seen her?
Fifty and... not a little bit.
Admica, tell me,
Why do you need to date someone
who's older than you by a few terms?
How many terms are we talking about?
Turns out it's twenty years or more.
-How do you know?
Admica, I don't think
you should date a widow.
You even knew the late husband.
-Ugh...
Look, listen! I'm good.
I have no idea how old she is,
I don't know who her husband was,
I don't know where she works,
And I don't care. She's got a body... amazing.
What's wrong with you?
-Adam...
We want you to bring home a woman
to have kids and a family with,
like it should be.
Why? So I can rush into all the poop and diapers?
No, because with Mili's age, you'll be dealing
with diapers from the other end, Admica.
So, how's it going, Mili?
-I'm doing great.
Lately, I can say I'm really thriving.
I can see that. And how's work?
Work's been really busy lately
but I'm not complaining.
Tell me, queen, what are you doing with him?
Do you want me to go into detail?
Do you think I need to save her from Mom?
They're friends of Fanny from the cafeteria. What’s there to save?
If you need help, just say so.
Especially now that Shai found some treasure
Treasure... a little bag.
So if you need help, just say.
Tell me, are you in a relationship?
Do me a favor...
-What, are you a ladyboy?
Hello, Adam. Cutie.
Yeah.
-Why are you so angry?
Mili and my mom...
-What, they don't get along?
More than that, they're friends from the cafeteria.
Mom! What’s this, how old is she?
-Older than I thought.
You're not doing this to your mom on purpose, are you?
Not this time.
Listen, if this is the girl you're willing
to fight with your family over,
then go for it.
-Okay, okay.
Look what plastic surgery can do.
I want you to understand him. He needs
to find the woman of his life.
You just want him as a pet.
So go find yourself a cat, a dog,
sushi, but understand him.
It's not like he was innocent.
I'm against it, Mili.
I demand you leave him alone.
Of course.
So everyone’s messed up in their heads?
-Who else did you ask?
Doesn't matter. Adam.
Adam. And his opinion matters to you?
Why not?
-Did you see what kind of girls he hangs out with?
I prefer a woman.
Is that your way of telling me I'm ugly?
Babe, you're not a model but you're perfect.
You fit me just right in all the right places.
You're growing up, nice.
I'm just saying, I like to look at you like this.
Well, you're not exactly a saint either.
Fine. But I could... let’s say I could promote...
Welding masks.
There's no middle ground, you know.
-True.
Dad, give him a few days, he’ll ditch you on his own.
What "a few days"?
You know what Mom can do to me in a few days?
It's a soul possession.
Adam.
-What?
I forbid you to date Mili Tavalet.
Dad, what are you doing?
Riki, just let me, I’ll handle it gently.
Gently. I’m crazy about him.
-Me too.
Gently!
-Gently, gently.
And this
“And this
Oh, here, meet her. Sit down, this is Mili Tavalet.
I was just telling her about you today.
-Shai, nice to meet you.
What a coincidence, wow, because when you said "Mili Tavalet"
I didn’t... I didn’t picture you like this.
Mili, tell me,
what things would you suggest she renovate
if she had enough money to renovate?
Mom, please, leave Shabi alone,
she doesn’t need any insurance.
Since when do you understand this? It’s just between women,
it’s not a guy thing at all,
and if you’re going to the living room,
invite everyone. We’re about to start eating.
Stay strong.
Shai, nice...
-Nice to meet you.
Let’s eat before Mom
drives Shabi even crazier.
Adam, my sweet, there’s such a big age gap
it’s impossible to bridge.
Why? Look, it works for me and Itamar.
Right, babe?
-Yeah, but babe, it’s not the same case.
Are you coming? Girls!
Why did you have to bring this up now? Huh?
Little fool.
So tell me, babe,
how much money are you willing
to spend on stuff like this?
Well, Shabi, no one here but me
thinks you need to do anything.
And your mom.
-My mom doesn’t say anything
unless she has some hidden agenda.
-What do you mean? What agenda?
She’s probably all about those surgeries
because she wants something else.
Try to think about what.
-What? No...
What interest does she have?
-When did she tell you that?
Look at what it says.
-How nice. What is it?
It’s an ad, saying whoever lost the pouch, it’s with us.
Nice.
Pretty.
The pouch... like it’s a doll
for the jewelry inside?
What jewelry? Pouch...
-No, no.
No, no, no, no.
What are we talking about?
-Where’s my phone?
Shai, what did you even say to her?
Turns out Shai found a pouch with jewelry earlier.
-Wow...
Where are you calling?
-The police. She wants to return them.
Adam.
-Come on, are you guys out of your minds?
What, don’t you remember what Mom always says?
That in the police, the fish stinks...
-No, no...
...from head to tail or something like that.
-No. No.
They’ll keep it for themselves.
-No, no.
What happened?
What Riki's trying to say
is that I'm a deputy superintendent in the police,
head of the investigations department.
Just like Riki says.
I don't think this will work out.
-I'm Shai, we're coming...
Where are the jewelry, the bag, what did you find?
-Here, here.
Take this, everything. We didn't take anything.
I'll take this with me.
-Thanks.
Still.
-Still, still.
Mom was really frustrated.
-I keep thinking
that I’ll postpone the surgery for a few weeks,
but if you want to treat me,
I’d love a pampering day.
If it’s cheaper than eyelid surgery...
-Of course. It’s the price of a third of an eyelid.
Then I’ll treat you.
-Great.
Are you treating me too?
-What do you want?
I want a nice facial treatment.
-No. I’m really sorry, it’s very expensive,
but I’m willing to invest in you a kilo of avocados from the market.
I’ll mash it up, spread it all over your face,
like this, you’ll be all green, it’s good for the skin.
What green, what am I, Shrek?
-Which Shrek?
Does Shrek suit you? Maybe the donkey fits better.
Riki, think that maybe there’s a person
who really planned, he planned
to sell this jewelry
to maybe buy medicine...
-No, no.
The wife... the widow of Gershon.
I’ll run downstairs,
check if there’s another bag there.
What happened to you? One bag is a sign of dozens of bags.
Move, move, and Shai, don’t...
-This is too much.
I have...
-Full as a pomegranate.
But what do I care?
-Admica...
She has a body... amazing. What’s wrong with you?
Adam.
-Look at him.
Got it? I’m bored.
-Oh, you’re bored. Rich people problems.
But I want you to bring someone home...
to have kids with you,
a family...