Can we listen to Rivat Gabai?
-Can we listen to Justin Bieber?
No, no, no, no Justin and no Rivat Gabai.
Enough already, today we’re listening to
what Mom and Dad want, enough.
Well, Per Olsson, the Swedish hit
that’s topping the charts worldwide
is visiting the country.
Tonight at the cultural hall.
Hey, why don’t we go
to a show at the cultural hall sometime?
He’s Swedish.
Do you know any of his songs?
-No, I wasn’t talking about his specific show,
any show, play, movie,
concert, melodrama, exhibit, something.
What’s that?
World music.
What a disaster, what is this?
Besides the song being bad and boring
the lyrics, what are those lyrics?
What, is it in German?
No, it’s Swedish,
it sounds like German but softer.
In German, if you want to say
"I love you,"
you say "Ich liebe dich."
It’s sharp, rough.
And in Swedish, you say
Jag älskar dig.
-Oh, really?
Like a sputtering Volvo.
I think about those Swedes,
what have they brought to the world
besides Volvo and ABBA?
What else do they have to offer?
True.
Tell me, how do you know how to say
"I love you" in Swedish?
What?
Change the subject, please.
Look at me, look at me and...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Shabbat Shalom, Dad.
Did something happen?
-No, no, everything’s great.
Great?
What did you do to her?
-Nothing.
Got it.
I just told her in the car
about a tiny romance I had once
and she got all upset.
Big mistake.
You made the mistake they teach in lesson one
at the school for beginner husbands
"Introduction to the Hurt Woman."
What’s the lesson?
Shut your mouth.
You understand?
Never tell her anything
about your past relationships
because they get really hurt by that.
But how can they be hurt if it was before
I even met her, before the army?
No, no, you don’t understand, you don’t get it.
Women don’t have timelines, past, present, future.
You understand?
Women have spatial time, for them everything is present.
Got it.
-Yeah.
So what do I do now?
-Nothing, move on to chapter two,
the apology.
Honey, what happened?
-Nothing, nothing.
What did Shai do?
-Just put me in some bad movie.
What movie?
-Turns out he had a fling with a Swedish girl at some kibbutz.
Which kibbutz?
-Beit Zera, I know which kibbutz.
Turns out he volunteered there
picking avocados before the army.
Son, that was before he met her.
Boy
Oh boy.
So why didn't he tell me?
-Did you ask him?
No, but still, she's Swedish, right?
Come on, sweetie, don’t think about it,
it just gives you heartache.
Forget it, it’ll be forgotten.
Okay, but why did he hide it from me
all these years? I don’t get it.
Shani, I couldn’t help but listen to the conversation.
I totally get you.
It’s just infuriating, and let me tell you,
from my messed-up experience with guys,
a guy who hides a little, hides a lot.
Come on, really, Shai, he’s such a good boy.
A good boy should have told everything
on the first or second date,
and preferably the first because there’s no second chance.
Okay, enough, Meirav, you’re exaggerating.
Shani, can I talk to you for a sec?
-Yeah, sure, no problem.
Just how do you say "please" in Swedish?
-Uh..
I don’t get the excitement
Israelis have for Scandinavians,
most of them, by the way, are big girls who don’t shave,
hairy for the sake of Helga, with blonde braids
and cowbells around their necks.
Honey, ask any guy in the world,
they’ll all tell you there’s nothing like Israeli girls.
-True.
Okay, I get that I need to apologize.
-Of course.
Look, this was before I enlisted
at some avocado farm up north.
I was dead, exhausted,
because the avocados there were huge,
big and heavy too,
and the guys had a few drinks.
A few volunteers showed up, that’s all.
What did I do wrong?
I just thought we had no secrets between us.
Shani, it’s not secrets, it’s history, okay?
It’s prehistory.
Fine, that’s your past, and now
you live in our shared present, right?
Shani.
-No, don’t call me Shani.
If you disconnect your past from our present,
then we won’t have a shared future together.
-Okay, okay.
I made a mistake not telling you.
-True.
Sorry.
It’s fine.
So how was she?
-Why? Why?
No, I want to know.
If I tell you, we won’t talk about it anymore?
-Yeah, go on, how was she?
I know, Swedish.
Blonde?
-Swedish.
What, tall, short, fat, skinny, big chest?
I don’t know? Like an avocado.
You said we wouldn’t talk about it anymore.
-You said that.
Go on?
-I apologized like a champ.
Fine.
-A ton of apologies and bowing down to the ground.
Not in the mood.
-Oh, not in the mood?
Tell me, did she ask you how the other one looked?
-Right.
Yeah
you, son
boy.
And you idiot, you probably told her the truth.
-Oh no.
Do I need to apologize again?
-No, no, you can’t apologize,
there’s no point in apologizing, it’s all lost now,
it’s complicated now,
it’s already a level three language course.
Who’s calling on a Friday?
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
This is Silvan Hasson’s apartment.
-Yes, Silvan Hasson, that’s me.
Big problem, I'm Dana,
can I talk to you for a sec in private?
What do you mean in private?
-No, it's fine, I have nothing to hide.
Please, have a seat.
-Thanks.
I'm again
in a big problem, and...
Dana.
-Sit down.
So my name is Dana and I'm the producer of a documentary
about the famous Swedish singer Per Olsson, you know him?
Hello, hello, nothing more than that.
Really?
-No.
But on the way here we heard in the car
by chance a rap song by that singer.
How is all this related to us?
So here's the thing, they're making a film on Swedish TV about Per,
Moshe! Like the master! Like that,
and I'm the producer on the Israeli side.
The story actually started when he
came to the country to find his lost dad,
he grew up without a father.
And because he's very, very famous
they decided to document this search in a documentary.
Nice.
-No, still not clear why you're here.
Because according to the research they did back in Sweden,
they discovered that his dad met his mom here in the country
at Kibbutz Ein Hores in the summer of 1966.
Wow... 19... check this out,
1966 I was at Kibbutz Ein Ha...
Yeah, and you met volunteers from abroad there.
Sali, is... is this real what's happening here?
No, Racheli, I'm hearing about this for the first time.
Of course, of course it's not real, obviously,
she wasn't Swedish, she was Scandinavian.
Sweden is a Scandinavian country.
-Oh, really?
Rachel...
-I told you I prefer privacy.
Excuse me, okay?
I'm Shani, I'm their daughter,
can you please continue the story?
Yeah, to make it shorter
-to shorten, yeah.
What actually happened is that after their brief romance
she went back to Sweden,
and your dad didn't know he left her
a little gift from the Holy Land
that later became the singer Per Olsson
who is actually your half-brother.
Wow.
Tell me, is it okay to include you in the film?
Racheli, come on, that was so long ago.
That was before we were together.
Before there was even a settlement law.
-I don't know, Sali, I don't know.
I was wrong, sorry, okay?
Okay.
What was she like?
-What do you mean what was she like? Come on, she was...
Short, she had this short hair,
with a blonde mustache, with stubble like that, come on.
Yeah, okay, okay, okay.
How was her voice?
-Her voice?
She didn't have a voice.
She spoke Swedish, I spoke
Hebrew, and we didn't even need to talk,
we just communicated with gestures.
-Oh, sure, with gestures,
who needs words when you have a talented choreographer like you-
Enough, Rach...
-Without words.
Listen, he came all the way to the country
for this, for the film,
he learned Hebrew.
If they refuse, it would be really nice
to at least talk to some of the family.
What, what are you saying?
Very problematic.
Maybe you should tell her that in Swedish too.
-Come on, babe, why...
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Who do we have the honor of meeting?
-Hi, Dana, film producer.
They're filming a movie about the Hasson family living in a movie.
That's interesting,
She's here to film a movie about Silvan
meeting his long-lost son from Sweden.
-What son?
So it turns out your dad
once had a fling with a Swedish volunteer
and he didn't know he left her with a kid.
No way.
-Absolutely.
That guy grew up to be a famous singer in Sweden.
Per Olsson?
-I think you're the only one who knows him.
And what does Mom say about all this?
-She doesn't say much,
she's more at a loss for words.
Wait, she didn't get the last word?
-Shh...
What's with the shh and the silence?
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom, Manny, Shabbat Shalom, Alin.
Sorry, I just want to know if everything's sorted out.
Can we start filming?
-No, absolutely not.
I thought you knew that book by heart.
I didn't know she knew it too, she...
She really surprised me.
Tell me, if they don't agree, would you
be willing to film with your half-brother?
You think?
Dad, tell me, is he older than me?
Mom, come on, maybe you should forgive Dad too?
-Why, because you forgave Shai?
It's not the same, Mom,
it's nonsense Dad did years ago.
Yeah, but from Dad's nonsense
a kid was born, and that's not funny anymore.
A kid? He's about to be a grandpa.
Let them film that
emotional scene, their reunion,
and they can take their awful songs
back to Sweden.
Shai, I know it's childish but...
I don't want them filming this movie here.
Mom, come on.
Tell me, didn't you have guys before Dad?
Me? No way.
Well, nothing serious.
-And does Dad know about it?
He knows most of it.
But not everything.
-Not everything, he doesn't need to know everything,
it's the first chapter in "How to Manage Men."
Of course, it's still in the introduction.
That comes later. I only had two guys before you.
And one of them was when I was drunk.
-Exactly.
Mr. Hasson, I'm begging you.
Your meeting with him is the whole movie.
If I don't have a meeting, I don't have a movie.
Listen carefully, I'm not willing to hurt
my wife's feelings.
If Rachel doesn't agree to the movie, there won't be a movie.
Tell me, even if he doesn't agree,
can we get a couple
of tickets to the show?
Shabbat Shalom.
-Shabbat Shalom.
Sorry for being late,
we just couldn't find the car keys.
Great, Moshe, you had an hour and a half drive.
Is that the excuse you came up with?
The dog peed on the car keys?
For an excuse like that, you need to have a dog first.
Alright, Rabbi, Silvan, Rabbi, what can I do?
I got tickets from work
tonight for the show at the cultural hall,
And she doesn't want to come with me, what should I do?
He should give you a raise
instead of throwing concert tickets at you.
For a singer I don't know and don't want to know.
Who are you?
-Daba, she's the producer for the Swedish singer.
That you don't know and don't want to know, who happens to be
much closer to you than you think.
Great, what's the nonsense this time?
Your dad is going to meet his long-lost son today.
From an old romance with a Swedish volunteer.
-Before he got married.
And they want to film a movie about it here at home.
You expect me to believe that.
-It's real, there's a half-Swedish brother.
And what happened to the other half?
Delightful.
And where's Mom?
-Mom's in a mood,
it's a territory somewhere around the kitchen.
What's going on, no kiddush today?
What, is it because of Shai's Swedish?
No, it's delayed now because of Dad's Swedish.
Dad and Shai were with the same Swedish?
-No way, come on.
Her mom?
No, the mom of Per Olsson.
-What?
Ice?
-Not anymore.
No, I can't believe that really happened.
No, if Moshe showed up one day with news like that,
I would be
his being
No, I can't even imagine
what I would do to him.
Wait, Moshe was at the kibbutz with that volunteer?
No, but if...
-What if, what?
You would tell him about the rented apartment
you had in Tel Aviv,
a bus stop?
She had a bus stop under her house,
it was noisy.
There was nothing, come on, nonsense.
-The location isn't great.
Alright, come on,
let's let them film this stupid movie,
then they can go home and we'll do kiddush.
Hey, Moshe,
if you're not using the tickets,
can I have them?
I don't know, maybe now that Rachel
found out that guy is her brother,
maybe she'll want to come with me.
You, come here.
Not you, dummy, no, you.
After much consideration and deliberation
I've decided to allow them to film this movie here.
Got it.
Good, excellent.
-But on one condition,
that this is the last stepchild I hear about.
If you have any concern
that somewhere on this globe
there's another kid claiming you're his dad,
then forget it.
So is there or isn't there?
-No, Racheli, I don't have any stepchildren, I swear.
This is a one-time exception.
-Okay, I'm going to call.
Alright, so here's the deal...
-Sit down, honey,
you can't do this, you just can't.
Look, right this moment
your mom is forgiving your dad
for a very, very similar case.
-No, it's not the same, sorry,
and besides, my dad got burned.
-But I got burned too.
Okay, okay, so right now I'm agreeing
not to make a scene here
about your date with your Miss IKEA-
-What Miss IKEA, what Miss IKEA?
She was small, ugly,
cross-eyed, with bad breath
and a blonde mustache like this.
Ah, well, maybe it's really better
if I don't tell your mom about this.
What about my mom?
Let's see how you behave until the end of the night.
- Professor Olson, master! -
- Last episode -
- Dad -
And then I reached my dad's door
whom I’ve never met.
I don’t know what’s waiting for me behind the door,
and wow.
R bitu.
S
(and
ro.
1 A
ro.,
soft..
I didn’t come here for nothing.
I’ll ring the bell.
Professor.
Professor Olson.
Hello.
- Hi.
Hello, come in, come in.
Hello.
Professor.
Dad.
Yes.
- Dad.
I love you, Dad.
You explained to me in Hebrew where you met Mom.
Mud
to the nest
saw
and
She worked and goodbye.
- And goodbye.
Hello.
- Hi.
All of a sudden, my family grew by 80 percent.
I’m Shani, and I’m Professor’s new sister.
- And I’m Shani’s husband.
Sho
“Sho
Sh.
It’s a crazy thing I need to
get used to now that I have another brother,
another one,
and by the way, he just happens to have
tickets to his show tonight.
Of course, not everything went smoothly...
You listen to music, I’m doing Sweden.
Why?
- Here.
Oudi, Oudi, let’s go, let’s go.
Nice, nice.
Yeah, yeah, nice, nice, nice.
Just so you know, I know
all your work over the years.
Me too.
- That’s loud!
This, z,,
is this
Hello, cut, cut.
Close it, bottom', enough.
Swedish music is really trash that the devil didn’t create,
what is this? It’s gravel. What?
Israelis are full of prejudices
about us Swedes.
Once you’d go to the beach, blind you’d see
like, two, three Swedes sunbathing topless.
What is this, you want them to show us
in Sweden as racists, what’s wrong with you?
Not just Swedish tourists,
there were all kinds of tourists in the country,
there were also English, there were also French,
even once I met a cute Italian.
What Italian?
- What Italian?
The Israeli sense of humor is a bit weird...
Professor, Professor, say, say mezilof.
Mezilof.
Say machlata, machlata.
Machlata.
- Machlata.
Theoretically, every addition of a brother automatically reduces
the number of available eligible men
for a relationship, for me.
Of course, my religion came up.
Basically, brother or not, you’re not really Jewish.
Not from my side.
- Your mom isn’t Jewish.
Mom’s a kibbutz cow.
Did you have a bris?
-Not from my side.
No, Manny, Manny, the...
But at least I have a dad.
She was young...
Kolban HaYav! Youngsters,
Kolban HaYav! Young and mischievous,
And that was that, praise be.
As we say, enough, enough.
"The Day of Shushan
And the heavens and the earth
And all their hosts"
Every Friday, Jewish families in Israel
Sanctify the Sabbath
And thank God for the world, the food, and the wine.
Sabri Maranan-
-Cheers!
And then to the food.
One of the tastiest meals I've ever had...
Now we just need him to talk to Mom
for this movie to have a happy ending.
So, we organized a little surprise
for Olson and especially for Silvan,
a conference call with Olson's mom from Sweden.
What, now?
-Right now she's connecting to the computer in Stockholm.
Well, now we'll have a chance
to see her live.
We can see what she really looks like.
Lucky it's a computer,
so her blonde mustache
won't poke, the bristles.
A blonde mustache.
-I think that's a genetic Swedish issue.
Good evening, Mom.
Hello.
-Shabbat Shalom, Shabbat Shalom.
Mom, Mr. Silvan.
-Do you recognize her?
Yes, of course I recognize her, she
volunteered at the kibbutz I was at.
Solveig, that's her name,
I dated one named Helga.
Solveig dated my best friend,
Chaim Solomon.
Yeah.
What what? You're not a strong guy, you're a Solomon guy.
I dated Helga.
Helga was a very tall girl,
she had blonde hair.
She used to collect them after with some
What did she have? She had a big mustache with bristles.
Yeah, yeah, for sure.
-Like that...
One moment.
-Yeah.
He's not my brother?
-No.
Okay.
Good evening, Meirav.
They're Bradman.
-Maybe, now to Abayben.
Which Italian are we talking about?
Tell me, what, do you think
you'll wander the world with Swedes
and I'll sit at home, making goblins?
Tell me exactly what it was and what happened.
Come on, forget it, we're even.
I told you about Partiban.
-Okay, fine.
He had a kind of accent.
Calm down, calm down, I can learn Italian too.
Yeah, but he also knew how to cook,
he would make me pasta and pizza
and tortellini and bucatini.
Now you're just throwing names around.
He painted
in
and
well
Bucatini in Khu-
He also knew how to paint.
Did he ever paint you?
-Yeah, once.
With or without?
Without.
Are you crazy?
Now a naked picture of you is out there?
No, I was dressed, he was not.
Now that I think about it,
I'm not even sure he had a brush.
What was her voice like?
-Voice?
She didn't have a voice.
That he volunteered there for avocado picking.
Why am I getting an avocado?
The dog peed on his car?
...Should I tell your mom about this?
Which mom are you talking about?
What's going on?
Maybe I shouldn't tell your mom.
-What about my mom?
No...
That cracked me up.
He's scared of his mom.